<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>iwantmyname Domain Blog</title>
		<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/</link>
		<atom:link href="https://iwantmyname.com/blog/feeds/posts/recent.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>We do domain names</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://radar.oreilly.com/2015/10/do-one-thing.html&#34;&gt;Mike Loukides on wanting tools that do one thing well, as opposed to a number of things not so well:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been lamenting the demise of the Unix philosophy: tools should do one thing, and do it well. The ability to connect many small tools is better than having a single tool that does everything poorly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That philosophy was great, but hasn’t survived into the Web age. Unfortunately, nothing better has come along to replace it. Instead, we have “convergence”: a lot of tools converging on doing all the same things poorly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We do domain names. That&amp;rsquo;s it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2015 15:10:00 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/10/we-do-domain-names.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/10/we-do-domain-names.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Quality of work-life should be a top priority</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/wonkblog/wp/2015/10/28/researchers-have-determined-how-many-years-of-life-you-lose-to-a-stressful-job/&#34;&gt;Ana Swanson on how job stress is literally killing people in the US:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People often like to groan about how their job is &amp;ldquo;killing&amp;rdquo; them. Tragically, for some groups of people in the U.S., that statement appears to be true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A new study by researchers at Harvard and Stanford has quantified just how much a stressful workplace may be shaving off of Americans&amp;rsquo; life spans. It suggests that the amount of life lost to stress varies significantly for people of different races, educational levels and genders, and ranges up to nearly three years of life lost for some groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech startups tend to spend a good deal of time talking about workplace culture and work/life balance, but it&amp;rsquo;s clearly something all business owners and managers need to be working on. These workplace decisions have long term effects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(On a related note, the US clearly needs to figure out its healthcare system. The amount of years shaved from lack of health care is insane.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2015 14:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/10/quality-of-work-life-should-be-a-top-priority.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/10/quality-of-work-life-should-be-a-top-priority.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Ad blockers and an-ugh-lytics</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://snipcart.com/blog/ad-blockers-saas-web-developers?utm_content=bufferd7420&amp;amp;utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_source=twitter.com&amp;amp;utm_campaign=buffer&#34;&gt;François Lanthier Nadeau on how ad blockers are messing with Snipcart&amp;rsquo;s metrics:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We quickly spotted a few listed third parties names that reminded us how effective those blockers can be. Especially when we read: Google Analytics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why the facepalm? Well, most of our website visitors and potential users are tech-savvy developers who are highly susceptible of running general purpose blocking software such as uBlock &amp;amp; uBlock Origin. In other words, we had just realized that a potentially substantial chunk of our website traffic were basically… ghosts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We learned something we should’ve learned a while ago: we can’t rely 100% on our tracking analytics. As a SaaS startup that focuses most of its growth on content marketing and website optimization, that’s not exactly good news. So for SaaS businesses, ads are just the tip of the ad-blocking/general purpose blocking iceberg. And what’s under the water here has a much more important potential impact on the businesses themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not that we care (I myself run ad blockers on desktop and mobile), but I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure our analytics are barely worth tracking these days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a related note, I think if we all turned off analytics and did marketing/site content solely based on what we think is most worthwhile for our customers, the internet would be a much more eclectic place. Maybe not measurably better, but certainly more interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2015 14:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/10/ad-blockers-and-anughlytics.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/10/ad-blockers-and-anughlytics.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Standing desks are for overachievers</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fastcoexist.com/3052273/instead-of-standing-why-not-lie-down-while-you-work-this-desk-lets-you-do-both&#34;&gt;Adele Peters on the new Altwork Station:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe you slouch in your Aeron chair. Maybe you tried—and failed—to make using a standing desk a habit. Maybe, like me, your preferred working position is curled up on a sofa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is it time for an ergonomic desk and chair that lazy people will actually want to use?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new Altwork Station, designed by aerospace engineers, has a standing and sitting position. But it also reclines fully into a &amp;ldquo;zero g&amp;rdquo; position—basically as comfortable as being in bed—with a monitor, laptop, and mouse floating the proper distance away above you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Out with your standing desk. Out with your upright chair. Out with your yoga ball. If you want to maximize my workplace happiness, I&amp;rsquo;d like to roll out of my real bed and into a work bed. (To be fair, I already do 75% of my work in a giant beanbag.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2015 10:10:00 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/10/standing-desks-are-for-overachievers.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/10/standing-desks-are-for-overachievers.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Sign me up!</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mailchimp.com/resources/guides/how-to-avoid-spam-filters/html/&#34;&gt;MailChimp on how spam filters work:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spam filters consider a long list of criteria when judging the “spamminess” of an email. They’ll weigh each factor and add them up to determine a spam score, which then determines whether a campaign will pass through the filter. They might look for spammy phrases like “CLICK HERE!” or “FREE! BUY NOW!” Then they&amp;rsquo;ll assign points every time they see one of those phrases. Certain criteria get more points than others. Here’s a sample of criteria from SpamAssassin:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Talks about lots of money (.193 points)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Describes some sort of breakthrough (.232 points)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Looks like mortgage pitch (.297 points)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contains urgent matter (.288 points)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Money back guarantee (2.051 points)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your campaign’s total “spam score” exceeds a certain threshold, then your email goes to the junk folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thought of this when &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aAYw69hU2Yc&#34;&gt;watching this&lt;/a&gt; (sign me up!).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2015 15:50:00 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/10/sign-me-up.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/10/sign-me-up.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>1API Abuse Domain Suspension Scam</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Recently we have been made aware of fraudulent emails that have been sent to a number of high profile domain registrars&amp;rsquo; customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These emails appear to be coming from abuse@1api.net or similar email addresses and attempt to impersonate the Spam and Abuse Department of our in-house domain name registrar 1API GmbH. These suspension emails are NOT being sent from Hexonet, 1API, or iwantmyname.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fraudulent emails claim your domain name has been suspended because you have failed to respond to previous email and telephone notices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The email message is an attempt to have you click on links and download files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DO NOT reply to the email directly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DO NOT click on any links.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DO NOT call the number listed in the email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just delete and ignore the email. If you have any questions or concerns, whether you have received the email or not, &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/support&#34;&gt;please don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a copy of one of the emails:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://iwmn.me/jcA7/1t06yaFS+&#34; alt=&#34;abuse spam email&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2015 11:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/10/oneapi-abuse-domain-suspension-scam.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/10/oneapi-abuse-domain-suspension-scam.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Tiny domain names for tiny brains</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://news.usc.edu/79313/study-reveals-internet-like-networks-in-cerebral-cortex-of-rats/&#34;&gt;Robert Perkins on the discovery that rat brains are set up like the internet:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Researchers sketching out a wiring diagram for rat brains — a field known as “connectomics” — have discovered that its structure is organized like the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For years, scientists looking for clues to brain function through its structure focused on what could be seen — the brain’s lobes, grooves and folds. Now, with a more comprehensive picture of how neurons connect to one another, they’ve discovered local networks of neurons layered like the shells in a Russian nesting doll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The cerebral cortex is like a mini-Internet,” said Larry Swanson, professor at the USC Dornsife College of Letters, Arts and Sciences, and corresponding author of a paper on the discovery. “The Internet has countless local area networks that then connect with larger, regional networks and ultimately with the backbone of the Internet. The brain operates in a similar way.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A new and exciting domain name market!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2015 10:30:00 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/10/tiny-domain-names-for-tiny-brains.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/10/tiny-domain-names-for-tiny-brains.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>2G Tuesdays</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.businessinsider.com/facebook-2g-tuesdays-to-slow-employee-internet-speeds-down-2015-10?op=1&#34;&gt;Jillian D&amp;rsquo;Onfro on Facebook handling its &amp;ldquo;empathy gap&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook is launching a new initiative called &amp;ldquo;2G Tuesdays&amp;rdquo; that will give all employees an opportunity to see what using the app with an incredibly slow connection feels like and help close the &amp;ldquo;empathy gap&amp;rdquo; between Silicon Valley and emerging markets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For most people, the stark differences will likely be jarring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s easy to dream up interfaces that take advantage of blinding connection speeds, but businesses trying to reach global audiences need to do a much better job serving the other end of the spectrum. Even here at iwantmyname, our site is relatively minimal, but searching for a domain with a less-than-optimal connection can be grueling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along with responsive interfaces and top-shelf security, speed should be a main priority when building on the web. (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sitepoint.com/average-page-weight-increases-15-2014/&#34;&gt;Your 2Mb page weight&lt;/a&gt; just isn&amp;rsquo;t working for a lot of people.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2015 11:05:00 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/10/twog-tuesdays.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/10/twog-tuesdays.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Getting the internet to the underdeveloped world without drones or high-altitude balloons</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lowtechmagazine.com/2015/10/how-to-build-a-low-tech-internet.html&#34;&gt;Kris De Decker on how to build a low-tech internet:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than half of the global population does not have access to the &amp;ldquo;worldwide&amp;rdquo; web. Up to now, the internet is mainly an urban phenomenon, especially in &amp;ldquo;developing&amp;rdquo; countries. Telecommunication companies are usually reluctant to extend their network outside cities due to a combination of high infrastructure costs, low population density, limited ability to pay for services, and an unreliable or non-existent electricity infrastructure. Even in remote regions of &amp;ldquo;developed&amp;rdquo; countries, internet connectivity isn&amp;rsquo;t always available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Internet companies such as Facebook and Google regularly make headlines with plans for connecting these remote regions to the internet. Facebook tries to achieve this with drones, while Google counts on high-altitude balloons. There are major technological challenges, but the main objection to these plans is their commercial character. Obviously, Google and Facebook want to connect more people to the internet because that would increase their revenues. Facebook especially receives lots of criticism because their network promotes their own site in particular, and blocks most other internet applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, several research groups and network enthusiasts have developed and implemented much cheaper alternative network technologies to solve these issues. Although these low-tech networks have proven their worth, they have received much less attention. Contrary to the projects of internet companies, they are set up by small organisations or by the users themselves. This guarantees an open network that benefits the users instead of a handful of corporations. At the same time, these low-tech networks are very energy efficient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2015 10:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/10/getting-the-internet-to-the-underdeveloped-world.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/10/getting-the-internet-to-the-underdeveloped-world.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>The machines have taken over (your search results)</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2015-10-26/google-turning-its-lucrative-web-search-over-to-ai-machines&#34;&gt;Jack Clark on Google using AI to figure out its search results:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the past few months, a “very large fraction” of the millions of queries a second that people type into the company’s search engine have been interpreted by an artificial intelligence system, nicknamed RankBrain, said Greg Corrado, a senior research scientist with the company, outlining for the first time the emerging role of AI in search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RankBrain uses artificial intelligence to embed vast amounts of written language into mathematical entities -- called vectors -- that the computer can understand. If RankBrain sees a word or phrase it isn’t familiar with, the machine can make a guess as to what words or phrases might have a similar meaning and filter the result accordingly, making it more effective at handling never-before-seen search queries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in the day I spent a lot of time thinking about SEO. I poured over SEO blogs, asked for advice on how I can improve my search results, and did everything in my power to game the (people-powered) Google system. But it&amp;rsquo;s 2015. The computers are taking over. All that matters now is making sites that perform their intended task with the least resistance possible.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 12:05:00 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/10/the-machines-have-taken-over.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/10/the-machines-have-taken-over.html</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
