<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>iwantmyname Domain Blog</title>
		<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog</link>
		<atom:link href="https://iwantmyname.com/blog/feeds/posts/recent.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>A call to help Vanuatu after Cyclone Pam</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/assets/images/content/2015-03-23-vanuatu-cyclone.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Vanuatu&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those of us who live in temperate climates, it&amp;#39;s difficult to imagine
the unfolding horror of a category 5 tropical cyclone bearing down on your
home with winds exceeding 200 mph. But that was the scenario facing the
inhabitants of the far flung islands of Vanuatu recently. The tiny Pacific
Ocean island archipelago took a direct hit from Cyclone Pam, resulting in
many villages being entirely flattened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Incredibly and thankfully, the death toll as a result of the storm has been kept to a minimum, but a large section of the population has been left without food, water, and housing. Now a major relief operation is underway involving NGOs and neighbouring governments from the South Pacific region such as New Zealand and Australia. Technology is also playing a part in the recovery with power and communications providers rallying to get services running again quickly. We have seen &lt;a href=&quot;http://pacificpolicy.org/2015/03/surviving-cyclone-pam/&quot;&gt;encouraging reports&lt;/a&gt; suggesting that some progress is being made, against all odds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s not the first time a huge cyclone has ravaged communities in the
Pacific. Typhoon Haiyan wreaked havoc across the islands of the Philippines
in 2013. You may recall our efforts to contribute during the &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2013/11/philippines-typhoon-how-you-can-help.html&quot;&gt;Haiyan relief
operation&lt;/a&gt;. With your help, we will be financially supporting UNICEF&amp;#39;s operation on the ground in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.unicef.org.nz/vanuatu&quot;&gt;Vanuatu&lt;/a&gt; today with an immediate donation of $6,500. We are thrilled to learn that our cash will pack twice the punch because New Zealand philanthropists Gareth and Jo Morgan have agreed to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.unicef.org.nz/UNICEF-New-Zealand-issues-fundraising-challenge-to-reach-82000-children-in-Vanuatu&quot;&gt;match&lt;/a&gt; the first $1 million in donations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;iwantmyname has a longstanding policy of setting aside 10 cents from every
domain registration for charitable purposes, but with the crisis being so
great, we&amp;#39;ve dug a bit deeper to help out our neighbours in their time of need. If you want to make your own donation to the Vanuatu relief fund, you can do so &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.unicef.org.nz/vanuatu&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Photo by Dave Hunt-Pool/Getty Images)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2015 14:51:56 -0700</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/03/a-call-to-help-vanuatu-after-cyclone-pam.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/03/a-call-to-help-vanuatu-after-cyclone-pam.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>The story of how Buffer bought buffer.com, and why a short .com isn&#39;t necessary for startup success</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/assets/images/content/2015-03-19-buffer-home.png&quot; alt=&quot;Buffer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.bufferapp.com/acquired-buffer-com/&quot;&gt;From Rodolphe Dutel - Buffer:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a great blogpost that Joel wrote on how to name your startup, where he mentioned that the domain name of your startup doesn’t matter. In fact, thinking about Buffer’s own domain history, we originally started out with bfffr.com, when Joel launched Buffer in late 2010.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joel went on to change it to bufferapp.com, to make things more clear and worry less about not having the exact domain of your startup’s name, “Buffer” in our case. It can be a huge time-suck in the early days of your company, where your first and foremost goal should be to hit product-market fit and building something people want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spending time on acquiring a certain domain name could be a very futile exercise without a product that works. In fact, as Joel illustrates, most well-known companies all had “placeholder” domains for a long time before they got their actual name as their domain too:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Square was squareup.com&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DropBox was getdropbox.com&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Facebook was thefacebook.com&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instagram was instagr.am&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Twitter was twttr.com&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Foursquare was playfoursquare.com&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The primary point of the post is to tell the story of how Buffer acquired buffer.com, but the real story to me is that while most of us aren&amp;#39;t &amp;quot;generat(ing) over $5m/year,&amp;quot; and probably don&amp;#39;t have the time or money to pay what it would cost to get a short .com in 2015, there&amp;#39;s no reason you can&amp;#39;t get to that level of success with a domain name you find less than perfect. Buffer had a $60m valuation while using bufferapp.com, and the roster of huge brands listed in the post that started with dodgy domains is pretty incredible. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you take anything away from this, it&amp;#39;s that the domain name you choose is only a minor piece of a very large puzzle. Before you go throwing resources at the domain aftermarket, just grab a name that fits and make your product as solid as it can possibly be. Good work attracts customers—your domain is just a sticker on the door.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2015 15:35:22 -0700</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/03/the-story-of-how-buffer-bought-buffer-com.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/03/the-story-of-how-buffer-bought-buffer-com.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>On the sad stagnation of Virb</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sitebuilderreport.com/blog/what-happened-to-virb-after-godaddy-acquired-it&quot;&gt;From Steve Benjamins - Site Builder Report:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The culture at Virb began to shift after the GoDaddy acquisition. There were now new bosses and new goals— but not ones that aligned with Virb’s original vision. The 4 original Virb team members decided it was time to leave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It was clear to me that our new leadership wanted to extract as much money from our customers as possible.” Ryan Clark, Virb’s Product Manager and Creative Director at the time says. “Our new directive was simple: revenue.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make matters worse, the Virb team was denied any resources. After losing the 4 original Virb team members Clark notes, “All of my requests to fill the positions disappeared in the ether of the acquisition. It seemed clear to me that GoDaddy had no intention of backing up their new goals for us with the resources to actually achieve them.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn&amp;#39;t so much an indictment of GoDaddy, as they clearly acquired Media Temple to better compete in the web hosting game (Virb just happened to be part of the deal), but it&amp;#39;s sad to see a once-promising platform slow to a grind. As a writer who frequently uses all-in-one platforms to get ideas on the web, I&amp;#39;ve primarily moved on to Squarespace. It&amp;#39;s fast enough, beautiful, and best of all, dead simple to use. Hopefully we&amp;#39;ll see other hosted, all-in-one solutions take up the torch though—competition in the space is what drives innovation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the future of Virb:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hallgren speculates that GoDaddy will let Virb “die a slow death and collect the money being made on it in the meantime.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately this most effects the 20,000 customers who still rely on Virb to provide a stable, contemporary website— unfortunately, it’s not clear how stable that future is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2015 11:30:38 -0700</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/03/on-the-sad-stagnation-of-virb.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/03/on-the-sad-stagnation-of-virb.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Happy belated 30th to .com</title>
				<description>&lt;div class=&quot;embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/UlJku_CSyNg&quot; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The internet has come a long way in the last 30 years. Happy belated (&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/com-domain-name-registration-for-commercial&quot;&gt;.com&lt;/a&gt; turned 30 on March 15th)!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2015 16:51:59 -0700</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/03/happy-belated-to-com.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/03/happy-belated-to-com.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Mike Carson compiles the 1457 most popular .io domains</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://hack.ly/articles/the-most-popular-dot-io-domains-2015/&quot;&gt;From Mike Carson:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exactly one year ago today I created a list of the top .io domains. At that time there were only 676 .io domains in the top 1 million sites in the world (from Alexa). In one year that number has more than doubled to 1457.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#39;s a little sample (the top 10):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;github.io - rank 307&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;codepen.io - rank 1372&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;soup.io - rank 3161&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;intercom.io - rank 3375&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;t411.io - rank 3477&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;meduza.io - rank 3546&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;keywordtool.io - rank 3637&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;popcorntime.io - rank 4816&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;spring.io - rank 5566&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;greenhouse.io - rank 6263&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Short lists are interesting. Massive lists are amazing. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2015 14:41:44 -0700</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/03/mike-carson-compiles-the-most-popular-io-domains.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/03/mike-carson-compiles-the-most-popular-io-domains.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Usability is something we should all be striving for</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://melodykramer.github.io/how-betty-who-is-89-gets-her-news/&quot;&gt;From Melody Kramer:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After we drank tea, I watched Betty read articles on her iPad. Her Internet was really slow. She kept accidentally clicking on the ads, or on parts of the story that she didn’t mean to click on. And she was getting a bit frustrated and worried — that by clicking on something, she was going to install malware or not be able to return to her story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are 13 million people between the ages of 75 and 84 in the US. There are 5 million between the ages of 85 and 94. (census) That population will grow. At some point, it will be composed of digital natives but that’s a while away. In the interim, are there better ways to design websites for this population? Are there better ways to design the news for them? Of course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like any good web entity, we&amp;#39;re always planning for the next evolution of our website. Whether we like it or not, trends change, platforms that were built for one thing get weighed down by incremental additions, and new technologies emerge (like responsive design) that change how sites move through the world. Those things are always moving targets that need to be addressed, but one factor that cannot be overlooked, no matter when your design/redesign occurs, is usability. At the end of the day, the single most important thing you can offer is an easy path from idea to completion. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#39;s a good example of where the internet is going. After I wrote our &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/03/what-should-the-internet-do-with-money.html&quot;&gt;post about .money&lt;/a&gt;, I started looking through various finance websites. What I found didn&amp;#39;t really surprise me, but it&amp;#39;s worth noting nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/assets/images/content/2015-03-11-fidelity-homepage.png&quot; alt=&quot;Fidelity homepage&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#39;s Fidelity&amp;#39;s homepage. As you can see, it&amp;#39;s packed with information, but if your goal is to start an account (which, I&amp;#39;d argue, should be the goal in a logged-out state) , you have a lot to contend with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/assets/images/content/2015-03-11-wealthfront-homepage.png&quot; alt=&quot;Wealthfront homepage&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other end of the spectrum is Wealthfront, an investment startup that puts usability first. Big buttons. Clear calls to action. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could certainly make the argument that Fidelity&amp;#39;s website is more immediately useful, strictly from a knowledge-density perspective, but we&amp;#39;re heading in a direction, as a society, where screens are rapidly shrinking in size.  Apple recently announced their new 12&amp;quot; Macbook, which is their most technologically advanced laptop to date (not to be confused with fastest), and the only reason the screen is as big as it is is because they didn&amp;#39;t want the keyboard to be any smaller. There &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; come a day, and it may come faster than we think, where an iPad/phablet-type device will be the primary device for many, and then what? Will the Fidelity content-density model hold up? Are we just going to sit around while our aging population is designed off these unusable platforms?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;/rant&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just something to think about when you&amp;#39;re starting your next design/redesign process.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2015 11:47:11 -0700</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/03/usability-is-something-we-should-all-be-striving-for.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/03/usability-is-something-we-should-all-be-striving-for.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>What should the internet do with its new .money?</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/assets/images/content/2015-03-10-money-bowtie.png&quot; alt=&quot;Money bowtie&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Money is a hard thing for a lot of people to talk about, so let&amp;#39;s shift the focus a bit by putting a &amp;quot;.&amp;quot; in front. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;money = aghhhhhhh&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;.money = awesome!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what should the people of the internet do with their new .money (domains... &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-money&quot;&gt;.money&lt;/a&gt; goes live tomorrow)? Let me count the ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;1. Start the world&amp;#39;s most trusted Bitcoin blog&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a brilliant financier who rode Bitcoins from around $200 to nearly $1,000, then back down to $200, I can safely say that I don&amp;#39;t know right from left when it comes to Bitcoin valuations. But you know who else doesn&amp;#39;t know anything about Bitcoin valuations? The rest of the internet. And if I know anything, it&amp;#39;s that general confusion means there&amp;#39;s a gap in the market, just waiting to be filled. And really, using .money for a digital publication about digital money is magic in the making.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;2. Forget Bitcoins... start your own digital currency&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is beyond my scope, but there have to be a few iwantmynamers out there with cryptocurrency running through their veins. Seriously, if someone can build a currency around the doge meme, I think we (as in you and your friends) can band together to make something better. Just don&amp;#39;t forget the .money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;3. Start a finance blog&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, if your finance blog gets big, you might have to buy (and sometimes wear) a suit or two, but that&amp;#39;s the price you have to pay when you&amp;#39;re a big time analyst.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;4. Become a &amp;quot;startup finance expert&amp;quot;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of analysts, I feel like startup financing is having a bit of a PR issue these days. I read all the time about the overabundance of money flowing through places like Silicon Valley, but I rarely read about analysts saying the opposite. Going back to my gap-that-needs-to-be-filled theory, I think there&amp;#39;s a big opportunity for someone to start an expert site telling the world that tech startups need more cash. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or maybe your site could be about bootstrapped companies like iwantmyname... your call.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;5. Make your financial institution more &amp;quot;me&amp;quot; focused&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hear me out. Take your average bank, I&amp;#39;ll go with Wells Fargo for this example.  The website for Wells Fargo is wellsfargo.com—.com meaning commercial. What this says to me is that Wells Fargo is a commercial entity that wants to make money. But I don&amp;#39;t put money in the bank for them to make money, I do it so &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; can make money. So why not swap the bank&amp;#39;s .com with .money and give people a little something to aspire to? wellsfargo.money sounds like a bank I could get on board with. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;6. Give your personal brand a makeover&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking for a little personal brand boost? Change your personal website to &lt;code&gt;YOURNAME.money&lt;/code&gt;. You&amp;#39;re welcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;7. Coupon site?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the internet is in desperate need of something, it&amp;#39;s definitely more coupon sites. Retail coupon sites, online services coupon sites, coupon sites for coupon sites—the possibilities are endless! &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2015 16:47:14 -0700</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/03/what-should-the-internet-do-with-money.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/03/what-should-the-internet-do-with-money.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>New feature alert - domain hacks in search</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/assets/images/content/2015-03-05-domain-hack.png&quot; alt=&quot;work trip&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the world of domains, naming is a bit like an architecture project. The domain name has to stand on its own, make sense to those who use it, and be conventional enough to attract all types of potential guests. A standard domain name is much like a standard building—the outside can be nice, but it&amp;#39;s really what&amp;#39;s inside that counts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2009/05/how-to-find-a-domain-hack.html&quot;&gt;domain hacks&lt;/a&gt; are a bit different. They&amp;#39;re the circular buildings with no conventional walls, the tiny houses that don&amp;#39;t make sense to most, the underground mud huts that only the adventurous flock to. A domain hack will likely never be the primary domain of a multinational corporation, but for those who appreciate cultural oddities, there&amp;#39;s simply nothing better. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here&amp;#39;s the deal. In our domain search, when you type in a word or brand, a single domain hack will now appear as the second result (if one is able to be made). It&amp;#39;s nothing Earth-shattering—just a little something for your Thursday afternoon/Friday morning (depending on what side of the international date line you&amp;#39;re on) pleasure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2015 12:01:55 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/03/domain-hacks-in-search.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/03/domain-hacks-in-search.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Price increase alert for .INFO and .MU</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Heads up, folks. We&amp;#39;re not fond of domain extension price increases, but we have two to announce, both of which affect the registration and renewal costs for the domains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;May 1, 2015 - &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/info-domain-name-registration-for-information&quot;&gt;.INFO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;$15.50 to $16.50 USD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;€11.90 to €12.90 EUR&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;£10.90 to £11.50 GBP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;$19 to $19.90 AUD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;April 1, 2015 - &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/mu-mauritian-domain-name-registration-for-mauritius&quot;&gt;.MU&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;$99 to $119 USD &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;€89 to €129 EUR&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;$159 to $169 NZD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;£78 to £89 GBP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;$119 to $169 AUD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about the price increases, please &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/support&quot;&gt;get in touch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2015 09:59:38 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/03/price-increase-alert-for-info-and-mu.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/03/price-increase-alert-for-info-and-mu.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Trustworthiness as a factor in Google rankings</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newscientist.com/article/mg22530102.600-google-wants-to-rank-websites-based-on-facts-not-links.html#.VPSuQUIylBW&quot;&gt;From Hal Hodson - New Scientist:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Google research team is adapting that model to measure the trustworthiness of a page, rather than its reputation across the web. Instead of counting incoming links, the system – which is not yet live – counts the number of incorrect facts within a page. &amp;quot;A source that has few false facts is considered to be trustworthy,&amp;quot; says the team (arxiv.org/abs/1502.03519v1). The score they compute for each page is its Knowledge-Based Trust score.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The software works by tapping into the Knowledge Vault, the vast store of facts that Google has pulled off the internet. Facts the web unanimously agrees on are considered a reasonable proxy for truth. Web pages that contain contradictory information are bumped down the rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So much time and effort these days goes into search engine optimization (SEO), but every time I see an article like this, I see a day in the far-off future where all the &amp;quot;tips and tricks&amp;quot; will be replaced by variations of a single question—is your website helping the world or hurting it?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2015 10:37:58 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/03/trustworthiness-as-a-factor-in-google-rankings.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/03/trustworthiness-as-a-factor-in-google-rankings.html</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
