<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>iwantmyname Domain Blog</title>
		<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog</link>
		<atom:link href="https://iwantmyname.com/blog/feeds/posts/recent.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Trustworthiness as a factor in Google rankings</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newscientist.com/article/mg22530102.600-google-wants-to-rank-websites-based-on-facts-not-links.html#.VPSuQUIylBW&quot;&gt;From Hal Hodson - New Scientist:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Google research team is adapting that model to measure the trustworthiness of a page, rather than its reputation across the web. Instead of counting incoming links, the system – which is not yet live – counts the number of incorrect facts within a page. &amp;quot;A source that has few false facts is considered to be trustworthy,&amp;quot; says the team (arxiv.org/abs/1502.03519v1). The score they compute for each page is its Knowledge-Based Trust score.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The software works by tapping into the Knowledge Vault, the vast store of facts that Google has pulled off the internet. Facts the web unanimously agrees on are considered a reasonable proxy for truth. Web pages that contain contradictory information are bumped down the rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So much time and effort these days goes into search engine optimization (SEO), but every time I see an article like this, I see a day in the far-off future where all the &amp;quot;tips and tricks&amp;quot; will be replaced by variations of a single question—is your website helping the world or hurting it?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2015 10:37:58 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/03/trustworthiness-as-a-factor-in-google-rankings.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/03/trustworthiness-as-a-factor-in-google-rankings.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Leonard Nimoy&#39;s final tweet</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theverge.com/2015/2/27/8121021/leonard-nimoy-spock-live-long-and-prosper&quot;&gt;From Bryan Bishop - The Verge:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, it should go without saying that the sense of someone we get from their acting and public appearances often bears little resemblance to who they actually are. But what is undeniable is the emotional impact their work has on us. And for the millions of people, like myself, that grew up with Leonard Nimoy, those are the memories that we will carry with us throughout our lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s a sentiment that Nimoy himself reflected upon on Twitter this past Sunday, in his very last post. &amp;quot;A life is like a garden,&amp;quot; he wrote. &amp;quot;Perfect moments can be had, but not preserved, except in memory.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2015 15:49:40 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/02/leonard-nimoys-final-tweet.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/02/leonard-nimoys-final-tweet.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Domain hacks and the new generic top-level domains</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Domain hacks aren&amp;#39;t for the feint of heart. They disrupt the status quo of website naming, they&amp;#39;re often hard to say out loud, and countless online guides have been written warning people not to get too clever with their domain names.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But...I&amp;#39;m just going to come out and say it...I love a good domain hack. They&amp;#39;re counterculture without being overly brazen and they stick in my head forever (despite being hard to say sometimes). And with hundreds of new domain extensions to choose from with the launch of the new &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/new-gtld-domain-extensions&quot;&gt;generic top-level domains (gTLDs)&lt;/a&gt;, the domain hack possibilities are practically endless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I get into it, let&amp;#39;s set a working definition for what a domain hack is. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Domain hack - Using domain extensions like .es and .io to create words or brand names out of domain names, like bit.ly (brand name) or iwantmyna.me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now clearly, with these new gTLDs running around, the definition of domain hack is in a bit of flux. Is a domain like chess.club a domain hack? I&amp;#39;d argue that it&amp;#39;s not, unless your brand name is ChessClub. If every gTLD that makes a phrase is considered a domain hack, then the term itself has been diluted beyond comprehension. We just can&amp;#39;t have that! So... no phrases for domain hacks, just words and brand names. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With these boundaries in mind, let&amp;#39;s find some good gTLD domain hack possibilities (I&amp;#39;m not checking each for availability... this is really just to get your mind going).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ra.bid&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;specifi.city&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ac.company&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dis.credit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;super.fund&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bl.ink&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;never.land&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hyper.link&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;de.parts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bo.red&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;at.tax&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;net.work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So many good options! Again, domain hacks are definitely for the feint of heart, but if you find yourself hopelessly attracted to clever domain/TLD combinations, we&amp;#39;re right in the middle of a domain hack renaissance. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you need any help finding a killer domain hack, look no further than the trusty &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wordfind.com/#words&quot;&gt;Scrabble Word Finder&lt;/a&gt; (under advanced options, you can specifically ask for words that end with any combination of letters). Also, if you have a specific word in mind, our friends over at &lt;a href=&quot;https://domainr.com&quot;&gt;Domainr&lt;/a&gt; have the perfect domain search for the task—it takes any word you put in and shoots back a handful of awesome options, including any combination of domain hacks available (I typed in bored and got back bo.red &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; bo.re/d... both taken already, but still amazing).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy domain hacking!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2015 14:36:28 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/02/domain-hacks-and-the-new-generic-top-level-domains.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/02/domain-hacks-and-the-new-generic-top-level-domains.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Question. What extension should I use? Answer. .QA</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;With all the new &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/new-gtld-domain-extensions&quot;&gt;generic top-level domains (gTLDs)&lt;/a&gt; coming out, sometimes we forget to celebrate the other domains we add to the site. Just last week, we added a wonderful new country code top-level domain (ccTLD), .QA, to the list. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.QA is the domain extension for Qatar, located on the Arabian Peninsula between Saudi Arabia and the Persian Gulf. Businesses and individuals in Qatar will certainly use the extension to establish a local presence, but for non-Qataris, .QA is the perfect acronym—&lt;strong&gt;Q&lt;/strong&gt;uality &lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;ssurance and &lt;strong&gt;Q&lt;/strong&gt;uestions and &lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;nswers—for a host of professional websites. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#39;re looking to start a related site, check out our &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/qa-qatari-domain-name-registration-for-qatar&quot;&gt;.QA page&lt;/a&gt; for current pricing and transfer information.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2015 09:59:46 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/02/answer-qa.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/02/answer-qa.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>The simple guide to finding the right domain name for your podcast</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/assets/images/content/2015-02-20-podcast.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;podcast&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Podcasts seem to be getting more and more popular by the week, with big shows and big names finally getting the mainstream media attention they deserve. But one of the best things about podcasting is that it can be done by anyone. There aren&amp;#39;t any expensive broadcasting rights or legal hurdles to deal with—all you have to do is get a mic, learn how to use some basic audio software (free options like Garageband are readily available), and find a reliable platform to &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/services/podcast/&quot;&gt;host your show&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But one thing that trips up many budding podcasters is the domain name. For the same reasons naming anything is hard, naming and finding a domain name for a podcast is a tricky balance between science and intuition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;General naming tips&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we get into top-level domains (TLDs), let&amp;#39;s dive into some basic naming tips for your podcast. Here are a few rules to live by:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try not to pick a name that&amp;#39;s too long or too hard to spell. The last thing you want is for your show to be hard to find.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try not to name your brand something that could be confused with a bigger, more well-known brand. A quick check is to type the name in Google—if you find a brand with an entire page full of search content, you&amp;#39;ll be fighting an uphill battle (not to mention potential legal issues).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If your show begins with &amp;quot;The&amp;quot;, it may be wise to get two domains—one with &amp;quot;the&amp;quot; and one without. For example, if your show is The Domain Podcast, try registering thedomainpodcast.com and domainpodcast.com.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Non-letter characters like dashes and numbers are fairly rare online, and may confuse people trying to find your show. Only use them when it&amp;#39;s absolutely necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Domain extensions from iTunes&amp;#39; US top-50 podcasts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Excluding shows that don&amp;#39;t have their own sites due to being on larger networks, like Invisibilia with http://www.npr.org/programs/invisibilia/.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/com-domain-name-registration-for-commercial&quot;&gt;.COM&lt;/a&gt; - freakonomics.com, missedinhistory.com, stuffyoushouldknow.com, lightroomkillertips.com, wtfpod.com, dancarlin.com, commonplacebooks.com, thisiscriminal.com, fourhourworkweek.com, daveramsey.com, nerdist.com, thetruthpodcast.com, smartpassiveincome.com, adamcarolla.com, sciencefriday.com, billburr.com&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/org-domain-name-registration-for-organisation&quot;&gt;.ORG&lt;/a&gt; - serialpodcast.org, thisamericanlife.org, radiolab.org, themoth.org, howtodoeverything.org, 99percentinvisible.org, onbeing.org&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/net-domain-name-registration-for-network&quot;&gt;.NET&lt;/a&gt; - podcasts.joerogan.net, startalkradio.net&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/co-colombian-domain-name-registration-for-colombia&quot;&gt;.CO&lt;/a&gt; - howtostartastartup.co&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/info-domain-name-registration-for-information&quot;&gt;.INFO&lt;/a&gt; - everydayfinance.info&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&amp;#39;s interesting about podcasts is that although they&amp;#39;re seen as a fairly new phenomenon, they&amp;#39;ve been around for quite some time now, and many of the most popular shows are linked to either &amp;quot;old-school media&amp;quot; (NPR/various TV networks) or sites that represent established non-podcast entities (like Freakonomics Radio, which started as a book, and The Moth, which organizes live storytelling events). Given the abundance of pre-internet roots, it doesn&amp;#39;t surprise me to see so many .COMs, .ORGs, and .NETs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But like the rest of the internet, good names in these domain extensions are increasingly hard to come by. If you&amp;#39;re looking for some alternative domain extensions, here are some suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Alternative domain extensions for podcast websites&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-audio&quot;&gt;.audio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-community&quot;&gt;.community&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-digital&quot;&gt;.digital&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-expert&quot;&gt;.expert&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-media&quot;&gt;.media&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-press&quot;&gt;.press&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-report&quot;&gt;.report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-today&quot;&gt;.today&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-radio&quot;&gt;.radio&lt;/a&gt; (launch date TBD)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/fm-domain-name-registration-for-federated-states-of-micronesia&quot;&gt;.FM&lt;/a&gt; (popularly used by Overcast, one of the more popular podcast players for the iPhone)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/io-domain-name-registration-for-british-indian-ocean-territory&quot;&gt;.IO&lt;/a&gt; (still a very popular extension for startups and tech projects)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, don&amp;#39;t be afraid to use descriptive extensions for your brand. Here are some industry specific top-level domains (TLDs) that could work quite well:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-academy&quot;&gt;.academy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-beer&quot;&gt;.beer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-build&quot;&gt;.build&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-business&quot;&gt;.business&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-club&quot;&gt;.club&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-coffee&quot;&gt;.coffee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-events&quot;&gt;.events&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-futbol&quot;&gt;.futbol&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-hiphop&quot;&gt;.hiphop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-photography&quot;&gt;.photography&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-reviews&quot;&gt;.reviews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-reviews&quot;&gt;.tools&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-zone&quot;&gt;.zone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new generic top-level domains (gTLDs) open up such a huge world of naming options for everyone. If you find one you like, use it! Just remember that podcast discovery is unlike typical website discovery. If your show is good, fans will probably find your podcast on platforms like iTunes or Stitcher first, then attempt to find your website later after hearing a few episodes. Given that discovery path, your biggest concern should be how sticky your domain sounds when you inevitably say it at the end of each episode. Before you register a domain, say it out loud to a few of your friends—if it sounds awkward, long, or tricky to spell, you&amp;#39;re probably going to lose traffic. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you ever get stuck, try a &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-pizza&quot;&gt;.pizza&lt;/a&gt; domain. Nine out of ten scientists agree that it&amp;#39;s impossible to forget domains that end in .pizza.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2015 15:15:43 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/02/guide-to-finding-the-right-domain-name-for-your-podcast.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/02/guide-to-finding-the-right-domain-name-for-your-podcast.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>A big WHOIS privacy update</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/assets/images/content/2015-02-17-superhero.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Superhero&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Privacy is rightly a huge concern for many people, and we&amp;#39;re actively updating our platform to keep as much of your information off the Internet as we can. On the domain front, one of the easiest ways to keep your identity hidden is to use a WHOIS privacy service, which basically eliminates your domain registration information (name, address, phone number, etc.) from the WHOIS record altogether.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past, we&amp;#39;ve used our own WHOIS privacy service, which masked phone numbers and addresses, but still left names and email addresses in the WHOIS public record. For many, this worked fine, but we&amp;#39;ve received a number of requests for a more robust solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the new WHOIS privacy in place, all personal information, including names and email addresses, will now be masked. With the service turned on, you are still the legal owner (registrant) of the domain name, and have full control should you wish to update the registrant details, change the owner, or transfer it to another registrar, but a WHOIS lookup will show none of your personal information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please note that WHOIS privacy is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; added to domains automatically (it&amp;#39;s entirely optional), but you can add the service (for free) from your domain&amp;#39;s WHOIS update page under &lt;strong&gt;Domains &amp;gt; yourdomain.com &amp;gt; Domain owner &amp;gt; enable privacy.&lt;/strong&gt; If you currently have our old WHOIS privacy service in place, you can update to the new full masking service by clicking &lt;strong&gt;disable privacy&lt;/strong&gt; in your dashboard to remove the old service, let the page refresh, then click &lt;strong&gt;enable privacy&lt;/strong&gt; to add the new WHO privacy service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also note that WHOIS privacy isn&amp;#39;t available for all domain extensions (WHOIS privacy availability is determined by the individual registries). Currently, you can use it with the following extensions (this list is constantly growing as we add new generic top-level domains (gTLDs), so please refer to our knowledge base for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://help.iwantmyname.com/customer/portal/articles/184425-do-you-offer-a-whois-privacy-service-&quot;&gt;updated list&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;list-inline&quot;&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.ac&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.academy&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.accountants&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.actor&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.ae.org&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.ag&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.agency&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.ar.com&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.associates&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.auction&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.band&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.bar&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.bargains&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.bayern&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.beer&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.bike&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.biz&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.black&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.blue&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.boutique&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.br.com&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.builders&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.business&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.bz&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.cab&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.camera&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.camp&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.cards&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.care&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.careers&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.casa&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.cash&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.catering&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.cc&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.cheap&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.church&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.city&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.claims&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.cleaning&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.clinic&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.clothing&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.club&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.cn.com&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.co&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.codes&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.coffee&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.com&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.community&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.company&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.computer&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.condos&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.construction&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.consulting&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.contractors&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.cooking&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.cool&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.country&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.credit&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.dance&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.degree&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.delivery&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.democrat&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.dental&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.diamonds&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.digital&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.direct&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.directory&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.discount&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.domains&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.education&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.email&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.energy&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.engineer&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.engineering&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.enterprises&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.equipment&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.estate&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.eu.com&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.events&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.exchange&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.expert&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.exposed&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.fail&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.finance&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.financial&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.fish&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.fishing&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.fitness&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.flights&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.florist&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.fm&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.forsale&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.foundation&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.fund&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.furniture&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.futbol&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.gallery&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.gb.com&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.gifts&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.gives&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.glass&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.graphics&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.gratis&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.gripe&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.guide&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.guru&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.haus&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.holdings&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.holiday&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.horse&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.house&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.hu.com&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.immo&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.immobilien&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.industries&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.info&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.ink&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.institute&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.insure&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.investments&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.io&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.jpn.com&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.kaufen&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.kim&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.kitchen&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.kiwi&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.kr.com&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.la&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.land&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.lc&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.lease&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.life&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.lighting&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.limo&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.loans&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.maison&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.management&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.market&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.marketing&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.me&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.media&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.mn&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.mobi&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.moda&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.moe&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.mortgage&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.nagoya&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.name&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.net&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.network&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.ninja&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.no.com&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.okinawa&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.org&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.partners&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.parts&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.photography&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.photos&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.pictures&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.pink&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.pizza&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.place&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.plumbing&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.press&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.productions&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.properties&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.pub&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.pw&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.qc.com&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.quebec&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.recipes&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.red&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.rehab&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.reisen&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.rentals&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.report&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.republican&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.rest&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.restaurant&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.reviews&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.rip&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.rocks&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.rodeo&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.ru.com&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.ryukyu&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.sa.com&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.sarl&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.sc&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.schule&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.se.com&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.services&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.sh&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.shiksha&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.shoes&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.singles&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.so&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.social&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.software&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.solar&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.solutions&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.soy&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.supplies&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.supply&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.support&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.surf&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.surgery&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.systems&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.tax&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.technology&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.tienda&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.tips&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.today&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.tokyo&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.tools&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.town&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.toys&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.training&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.tv&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.university&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.uno&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.us.com&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.uy.com&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.vacations&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.vc&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.vet&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.viajes&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.villas&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.vision&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.vodka&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.voyage&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.watch&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.website&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.wiki&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.work&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.works&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.world&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.ws&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.wtf&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.在线&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.移动&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.中文网&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.みんな&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.xyz&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.yoga&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.yokohama&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.za.com&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;.zone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about WHOIS privacy or your current setup, definitely &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/support&quot;&gt;let us know&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2015 10:23:48 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/02/whois-privacy-update.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/02/whois-privacy-update.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Found reviews - Fastmail, the &quot;slickest web interface currently available&quot;</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/assets/images/content/2015-02-13-fastmail.png&quot; alt=&quot;FastMail&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lemery.io/review-fastmail&quot;&gt;From Sebastian Lemery:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I pay $40 a year for FastMail. That&amp;#39;s $3.33 a month for something I use every day, multiple times an hour. Because I pay for this product, I get:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Customer service oriented towards my happiness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No ads&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A company focused on me, the customer, instead of advertisers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Features targeting users, not advertisers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cannot stress this enough: pay for what you use. I love that I pay Fastmail to handle my email. I enjoy knowing their engineers are making money, improving the app I thoroughly enjoy using. When you don&amp;#39;t pay for software, you create a void that must be filled by either selling your data or catering a product to advertisers. Even if you are indifferent, it still creates an environment where engineers are potentially assigned to features that appease advertisers over users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#39;re big fans of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fastmail.com&quot;&gt;FastMail&lt;/a&gt; here at iwantmyname, and this review seems pretty dead-on—it&amp;#39;s fast, reliable, and always customer-focused. If you&amp;#39;re on the market for a new email service, check FastMail out (also, using our Marketplace, you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/services/hosted-email/fastmail-mail-hosting-own-domain&quot;&gt;add it to your domain&lt;/a&gt; in a snap). &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2015 09:46:06 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/02/found-reviews-fastmail.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/02/found-reviews-fastmail.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>New in the Marketplace - QuickMVP, the easiest way to test your next big idea</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/assets/images/content/2015-02-12-quickmvp.png&quot; alt=&quot;5-Minute Technique&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How many times have you come up with a big idea, spent the money, time, and effort needed to get it going, only to watch it flame out after a few months due to a lack of traction. It&amp;#39;s hard to know how successful an idea will be before launch, but and easy way to find out is with &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/services/marketing/quickmvp&quot;&gt;QuickMVP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;QuickMVP&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;5-Minute Technique&amp;quot; is just about as simple as it sounds. You create a quick landing page that tests the demand for your idea, set up some Google Ads with their built-in ad creator to spread the word, then sit back and see what happens. It sounds ridiculously easy, but the methodology has been used successfully by many of today&amp;#39;s brightest entrepreneurs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#39;s a little case study from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://quickmvp.tumblr.com/post/88837748550/validating-an-ny-times-best-selling-title-with&quot;&gt;QuickMVP blog&lt;/a&gt; about Tim Ferriss&amp;#39; naming of The 4-Hour Workweek:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He bid on keywords related to the book’s content such as ‘401k’ and ‘language learning’: when those keywords formed part of someone’s search on Google the title popped up as a headline and the advertisement text would be the subtitle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ferriss was interested to see which of the advertisements would be clicked on most, knowing that he needed his title to compete with over 200,000 books published in the US each year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the week, for less than $200 Tim discovered that “The 4-Hour Workweek” had by far the best click-through rate. The rest is history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next time you&amp;#39;re in the testing stage of a big idea, keep &lt;a href=&quot;http://quickmvp.com&quot;&gt;QuickMVP&lt;/a&gt; in mind—it&amp;#39;s a bit of a no-brainer. The process isn&amp;#39;t quite free, but anything beats throwing money at an idea that might not be market-ready.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2015 15:50:10 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/02/new-in-the-marketplace-quickmvp.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/02/new-in-the-marketplace-quickmvp.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>4 tools for remembering your passwords... a year later</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/assets/images/content/2015-02-11-vault.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Vault&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#39;ve worked hard over the past half-decade making domain registration as easy as possible, but one pain point we often encounter is password memorization. The vast majority of our customers simply don&amp;#39;t need to interact with us very often, and what seems like a strong, easily remembered password could be completely alien when domain renewals come around a year later. But there are solutions for this very problem—all you need is a solid password manager.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#39;s an intro to password managers from &lt;a href=&quot;The%20paranoid%20guide%20to%20digital%20security&quot;&gt;Consumer Reports&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concept is straightforward: You sign up for a service that generates and stores a unique, strong password for each of the websites where you need log-in credentials. You can do that yourself if you have a savant-like memory for numbers, but in all likelihood you don’t. Then, you just need to remember one, excellent password in order to access the service. Yes, you may ask, but what if the password manager gets hacked? Not to worry, says Chris Soghoian. “Password managers encrypt their data, so these services are safe. And, ultimately, in 2015 it’s not a good idea to use the same password for more than one website. That effectively means that you have to outsource the task.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;1Password&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/assets/images/content/2015-02-11-one-password.png&quot; alt=&quot;1Password&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the name suggests, &lt;a href=&quot;https://agilebits.com/onepassword&quot;&gt;1Password&lt;/a&gt; is a tool that acts as a vault for all your passwords, secured by a single password of your creation. Basically, using a browser extension (available for Safari, Firefox, Chrome, and Opera), app, or smartphone app, you can open your vault with your master password and have instant access to all the passwords you&amp;#39;ve created, on any device you happen to be using.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#39;s a little excerpt from an extremely in-depth piece by the Sweet Setup, titled &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thesweetsetup.com/apps/best-password-manager-and-why-you-need-one/&quot;&gt;The best password manager (and why you need one) - 1Password&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, 1Password is the best app for managing your passwords because it does the best job of taking hold of our slippery digital identity, all the myriad digital bits of ourselves we use to prove who we are, and helps ease the friction of our travels through the digital world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#39;s another glowing review from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.macstories.net/reviews/1password-4-for-mac-review/&quot;&gt;MacStories&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every time a new version of 1Password comes out, I feel like repeating myself: if you’re serious about your secure data and web logins, you need 1Password. While it’s a great thing that Apple will be providing native options for increased password security and form-filling with iCloud Keychain, my recommendation still goes to 1Password if you’re looking for a dedicated app with more and better options aimed at managing your passwords, login details, credit card information, software licenses, and more. iCloud Keychain is meant for Safari, whereas 1Password is system-wide, powered by great customizable menus with keyboard shortcuts, and goes beyond web logins to let you encrypt and protect just about anything. I can’t work without 1Password.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;LastPass&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/assets/images/content/2015-02-11-lastpass.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;LastPass&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another good password manager is &lt;a href=&quot;https://lastpass.com&quot;&gt;LastPass&lt;/a&gt;, which works basically the same way 1Password does, but with a few less bells and whistles (although LastPass has been making huge strides), and a cheaper price (there&amp;#39;s a free option!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#39;s a bit from PC Mag&amp;#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pcmag.com/article2/0,2817,2426798,00.asp&quot;&gt;LastPass 3.0 review&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Storing all of your passwords in a single, secure password manager means you can use a different, strong password for every site, without worrying that you&amp;#39;ll forget. It also means that a successful attack on your password stash could give a hacker access to every one of your secure sites. If that thought worries you, the free LastPass 3.0 is just what you need. Your data is stored online in encrypted form that even the company can&amp;#39;t read, and it&amp;#39;s encrypted going to and from your PCs. You can protect your LastPass data with more different kinds of two-factor authentication than any other password manager I&amp;#39;ve encountered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Dashlane&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/assets/images/content/2015-02-11-dashlane.png&quot; alt=&quot;Dashlane&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dashlane.com&quot;&gt;Dashlane&lt;/a&gt; is similar in many ways to the other password managers on the market (if you want details, David Pogue wrote a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2013/06/06/technology/personaltech/too-many-passwords-and-no-way-to-remember-them-until-now.html&quot;&gt;very positive review&lt;/a&gt; in the New York Times, as did &lt;a href=&quot;http://thenextweb.com/apps/2014/12/09/dashlanes-automatic-password-changer-makes-precious-accounts-less-hackable/&quot;&gt;The Next Web&lt;/a&gt; in late 2014), but a new feature dropped in December that makes it extremely enticing. Here&amp;#39;s the description from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theverge.com/2014/12/9/7357251/dashlane-can-now-change-all-your-passwords-with-a-single-click-and&quot;&gt;the Verge&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dashlane, the subscription-based password management service, is introducing a feature today that ought to become standard in every product like it: the ability to change all your passwords with a single click, including accounts with two-factor authentication enabled. The feature will work with about 75 major websites at launch, including Amazon, Apple, Facebook, Google, LinkedIn, PayPal, Pinterest, and Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Password Changer, as the feature is called, is made possible by Dashlane’s acquisition of PassOmatic, a New York startup that developed the core technology. For now, it works on desktop versions of Dashlane for PC and Mac, though the company is working on a mobile version. Dashlane now includes a big green &amp;quot;change all passwords&amp;quot; button; click it, and it will replace your existing passwords with ones that are unique and randomly generated. If you have two-factor authentication enabled, a pop-up will ask you for a code or for the answer to a security question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Safari Passwords&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to avoid the master password thing and just want a simple password storage system, the Safari Password Manager is a pretty nice tool. Basically, when you&amp;#39;re setting up an account online, Safari can auto-generate and save a secure password that will sync via iCloud Keychain for you to use on any device. It&amp;#39;s incredibly easy, but for some, it might be too easy. Here&amp;#39;s a specific pain-point, from the pro-1Password &lt;a href=&quot;http://thesweetsetup.com/apps/best-password-manager-and-why-you-need-one/&quot;&gt;Sweet Setup&lt;/a&gt; article above:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Different people also have different levels of comfort with iCloud Keychain. I, for one, don’t actually love the frictionless experience. I want to be intentional about how I use my passwords and my credit card information, and I like how 1Password makes me conscious of when I’m using those things. I also like how I have more control over access to my information on my devices. I can require a login to 1Password after not using it for even a few minutes. I also like that if my daughter is using my iPad, she can’t easily hop over to Zappos and buy herself a new pair of shoes with my credit card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, practically anything is better than using the same passwords for all your online accounts (or forgetting your clever creations after a week), and without the help of a password manager, that&amp;#39;s almost always what happens. So before you create yet another password you&amp;#39;ll forget, do a little comparison shopping and leave the memorization to the machines. It&amp;#39;ll change your online life forever.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2015 15:34:45 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/02/tools-for-remembering-your-passwords.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/02/tools-for-remembering-your-passwords.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>New in the Marketplace - PodBean, the podcast platform with its own network</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/assets/images/content/2015-02-10-podbean-best-of.png&quot; alt=&quot;Best of&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/services&quot;&gt;App Marketplace&lt;/a&gt; is filled with dozens of great platforms you can add to your domain with just a few clicks (no DNS knowledge required), and in 2015, we’re looking to add a ton more. As we add new platforms to the list, you can get a little taste of what they offer here in the &amp;quot;New in the Marketplace&amp;quot; blog series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the more interesting challenges podcasters face is exposure, and most of the podcast hosting platforms on the market don’t provide much in terms of built-in audiences. &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/services/podcast/podbean&quot;&gt;PodBean&lt;/a&gt; does, and their built-in podcast marketplace has more than 500,000 independent podcasts covering any category you could ever want. And on top of that, PodBean gives you the tools you need to create customizable websites that can instantly ship shows off to all the biggest podcatchers, with options like unlimited bandwidth and storage, a simple platform for creating premium content, and advertising options via third-party networks for additional monetization. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/assets/images/content/2015-02-10-podbean.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;PodBean&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pricing starts at $3/mo, so if you’re looking for a podcast host that does it all, be sure to check out &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.podbean.com&quot;&gt;PodBean&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2015 16:21:18 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/02/new-in-the-marketplace-podbean.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/02/new-in-the-marketplace-podbean.html</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
