<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>iwantmyname Domain Blog</title>
		<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/</link>
		<atom:link href="https://iwantmyname.com/blog/feeds/posts/recent.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Every TLD has a story</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://priceonomics.com/the-rise-and-fall-of-ly/&#34;&gt;Rosie Cima on the rise and fall of .LY:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, in 2011, civil war broke out in Libya. One of the main registrars of .ly addresses, Libyan Spider, was shut down, apparently as part of UN/US sanctions on Libya. For a time, the owners of Libyan Spider were only able to revive these urls by leaving the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The start-up Letter.ly also announced that it had gone down because it had let its domain registration expire, and it could not establish contact with the registrar to renew it’s contract. “Sorry for the hassle,” they wrote in an email to their users. “it’s amazing that a physical war has affected our service in this way.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 07:00:21 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/10/every-tld-has-a-story.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/10/every-tld-has-a-story.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>An educated guess as to why domain name growth has been stalling</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.circleid.com/posts/20150716_where_has_the_domain_name_growth_gone/&#34;&gt;Jay Dailey, Chief Executive of the .nz registry, on slowing domain name growth:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The impact of new gTLDs has been to solve the &amp;lsquo;meaningfulness problem&amp;rsquo; by the creation of hundreds of new gTLDs and this in turn directly affects the perception of scarcity. This reduction in scarcity is in turn reducing the incentive to speculate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is my assertion that this speculative behaviour has been a significant factor in historical growth and so domain name growth prospects are partly dependent on what happens to that behaviour. At the macro level, global speculative behaviour in domain names will reduce and the money will switch to a different scarce asset, permanently leaving our industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the foreseeable future people will need domain names to create things on the internet, so registrars will be fine (although the days of bananas growth might be over). But the owners of these new gTLDs are probably sweating a bit. Their &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.geek.com/news/gtlds-whats-the-process-and-how-much-pay-icann-1392947/&#34;&gt;$185,000 investments&lt;/a&gt; might take much longer than expected to return a profit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2015 12:30:00 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/10/an-educated-guess-as-to-why-domain-name-growth-has-been-stalling.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/10/an-educated-guess-as-to-why-domain-name-growth-has-been-stalling.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Too much choice might be a bad thing</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2015/oct/21/choice-stressing-us-out-dating-partners-monopolies&#34;&gt;Stuart Jeffries on the stress that choice induces:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time in Springfield, the Simpson family visited a new supermarket. Monstromart’s slogan was “where shopping is a baffling ordeal”. Product choice was unlimited, shelving reached the ceiling, nutmeg came in 12lb boxes and the express checkout had a sign reading, “1,000 items or less”. In the end the Simpsons returned to Apu’s Kwik-E-Mart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In doing so, the Simpsons were making a choice to reduce their choice. It wasn’t quite a rational choice, but it made sense. In the parlance of economic theory, they were not rational utility maximisers but, in Herbert Simon’s term, “satisficers” – opting for what was good enough, rather than becoming confused to the point of inertia in front of Monstromart’s ranges of products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;d be interesting to see how the domain industry, as a whole, is faring with &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/new-gtld-domain-extensions&#34;&gt;500+ (and counting) new gTLDs&lt;/a&gt; on the shelves. (Sometimes I think we should just pick the top 25 and say, &amp;ldquo;This is what we&amp;rsquo;re selling because these are the good ones!&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2015 08:00:21 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/10/too-much-choice-might-be-a-bad-thing.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/10/too-much-choice-might-be-a-bad-thing.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Solving the new privacy Rubik’s Cube</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.microsoft.com/eupolicy/2015/10/20/the-collapse-of-the-u-s-eu-safe-harbor-solving-the-new-privacy-rubiks-cube/&#34;&gt;Brad Smith, Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s President and Chief Legal Officer, on the collapse of the EU-US Safe Harbor:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need to protect privacy as a fundamental human right. We need a global Internet. We need to keep the public safe. And we need to find a legal path that will work on both sides of the Atlantic. We need to do all four of these things together and simultaneously. This is the privacy version of a Rubik’s Cube.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we’re going to find a long-term and sustainable approach, we need to think afresh. The leading privacy law in the United States was adopted in 1986. The laws in Europe come from the same era. The approaches that were developed fifteen years before the 20th century ended are simply not adequate fifteen years after the 21st century began. It’s not just technology that has changed. The world has changed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2015 15:55:21 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/10/solving-the-new-privacy-rubiks-cube.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/10/solving-the-new-privacy-rubiks-cube.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Death and digital properties</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple hundred years ago, it was possible to live and die leaving pretty much zero physical evidence of your existence. Except perhaps some kids. Today, though, someone with no identity footprint would be nearly unheard of. I&amp;rsquo;m even skeptical of companies that don&amp;rsquo;t have websites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that so many of us have these broad digital presences — websites, email accounts, social media profiles, photos, videos, text — the footprints we leave behind may require some maintenance and planning. After all, your online self is as much a part of your life as your photo albums,  household items, and collectibles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond keeping payment details updated, domains renewed, passwords secure, etc., we need to consider life&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;what ifs?&amp;rdquo; Or &amp;ldquo;hit by a bus&amp;rdquo; scenarios, as we&amp;rsquo;ve called them at a few places I&amp;rsquo;ve worked. What happens if you&amp;rsquo;re not there tomorrow? Maybe you moved on to a new job, left a relationship, or actually were hit by a bus!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can anyone else access your accounts? Do you want them to? Did you want any of your online profiles or properties to be left accessible? Are there going to be business issues with websites or email accounts if domains were registered in your name and paid for by your credit card?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It doesn&amp;rsquo;t tend to be something we give a lot of thought to. Maybe once a year when you get a domain renewal notice. Or when a site has a security breach and you&amp;rsquo;re advised to change your password. But it&amp;rsquo;s something our team deals with regularly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;So and so has left the company and&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; begins a lot of emails we receive. Some employee has set up an account with their email address, registered the company&amp;rsquo;s domain(s), and paid for them with their credit card. And now no one knows the login, the email address no longer works, and the credit card has been cancelled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If they&amp;rsquo;re lucky, they figure this out &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; the website and email stop working, but not always. As often as not the emails we get are somewhat panicked. But while we understand customers&amp;rsquo; predicaments in these cases, we can&amp;rsquo;t just hand over the keys, so to speak. We need to authenticate who has access to the account, who owns the domains(s), etc., to prevent straight-up theft. You don&amp;rsquo;t want to end up dealing with one of these situations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, how can you keep your online properties up to date, and make sure those who need administrative access to accounts can get it when needed?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-1&#34;&gt;Avoid registering business accounts or domains with personal information&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-2&#34;&gt;What will happen if you can&amp;rsquo;t access an account or there&amp;rsquo;s a dispute&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-3&#34;&gt;What will happen if you die&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-4&#34;&gt;Just part of being a grownup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-1&#34;&gt;Avoid registering business accounts or domains with personal information&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s pretty common for things like domains and social media accounts to be assigned to a primary person. Since you&amp;rsquo;re asked for personal details like name and email address (and sometimes &lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; to provide an individual information rather than company information), it seems like a no-brainer to use your own details. If you can avoid that, do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use an organizational email address that more than one person has access to. That way others will have the login, or at the very least can get and use a password reset email if needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have to use an individual&amp;rsquo;s name on an account, so be it, use yours or an administrative one, but be sure to include the organization&amp;rsquo;s name in the &lt;em&gt;Company&lt;/em&gt; field as well. It provides some link to the company if we hear from someone who&amp;rsquo;s not the main contact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be aware when registering domains that the registrant or owner contact name is the legal owner of the domain. Even if the person worked for your company and registered the domain on behalf of the company. If the registrant contact says John Smith, it&amp;rsquo;s legally John Smith&amp;rsquo;s domain name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If possible, register the domain under the company name, not a person&amp;rsquo;s name. Note that our system automatically adds the account contact information as the registrant information, but you can update that in your dashboard under &lt;strong&gt;edit contacts&lt;/strong&gt;, or, in some cases (like ccTLDs), we can do it for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If possible, use a corporate credit card under the company or organization&amp;rsquo;s name. There&amp;rsquo;s (perhaps) a better chance of someone tracking its use and when expiry dates will need to be updated, for example. The more data points we have for the organization, the easier it will be to prove who owns or should have access to the account and domains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When there&amp;rsquo;s an issue of account access, we request proof of ID for the account holder and a partial scan of the card on the account. Take a look at your account details and ask yourself if anyone else would be able to provide them if you&amp;rsquo;re not around to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-2&#34;&gt;What will happen if you can&#39;t access an account or there&#39;s a dispute&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At best, we require an assortment of proof of identification and ownership. At worst, if there seems to be an issue, or information isn&amp;rsquo;t clear, we lock down accounts while we wait for more information (for as long as necessary&amp;hellip;even if your website and email are down).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That means no party can access it, which means if a credit card is invalid, domains can&amp;rsquo;t be renewed and may expire and be lost. If something goes wrong with DNS or hosting, a site may remain offline or emails will bounce. You can imagine this could be a serious problem for businesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it&amp;rsquo;s just a customer who&amp;rsquo;s forgotten a password, we can send a password reset email, or do our standard authentication to help them get back into their own account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If one party claims another party has left a company, for example, and they need access to the account for the domains, we will take a look at the account. We&amp;rsquo;ll see what evidence there is that the domains belong to the company. We&amp;rsquo;ll see what other domains are in the account. (We&amp;rsquo;re not going to hand over account access if there&amp;rsquo;s one company domain and 10 that appear to be personal and unrelated.) We will ask for authentication documentation for the company, alleged former employee, person asking for access, and whatever else we feel is necessary to prove ownership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We take customer account security very seriously, which can be frustrating for some people. But just imagine someone was trying to get access to &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; accounts or domains. Would you want us to hand over access just based on an email saying, &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Let me in&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-3&#34;&gt;What will happen if you die&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s up to you. Some people may want their web properties&amp;rsquo; content archived, or their friends or families might. Some people might want everything to eventually expire and be deleted. Some people might have secret accounts or profiles they don&amp;rsquo;t want anyone to know about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s pretty common, in addition to a formal will, to have a more informal list of requests, bequests, or instructions. We&amp;rsquo;d recommend adding a section about your digital properties there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re big fans of password management programs, and if you use one of those, there&amp;rsquo;s a good chance you just need to keep track of one password. Record it with your will and any related documents. Remember to update it when you update your password(s). Then someone will be able to maintain or remove your accounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thedigitalbeyond.com/online-services-list/&#34;&gt;There are also a variety of sites and tools to help manage digital legacies.&lt;/a&gt; Whether it&amp;rsquo;s checking regularly whether you&amp;rsquo;re still alive or not, sending out posthumous messages to loved ones, providing a place for those who cared about you to memorialize you, or wiping accounts or files you don&amp;rsquo;t want anyone else to know about, handling our digital afterlives can be well covered.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember, too, that a lot of work can go into sorting things out and tying up loose ends after someone dies, and the people left doing it are often tired, sad, and stressed. It&amp;rsquo;s a kindness to make these arrangements in advance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-4&#34;&gt;Just part of being a grownup&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Occasionally we complain that websites or apps want too much personal information from us when we try to set up accounts or start using them. But in general, it&amp;rsquo;s extremely easy to create new digital footprints online. It&amp;rsquo;s actually often harder to erase them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of this, many of us give little thought to how broad our digital presences and properties actually are. Sure, many of us have plenty of little-used and abandoned accounts. They don&amp;rsquo;t cost us time or money (maybe a little email spam). But many of us &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; have online presences and properties that are important to us, and to others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For various reasons, if and when we&amp;rsquo;re not around to take care of them, like any good property management, it&amp;rsquo;s the grownup and responsible thing to do to make sure someone else can.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2015 15:55:21 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/10/death-and-digital-properties.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/10/death-and-digital-properties.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Anyone can build a small business website (even you)</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The commonly told tale is that website building is for &amp;ldquo;computer geniuses&amp;rdquo; who&amp;rsquo;ve been churning out complicated code for much of their waking lives. But it&amp;rsquo;s not true. Sure, building a massive site for a global corporation is a huge undertaking, but the tools exist, right now, for small business owners of any computer skill level to quickly create beautiful sites and online stores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t believe me? Read on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-1&#34;&gt;Step 1: Get a domain name&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-2&#34;&gt;Step 2: Choose a website platform&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-3&#34;&gt;Step 3: Install your domain to your website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-4&#34;&gt;Step 4: Get a custom email address&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-1&#34;&gt;Step 1: Get a domain name&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choosing a domain name, particularly the part after the dot (as in BUSINESSNAME dot COM), may seem like an arbitrary task, but it&amp;rsquo;s your first step to establishing legitimacy. There&amp;rsquo;s plenty of content on the web that goes over this in some detail—including &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/06/how-to-pick-the-right-domain-extension.html&#34;&gt;our guide&lt;/a&gt;—but let&amp;rsquo;s reframe it here from a traditional business perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think of your domain as the location of your shop. As with a shop, you generally want to be front-and-center on the best street in town (location, location, location!) to get the most traffic. In the world of domains, here&amp;rsquo;s how the city is layed out:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;.COM = Main Street, and the shorter your domain is, the closer you are to the center of town&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Popular extensions (the ones you&amp;rsquo;ve probably heard of) like .CO, .NET, .IO, and your country&amp;rsquo;s ccTLD (like .NZ for New Zealand) = other streets near the center of town&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;.PIZZA, .CLUB, and the new gTLDs = the suburbs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like any business, if you&amp;rsquo;re on top of your game, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter where you&amp;rsquo;re located. But at the moment, businesses are thought to be more legitimate if they&amp;rsquo;re not in an obscure location. Legitimacy is a fickle thing though—new domain extensions, like new suburbs, can grow quickly. So don&amp;rsquo;t let the fact that the domain you want in the .COM namespace is taken hold you back from starting a website. (But if you&amp;rsquo;re interested in buying that killer .COM from its current owner, &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/05/the-guide-to-getting-the-right-domain-name-for-your-brand.html&#34;&gt;here&amp;rsquo;s our guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that&amp;rsquo;s perhaps more in your control is what goes before the dot. Here&amp;rsquo;s the basic rule: go with the name of your brand in its simplest form—don&amp;rsquo;t add identifiers that don&amp;rsquo;t belong like &amp;ldquo;buy&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;store&amp;rdquo;. So if your business name is Layshock Limo:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;layshocklimo.com = good
layshock.limo = in the suburbs, but it&amp;rsquo;s short and memorable, which is good
ridelayshocklimo.com = not as good&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Does your domain name have a sketchy past?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technically, you can name your website anything you want, but like all things, names come with histories. Even if you have a sparkling marketing plan, getting unfavorable search results when seeking your site can be a killer. So do your research. Here&amp;rsquo;s a little video guide from Matt Cutts of Google Webmasters on how you can protect yourself from registering domain names with iffy histories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/C-EdhaMDXho&#34; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To recap, here are his three three main tips:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do a &amp;ldquo;site: DOMAINNAME.com&amp;rdquo; search. If you see anything fishy, be weary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Search for the domain name without the domain extension. So instead of &amp;ldquo;site: DOMAINNAME.com&amp;rdquo;, just search for &amp;ldquo;DOMAINNAME.&amp;rdquo; You never know what you might find.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Search for your desired domain on &lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.org/&#34;&gt;archive.org&lt;/a&gt;. If your site used to be a scam site, you could suffer a continued SEO hit. Also note that if your site used to be something you find unsavory, you may get residual unsavory emails.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-2&#34;&gt;Step 2: Choose a website platform&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the complicated part—or what used to be the complicated part. Ten years ago, creating a website meant finding some server space, installing your platform of choice onto that server space, then messing with some combination of a template (which meant a good deal of trial and error, even after learning some rudimentary coding skills) and some plugins until you&amp;rsquo;ve created something you&amp;rsquo;re remotely happy with. E-commerce was always tricky, keeping things updated was always a chore, and if you forgot to backup your site&amp;hellip; kapow! All gone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things today are quite different. In the &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/services&#34;&gt;iwantmyname Marketplace&lt;/a&gt;, we&amp;rsquo;ve cultivated a number of platforms that do it all. The templates are all professionally made and are often able to be changed with simple drag-and-drop interfaces. And they come stock with tools that make online shopping, marketing, and once-difficult tasks like displaying photo galleries and menus as easy as could be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, be sure to do a little research before picking the platform to want to go with. Platforms vary greatly in price, features, and general ease-of-use, so it&amp;rsquo;s important to find what&amp;rsquo;s best for your needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a few to start your search with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/features/applications/custom-domain-apps/websites/squarespace-build-your-website-with-own-url&#34;&gt;Squarespace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter what kind of site you&amp;rsquo;re looking to build, Squarespace has the tools you need. Just to list, they have templates and tools designed for businesses, online shopping sites, physical stores, restaurants (with amazing location and menu features), musicians, podcast hosts (you can serve shows directly from Squarespace to iTunes), photographers, and painters. And they&amp;rsquo;re adding new tools and features all the time, so the platform never gets stale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/features/applications/custom-domain-apps/websites/weebly-create-free-website-with-own-address&#34;&gt;Weebly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Decisions, decisions. In a lot of ways, Weebly is a lot like Squarespace. They have great online shopping solutions, offer simple drag-and-drop tools for website creation, and have some beautiful templates to choose from. Fortunately, you can try both out for free before you decide to plop your money down—so we&amp;rsquo;d recommend that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/services/ecommerce-hosting/big-cartel-custom-domain&#34;&gt;Big Cartel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re an artist, photographer, builder, sewer, or anyone making beautiful goods, Big Cartel is an e-commerce-only solution to check out. Their platform is extremely easy to use (they&amp;rsquo;ve been building it up since 2005), they specialize in showing off independent makers, and they&amp;rsquo;re still small enough to give you some honest personal attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-3&#34;&gt;Step 3: Install your domain to your website&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Easy. As. Pie. When you log in and look at your domains, you&amp;rsquo;ll see an Apps &amp;amp; Services column to the right of your domains. Just click &amp;ldquo;Install new service,&amp;rdquo; pick the platform you want, and follow the simple directions (it&amp;rsquo;s pretty much a one-click solution). And that&amp;rsquo;s it! (If you have any trouble though, don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/support&#34;&gt;let us know&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-4&#34;&gt;Step 4: Get a custom email address&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the secret sauce for having a successful small business site. If you&amp;rsquo;re trying to do real business, contacting customers and clients with an @gmail.com, @me.com, or @yahoo.com address is a nightmare for legitimacy. Those are free email services that anyone can sign up and use! (Just think about it—would you be more likely to respond to tim@apple.com or appletim@me.com?) What you need is an email address that&amp;rsquo;s attached to your domain, and it&amp;rsquo;s way easier to setup than you think. Just &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/06/the-guide-to-getting-your-own-custom-email-address.html&#34;&gt;head over to our simple guide&lt;/a&gt; to get started.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 14:49:59 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/09/anyone-can-build-a-small-business-website.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/09/anyone-can-build-a-small-business-website.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>The iwantmyname guide to blogging (and actually owning your content)</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Math is hard. Running a marathon is hard. Writing on the web, no matter what anyone tells you, is not hard. In fact, it&amp;rsquo;s become so easy that you pick up a following writing nothing more than 140 character messages riddled with abbreviated words, hashtags, and @ replies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s hard is writing words that matter. Evergreen content. Posts that, in a decade, people will still be able to read and discuss. This kind of writing requires a bit of planning, a bit of structure, and a willingness to forego the immediate &amp;ldquo;viral-ness&amp;rdquo; of social media—but if you stick with it, you&amp;rsquo;ll have a real collection of content that&amp;rsquo;ll withstand the fickle nature of the social web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-1&#34;&gt;Beware purely social platforms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-2&#34;&gt;Unless you&amp;rsquo;re internet famous, branding is important&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-3&#34;&gt;Choosing the right blog hosting platform&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-4&#34;&gt;Always have an exit plan in mind&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-5&#34;&gt;Your domain name matters, but maybe less than you think&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-1&#34;&gt;Beware purely social platforms&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.businessinsider.com/robert-scoble-why-im-still-betting-my-future-on-google-2011-9&#34;&gt;From Robert Scoble, circa 2011:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do you best capture the EMOTION of your time? Blogging? Not for me anymore. Tweeting? Not for me anymore (I will continue being there, mostly to let people who won&amp;rsquo;t leave that system know what I&amp;rsquo;m doing and where I&amp;rsquo;m doing it &amp;mdash; it has turned into a UI for my Facebook and Google behaviors). Facebooking? Yes. I&amp;rsquo;m still there and will be for forseeable future at &lt;a href=&#34;http://facebook.com/robertscoble&#34;&gt;http://facebook.com/robertscoble&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But my hub is Google+.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a past life, Robert Scoble was one of the many go-to industry insiders worth reading. But for most of this decade, he&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;pivoted&amp;rdquo; from blogging to social media to pursue the active engagement social media brings—and has been a pretty vocal advocate for the rest of us doing the same. His results though don&amp;rsquo;t seem all that rewarding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exhibit 1 is his love affair with Google+. He poured years of content into that platform, amassed nearly seven million followers, and is now perhaps the biggest boat on a dried up lake. Google+ is pretty much a dead platform these days, and the content on it might as well not exist. Now, Scoble&amp;rsquo;s primarily on Facebook, posting multiple times a day on a platform known for spotty content delivery unless you&amp;rsquo;re willing to pay to promote it. (On a personal note, our Facebook posts routinely get delivered to only 15% of our audience—hardly something we&amp;rsquo;d like to pour too much time into.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exhibit 2 is his standing on Google Trends, which tracks news headlines over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/media/2015-08-31-scoble-trend.png&#34; alt=&#34;Scoble trend&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not saying there&amp;rsquo;s a one-to-one correlation between his move to social and his flagging popularity (on Google Trends), but from an outsider&amp;rsquo;s perspective, the move certainly doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem like it&amp;rsquo;s helping his newsworthiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-2&#34;&gt;Unless you&#39;re internet famous, branding is important&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the biggest negative with social media is that with it, you&amp;rsquo;re forever tied to the platform you&amp;rsquo;re on. Modern social sites have little-to-no customization (Facebook, Twitter, and Medium look the same no matter what page you&amp;rsquo;re on), their URL structure is almost universally www.platformname.com/username, and they all come with unique baggage. Platform X is for this clique; Platform Y used to be cool until the adults arrived, etc., etc. Really, unless you&amp;rsquo;re internet famous (like Robert Scoble), fighting this uphill branding battle on social media sites seems crazy. Having a blog on a custom domain might not give the immediate gratification of a Facebook Like, but it&amp;rsquo;s still the best way to seem like a person who should be taken seriously on the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus, with a custom domain name, you can &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/06/the-guide-to-getting-your-own-custom-email-address.html&#34;&gt;pair your credible blog with a custom email address&lt;/a&gt; (a big deal if your blog ever gets media attention).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-3&#34;&gt;Choosing the right blog hosting platform&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First off, it&amp;rsquo;s important to know that there is no &lt;em&gt;perfect&lt;/em&gt; blog platform. Every platform will have a different set of pros and cons, so it&amp;rsquo;s important to do a little research to match your needs. Do you like writing in Markdown? Do you want extra site-building features on top of general blogging? Do you want your files to be stored in a Dropbox folder instead of a closed cloud? Is price a concern?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a few options from our &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/services&#34;&gt;Marketplace&lt;/a&gt; to start with, broken down by what they do:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;General website builders (with blog functionality)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/features/applications/custom-domain-apps/websites/squarespace-build-your-website-with-own-url&#34;&gt;Squarespace&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/features/applications/custom-domain-apps/websites/weebly-create-free-website-with-own-address&#34;&gt;Weebly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Blog hosting platforms:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/services/blog-hosting/ghost-custom-domain&#34;&gt;Ghost&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/features/applications/custom-domain-apps/blogs/tumblr-tumblelog-easy-blog-with-own-url&#34;&gt;Tumblr&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/services/blog-hosting/postagon-custom-domain&#34;&gt;Postagon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/services/blog-hosting/posthaven-custom-domain&#34;&gt;Posthaven&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/services/blog-hosting/silvrback-custom-domain&#34;&gt;Silvrback&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;WordPress hosting:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/services/blog-hosting/wpengine-wordpress-custom-domain&#34;&gt;WP Engine&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/services/blog-hosting/register-custom-domain-page.ly&#34;&gt;Page.ly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Based on Dropbox or Evernote (content stays on your computer):&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/services/blog-hosting/postachio&#34;&gt;Postach.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;For developers:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/services/developer/setup-custom-domain-amazon-s3&#34;&gt;Amazon S3&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/services/developer/github-pages-custom-domain&#34;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-4&#34;&gt;Always have an exit plan in mind&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s nice about owning your own domain is that if you don&amp;rsquo;t like the blog platform you&amp;rsquo;re on, you can move without confusing your readers. For example, if you&amp;rsquo;re blogging on Ghost one day, then realize you want to start leveraging your personal brand to start selling things online the next, you can migrate your content to Squarespace without losing your domain. Plus, because you already have a domain and you&amp;rsquo;re not moving to a closed social platform, you won&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about your brand name being taken on the next platform you&amp;rsquo;re headed to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So before you make any platform decision, be sure to look for a solid import/export tool. Make sure you can easily take all your content with you in case you want to jump platforms—and don&amp;rsquo;t compromise. Better and better platforms are coming out all the time, so getting stuck with something you&amp;rsquo;re not happy with is solely on you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-5&#34;&gt;Your domain name matters, but maybe less than you think&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having a killer domain name is a nice thing when you&amp;rsquo;re telling your friends about your site, but as the spread of content moves to social, it matters less now than ever. Remember that while social media isn&amp;rsquo;t great as your primary content bucket, it&amp;rsquo;s definitely good for spreading your content. Articles from your blog might get tweeted, posted, retweeted, commented on, etc., and on social media, the quality of the domain names means a lot less than the quality of the person posting the message (for example, you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t click on an strange site sent from a complete stranger, but you might if it were sent from your best friend).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Social media sharing aside, your primary objective when choosing a domain name is to not look like a spam site. &lt;a href=&#34;https://moz.com/learn/seo/domain&#34;&gt;Here are some simple tips from Moz&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid hyphens. Hyphens detract from credibility and can act as a spam indicator.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Top-level domains (like .com) are the extensions associated with domain names. For best ranking results, avoid uncommon top-level domains (TLDs). Like hyphens, TLDs such as .info, .cc, .ws, and .name are spam indicators.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid domain names longer than 15 characters. Short domain names are easier to remember, easier to share, and have a smaller chance of resulting in typos.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want more of an in-depth look at our thoughts on which TLD you should be using for your site, &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/06/how-to-pick-the-right-domain-extension.html&#34;&gt;here&amp;rsquo;s the guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2015 13:30:58 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/08/the-iwantmyname-guide-to-blogging.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/08/the-iwantmyname-guide-to-blogging.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Get your personal brand in tip-top shape</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re an adult of a certain age, the idea of a personal brand is a fascinating concept. A few decades ago, your personal brand boiled down to how you dressed, where you worked, and what social clubs you were a part of. But now your personal brand follows you everywhere on the web. It&amp;rsquo;s your social network, your resume, your photos, and quips. It&amp;rsquo;s a pervasive, evolving mass, and if you don&amp;rsquo;t cultivate it correctly, bits of your identity can erode without much thought. So let&amp;rsquo;s take a closer look at how you can get your personal brand in order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-1&#34;&gt;Nothing is permanent on the social web&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-2&#34;&gt;It starts to matter when your personal brand goes pro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-3&#34;&gt;Getting the right domain extension&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-4&#34;&gt;Platforms for creating a personal website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-5&#34;&gt;Your personal brand needs a custom email address&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-6&#34;&gt;Thoughts on reserving the digital future of your child&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-1&#34;&gt;Nothing is permanent on the social web&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the rub. Social media has made it easier than ever before in history to spread your ideas and actions online. Have a baby? Posting a picture on Facebook is easier than making instant coffee. Have a thought? Tweet it in two seconds. Want to write something long form? Medium will get it to the world in a snap. But you don&amp;rsquo;t own this content. Your baby picture is Facebook&amp;rsquo;s baby picture, on Facebook&amp;rsquo;s layout, with Facebook&amp;rsquo;s targeted ads hovering nearby (remember, on most social networks, &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; aren&amp;rsquo;t the customer, the advertisers are).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a lot of people, this situation is fine. But think about it for a second. The social web is only in its infancy. Facebook, Twitter, Medium—in 10 years, do you think you&amp;rsquo;ll still be using them? If not, where will that content go? Without a brand hub, you have nothing permanent—it&amp;rsquo;s like having a lot of friends with couches to sleep on, but no home. Looking long term, that&amp;rsquo;s a scary proposition. Especially if you ever want your personal brand to go pro.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-2&#34;&gt;It starts to matter when your personal brand goes pro&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was talking to a local artist the other day about how to leverage his online persona into real sales, and there&amp;rsquo;s no simple answer. But there are a few key points to note.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Your central hub can&amp;rsquo;t be a social network&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are a creator of things, your livelihood relies on people consistently being able to find you. You need a home that can withstand the whims of the market—remember, MySpace was the biggest thing on the web only a decade ago, and it&amp;rsquo;s not like people could just move that content to another platform with the same domain name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, be wary of using closed platforms with big social components as your main sales hub. The artist I was talking to had moved the majority of his sales over to Etsy, but once you go that route, you give up nearly all control over the experience. Your domain will have etsy.com in it, the site will look like an Etsy site, and most importantly, your brand will become tied to Etsy&amp;rsquo;s. Just think about it. Do you really want your brand to be an Etsy store? Maybe so, maybe no—but you can&amp;rsquo;t deny the existence of a brand connotation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a more analytics-geared answer, &lt;a href=&#34;https://moz.com/blog/answers-to-4-excellent-seo-questions&#34;&gt;Rand Fishkin of Moz says&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d always bias to taking the website over the social media presence. It&amp;rsquo;s not that a great Twitter, Facebook, Yelp, Foursquare or LinkedIn account aren&amp;rsquo;t great, it&amp;rsquo;s just that the flexibility, power, branding and measurability of a website has yet to be matched on any platform. With a website, you can custom build virtually any form of analytics, leverage any type of web technology to display/deliver content and control your own destiny. Even if Facebook or some other new, wholly flexible platform allowed for all of these features, you would still never truly own your home on the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a huge supporter of and advocate for social media marketing, but I don&amp;rsquo;t think I could ever endorse having your primary base of marketing and acquisition happen anywhere but on a site you fully own and control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Social media is a wonderful &lt;em&gt;marketing&lt;/em&gt; tool&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The keyword is &lt;em&gt;marketing&lt;/em&gt;. And on the marketing front, you should do all you can create authentic experiences that touch as many people as possible. But whether you do daily process shots on Instagram, talk to fans on Twitter, or organize events on Facebook, the key here is consistency. Like a good blog, you&amp;rsquo;re never going to build an audience with inconsistent posts—but unlike a blog, the instant consumability of social media requires you to be posting &lt;em&gt;all the time&lt;/em&gt;. Seriously. Daily Instagram posts, hourly tweets, twice-weekly Facebook events. Once you&amp;rsquo;re a part of someone else&amp;rsquo;s stream, you&amp;rsquo;re competing against the 100+ other things that person is following. It might seem like a lot, but the marketing benefits of having thousands of followers is huge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-3&#34;&gt;Getting the right domain extension&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, personal branding is the hardest of all the branding types. Seriously. (How many failed aliases have you tried to use in the last decade? I&amp;rsquo;m at three.). But now that the new generic top-level domains have launched, getting your real name on the left side of the dot is easier than ever. So what domain extension do you want on the other side?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Picking the right one can be tricky, and there are a number of things you should consider before making your choice. Let&amp;rsquo;s break down some of your options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;.COM&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most obvious choice for your personal site is yourname.com, and that&amp;rsquo;s probably the choice I&amp;rsquo;d make if it were available to me. If your name is rare enough for this to even be an option, your only real consideration should be whether you should go with lastname.com or fullname.com. I personally prefer lastname.com, because email addresses like chris@hall.com look nicer than chris@chrishall.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;.CO and .ME&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next to &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/com-domain-name-registration-for-commercial&#34;&gt;.COM&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/co-colombian-domain-name-registration-for-colombia&#34;&gt;.CO&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/me-montenegrean-domain-name-registration-for-montenegro&#34;&gt;.ME&lt;/a&gt; seem to be the next most common choices for personal sites. And in 2012, they were excellent choices, if only because they freed you from the confines of the .COM namespace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, the flood of new domain extensions allow me to be picky, and I do have some concerns with these specific two. Starting with .CO, my primary concern is spelling errors—particularly with people unconsciously adding an &amp;ldquo;m&amp;rdquo; to .CO when sending emails. .ME is a little safer in that no one will mistake it for another extension, but I always wonder if people think .ME has an Apple affiliation due to the recently retired Mobile Me (I still regularly use my @me.com email address).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Your local ccTLD&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Country code top-level domains (ccTLDs) are super popular around the world (aside for the US), and they make for wonderful personal domain names. For example, if you&amp;rsquo;re a designer who does the bulk of your work in New Zealand, picking up a &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-nz&#34;&gt;.NZ&lt;/a&gt; (or &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-kiwi&#34;&gt;.KIWI&lt;/a&gt;) domain name is a great choice. Due to popularity, many basic names will already be taken, but if your parents were adventurous types, there&amp;rsquo;s a good chance your name will be available (I desperately tried to rename myself Bowser as a child, and BowserHall is available in just about every extension).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Letters and phrases you identify with&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A very similar topic was brought up recently on &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=8466018&#34;&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt;, and one of the replies fits perfectly into this category.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use the .gg TLD. My personal site is bram.gg and my email is hello@bram.gg&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.gg is my favorite TLD, and the most underrated. It&amp;rsquo;s expensive enough that the domain you want probably isn&amp;rsquo;t taken, but cheap enough that it&amp;rsquo;s worth the price if it&amp;rsquo;s something you care about. &amp;ldquo;gg&amp;rdquo; is also a common phrase in gaming subculture, meaning &amp;ldquo;good game&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now going with something like &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/gg-channel-island-domain-name-registration-for-guernsey&#34;&gt;.GG&lt;/a&gt; for &amp;ldquo;good game&amp;rdquo; is a viable option, but I&amp;rsquo;d be a little concerned about longevity. Let&amp;rsquo;s say you keep this domain for 20 years—are you going to be ok with &amp;ldquo;good game&amp;rdquo; when you&amp;rsquo;re 40? 50?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To me, a similar concern goes for extensions like &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-wtf&#34;&gt;.WTF&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-rocks&#34;&gt;.ROCKS&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-ninja&#34;&gt;.NINJA&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-cool&#34;&gt;.COOL&lt;/a&gt;. If you&amp;rsquo;re a 40-year-old who genuinely, unquestionably rocks, then go for it, but if you&amp;rsquo;re 17 going with a .NINJA domain, will you be cool with it when you&amp;rsquo;re 37?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Career specific&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new gTLDs also allow for people to self-identify with their careers. So if you&amp;rsquo;re a photographer, you could use a &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-photography&#34;&gt;.photography&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-photos&#34;&gt;.photos&lt;/a&gt; extension. Or if you&amp;rsquo;re an engineer, you could go with a &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-engineer&#34;&gt;.engineer&lt;/a&gt; domain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When going for longer, more specific domains, there are two things you should consider. First, how confident are you that you&amp;rsquo;ll stay in that career forever? Are you sure you&amp;rsquo;re not going to quit your job and become a brewmaster (&lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-beer&#34;&gt;.BEER&lt;/a&gt; in the next five years? And second, be mindful of length. There&amp;rsquo;s an American football player named Michael Hoomanawanui, and if he retires and becomes a photographer, hoomanawanui.photography probably isn&amp;rsquo;t his best option for a domain name (24 characters is incredibly long).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Domain hacks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Domain hacks won&amp;rsquo;t work for everyone, but if you want to get clever, you could do a lot worse than finding the ccTLD that fits into your name. Some common name-enders are &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/es-spanish-domain-name-registration-for-spain&#34;&gt;.ES&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/am-armenian-domain-name-registration-for-armenia&#34;&gt;.AM&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/at-austrian-domain-name-registration-for-austria&#34;&gt;.AT&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/be-belgian-domain-name-registration-for-belgium&#34;&gt;.BE&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/ch-swiss-domain-name-registration-for-switzerland&#34;&gt;.CH&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/de-german-domain-name-registration-for-germany&#34;&gt;.DE&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/my-malaysian-domain-name-registration-for-malaysia&#34;&gt;.MY&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/sh-domain-name-registration-for-saint-helena&#34;&gt;.SH&lt;/a&gt;. Unfortunately, .LL (ha.ll) isn&amp;rsquo;t available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, just about anything you choose will be fine as long as you stick with it (isn&amp;rsquo;t that always the lesson?). The goal of a personal domain is for people to be able to find you, and if you stay in the same place long enough, they likely will. Just know that no matter what domain extension you go with, it&amp;rsquo;ll be better than sending people to Facebook or LinkedIn to discover who you are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-4&#34;&gt;Platforms for creating a personal website&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before you get too bogged down with actually creating your personal site, be sure to take a quick inventory of your current and potential needs. Are you just looking for an anchor for your various social handles and blog articles? Are you looking for a portfolio site to help you get a job? Are you trying to sell something? Once you know what your needs are, your search will be infinitely less complicated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below is a sample (not an exhaustive list) of platforms in our Marketplace that will help you get started with a custom domain:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;For a quick personal landing page: about.me&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike the big site builders that do it all, &lt;a href=&#34;https://about.me&#34;&gt;about.me&lt;/a&gt; acts more like your business card, online. In short, about.me allows you to put up a representative picture of yourself, basic CV-type information, and links to all your works on the web. It&amp;rsquo;s simple to use, easy to maintain, and is a great way to anchor your internet self.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;If you express yourself through blog posts: Ghost&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ghost.org&#34;&gt;Ghost&lt;/a&gt; is a super clean blog platform that makes it easy to get your words published. What&amp;rsquo;s neat about Ghost though is that it&amp;rsquo;s growing at a steady clip, yet isn&amp;rsquo;t part of a wider social network like Tumblr (or Medium, which is a double ouch in that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t let you use custom domains).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;For making online stores: Big Cartel&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re a &amp;ldquo;maker, designer, musician, or other artist&amp;rdquo; looking for a platforms to sell stuff, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bigcartel.com&#34;&gt;Big Cartel&lt;/a&gt; has all the tools you need.  And it gives you a nice social component as well, as Big Cartel has been cultivating and promoting great indie stores for years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;If you want to do it all: Squarespace&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter what you want to do on the web, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.squarespace.com&#34;&gt;Squarespace&lt;/a&gt; can help you create it. It does blogs, portfolios, stores, simple pages—heck, it&amp;rsquo;ll even host your podcast. But most impressive is the array of themes Squarespace provides, giving you the flexibility to make your site look any way you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-5&#34;&gt;Your personal brand needs a custom email address&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After you&amp;rsquo;ve created your website, don&amp;rsquo;t forget to create the custom email address to go along with it (especially if your personal brand is &amp;ldquo;going pro&amp;rdquo;). You&amp;rsquo;ll look a far more savvy with an @YOURNAME.com address than the gmail.com or yahoo.com alternative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you&amp;rsquo;re ready to make this happen, be sure to read our guide on &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/06/the-guide-to-getting-your-own-custom-email-address.html&#34;&gt;how to get your own custom email address&lt;/a&gt; (there&amp;rsquo;s even a free option!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-6&#34;&gt;Thoughts on reserving the digital future of your child&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we&amp;rsquo;ve really gone off the deep end. Here&amp;rsquo;s a bit from Alexander Taub in Forbes’ &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forbes.com/sites/alextaub/2012/10/25/the-mad-rush-to-reserve-your-childs-digital-future&#34;&gt;The Mad Rush To Reserve Your Child’s Digital Future&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been noticing a trend over the past few months. I have a lot of friends who are having their first child. Many of these friends, especially the ones who work in the technology space, are reserving and managing the handles, email addresses, and websites of their newborns. They believe that when their child comes of age, the good handles, email addresses, websites, and digital accounts will be much harder to come by. By 2025, Jonathan.Smith@gmail.com or @jonsmith equivalents will definitely not be available. You may have to settle for @jonsmith13 or Jsmith13@gmail.com.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our thought? Skip the gmail. Skip all the social media platforms that might not exist in a decade. Instead, register a solid domain name for your child—domain names, unlike social media, will be there when your child wants it, and custom email addresses are always cooler than their closed-platform alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2015 12:45:53 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/08/get-your-personal-brand-in-tip-top-shape.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/08/get-your-personal-brand-in-tip-top-shape.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>How to keep your passwords and logins safe</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Security is one of those things that no one wants to think about, but we all need to be paying attention to. Moving around today&amp;rsquo;s internet requires more than the short password you&amp;rsquo;ve been using since 1998, and no, adding a capital letter at the beginning probably isn&amp;rsquo;t enough. To really be safe, you need strong passwords and extra layers of authentication when logging in to sites—and for most people, you&amp;rsquo;ll need apps to help you keep track of it all. Here&amp;rsquo;s our primer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-1&#34;&gt;The best ways to manage your passwords&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-2&#34;&gt;Use 2FA for an extra layer of protection&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-1&#34;&gt;The best ways to keep your passwords safe&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve worked hard over the past half-decade making domain registration as easy as possible, but one pain point we often encounter is password memorization. The vast majority of our customers simply don&amp;rsquo;t need to interact with us very often, and what seems like a strong, easily remembered password could be completely alien when domain renewals come around a year later. But there are solutions for this very problem—all you need is a solid password manager.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s an intro to password managers from &lt;a href=&#34;The paranoid guide to digital security&#34;&gt;Consumer Reports&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concept is straightforward: You sign up for a service that generates and stores a unique, strong password for each of the websites where you need log-in credentials. You can do that yourself if you have a savant-like memory for numbers, but in all likelihood you don’t. Then, you just need to remember one, excellent password in order to access the service. Yes, you may ask, but what if the password manager gets hacked? Not to worry, says Chris Soghoian. “Password managers encrypt their data, so these services are safe. And, ultimately, in 2015 it’s not a good idea to use the same password for more than one website. That effectively means that you have to outsource the task.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;1Password&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/media/2015-02-11-one-password.png&#34; alt=&#34;1Password&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the name suggests, &lt;a href=&#34;https://agilebits.com/onepassword&#34;&gt;1Password&lt;/a&gt; is a tool that acts as a vault for all your passwords, secured by a single password of your creation. Basically, using a browser extension (available for Safari, Firefox, Chrome, and Opera), app, or smartphone app, you can open your vault with your master password and have instant access to all the passwords you&amp;rsquo;ve created, on any device you happen to be using.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a little excerpt from an extremely in-depth piece by the Sweet Setup, titled &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://thesweetsetup.com/apps/best-password-manager-and-why-you-need-one/&#34;&gt;The best password manager (and why you need one) &amp;ndash; 1Password&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, 1Password is the best app for managing your passwords because it does the best job of taking hold of our slippery digital identity, all the myriad digital bits of ourselves we use to prove who we are, and helps ease the friction of our travels through the digital world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s another glowing review from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.macstories.net/reviews/1password-4-for-mac-review/&#34;&gt;MacStories&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every time a new version of 1Password comes out, I feel like repeating myself: if you’re serious about your secure data and web logins, you need 1Password. While it’s a great thing that Apple will be providing native options for increased password security and form-filling with iCloud Keychain, my recommendation still goes to 1Password if you’re looking for a dedicated app with more and better options aimed at managing your passwords, login details, credit card information, software licenses, and more. iCloud Keychain is meant for Safari, whereas 1Password is system-wide, powered by great customizable menus with keyboard shortcuts, and goes beyond web logins to let you encrypt and protect just about anything. I can’t work without 1Password.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;LastPass&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/media/2015-02-11-lastpass.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;LastPass&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another good password manager is &lt;a href=&#34;https://lastpass.com&#34;&gt;LastPass&lt;/a&gt;, which works basically the same way 1Password does, but with a few less bells and whistles (although LastPass has been making huge strides), and a cheaper price (there&amp;rsquo;s a free option!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a bit from PC Mag&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pcmag.com/article2/0,2817,2426798,00.asp&#34;&gt;LastPass 3.0 review&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Storing all of your passwords in a single, secure password manager means you can use a different, strong password for every site, without worrying that you&amp;rsquo;ll forget. It also means that a successful attack on your password stash could give a hacker access to every one of your secure sites. If that thought worries you, the free LastPass 3.0 is just what you need. Your data is stored online in encrypted form that even the company can&amp;rsquo;t read, and it&amp;rsquo;s encrypted going to and from your PCs. You can protect your LastPass data with more different kinds of two-factor authentication than any other password manager I&amp;rsquo;ve encountered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Dashlane&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/media/2015-02-11-dashlane.png&#34; alt=&#34;Dashlane&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dashlane.com&#34;&gt;Dashlane&lt;/a&gt; is similar in many ways to the other password managers on the market (if you want details, David Pogue wrote a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2013/06/06/technology/personaltech/too-many-passwords-and-no-way-to-remember-them-until-now.html&#34;&gt;very positive review&lt;/a&gt; in the New York Times, as did &lt;a href=&#34;http://thenextweb.com/apps/2014/12/09/dashlanes-automatic-password-changer-makes-precious-accounts-less-hackable/&#34;&gt;The Next Web&lt;/a&gt; in late 2014), but a new feature dropped in December that makes it extremely enticing. Here&amp;rsquo;s the description from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theverge.com/2014/12/9/7357251/dashlane-can-now-change-all-your-passwords-with-a-single-click-and&#34;&gt;the Verge&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dashlane, the subscription-based password management service, is introducing a feature today that ought to become standard in every product like it: the ability to change all your passwords with a single click, including accounts with two-factor authentication enabled. The feature will work with about 75 major websites at launch, including Amazon, Apple, Facebook, Google, LinkedIn, PayPal, Pinterest, and Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Password Changer, as the feature is called, is made possible by Dashlane’s acquisition of PassOmatic, a New York startup that developed the core technology. For now, it works on desktop versions of Dashlane for PC and Mac, though the company is working on a mobile version. Dashlane now includes a big green &amp;ldquo;change all passwords&amp;rdquo; button; click it, and it will replace your existing passwords with ones that are unique and randomly generated. If you have two-factor authentication enabled, a pop-up will ask you for a code or for the answer to a security question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Safari Passwords&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to avoid the master password thing and just want a simple password storage system, the Safari Password Manager is a pretty nice tool. Basically, when you&amp;rsquo;re setting up an account online, Safari can auto-generate and save a secure password that will sync via iCloud Keychain for you to use on any device. It&amp;rsquo;s incredibly easy, but for some, it might be too easy. Here&amp;rsquo;s a specific pain point, from the pro-1Password &lt;a href=&#34;http://thesweetsetup.com/apps/best-password-manager-and-why-you-need-one/&#34;&gt;Sweet Setup&lt;/a&gt; article above:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Different people also have different levels of comfort with iCloud Keychain. I, for one, don’t actually love the frictionless experience. I want to be intentional about how I use my passwords and my credit card information, and I like how 1Password makes me conscious of when I’m using those things. I also like how I have more control over access to my information on my devices. I can require a login to 1Password after not using it for even a few minutes. I also like that if my daughter is using my iPad, she can’t easily hop over to Zappos and buy herself a new pair of shoes with my credit card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-2&#34;&gt;Use 2FA for an extra layer of protection&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In principle, making your online self more secure seems like a no-brainer. Of course you don&amp;rsquo;t want to get hacked. Of course you don&amp;rsquo;t want your identity to be stolen. But at what length are you willing to go to ensure your safety?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One easy (and totally free) step we recommend you take for every platform that supports it is two-factor authentication (2FA). Stripping technical jargon, 2FA makes it so that in order to login to your account, you have to type in a code that&amp;rsquo;s only accessible on your phone. So if Hacker X tries to access your account, they&amp;rsquo;ll need the code sitting on your phone to get through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s something we think is really important, so here&amp;rsquo;s a quick look at how to set it up, and what using it looks like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The setup&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Login to your account, then select &amp;ldquo;Login &amp;amp; Security&amp;rdquo; under the &amp;ldquo;Account&amp;rdquo; dropdown menu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Under &amp;ldquo;Two-step verification&amp;rdquo; type in your phone number and country code, then download the Authy app for iOS or Android (an SMS text option is available if you&amp;rsquo;re on an unsupported platform).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/media/2014-05-01-2fa-setup.png&#34; alt=&#34;2FA setup&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Using 2FA&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you&amp;rsquo;re all setup, your login will look like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/media/2014-05-01-authy-login.png&#34; alt=&#34;Authy login&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just open up your Authy app (or SMS text) and type in the code provided—and that&amp;rsquo;s it. You&amp;rsquo;ve quickly—and painlessly—added a second level of security to your iwantmyname account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/media/2014-05-01-2fa.png&#34; alt=&#34;Authy&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;But will this get annoying?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The million dollar question. Yes, adding 2FA will make logging into your iwantmyname account a touch more cumbersome, but we&amp;rsquo;re not a Bitcoin platform you&amp;rsquo;re logging into every day. If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, you probably only mess with your account once a month—or less. And at five seconds per login (the Authy codes expires every 20 seconds, so even if you&amp;rsquo;re slow, it can only take that long), you&amp;rsquo;re only looking at losing a few seconds of your life a month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;rsquo;s a really small price to pay for peace of mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Find more information&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to find more information about Authy, here are a few good places to start:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find answers to common questions, or ask your own, on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.authy.com/faq&#34;&gt;Authy FAQ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tweet Authy &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Authy&#34;&gt;@authy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authy has 11 informational videos on &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/user13020702/videos&#34;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you’re interested in integrating Authy to your platform, &lt;a href=&#34;http://code.tutsplus.com/tutorials/two-factor-auth-using-authy--net-33402&#34;&gt;here’s an introduction on Tuts+&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We’re big fans of DigitalOcean, and they have a great article titled, “&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.digitalocean.com/community/articles/how-to-install-authy-and-configure-two-factor-authentication-for-ssh&#34;&gt;How To Install Authy And Configure Two-Factor Authentication For SSH&lt;/a&gt;”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2015 10:21:09 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/07/how-to-keep-your-passwords-and-logins-safe.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/07/how-to-keep-your-passwords-and-logins-safe.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>.COM? .IO? .PIZZA? How to pick the right domain extension (TLD)</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In ye olde days (early 2013), most of the hard thinking that went into choosing a domain name went to the part before the dot. But now, with hundreds of &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/new-gtld-domain-extensions&#34;&gt;new gTLDs&lt;/a&gt; available to the public, the actual name of your site might be the easy part.  How do you choose between all the options? Do you go with .COM? .CO? Your local ccTLD? A descriptive word that aligns with your brand? Maybe .PIZZA (pizza goes with everything!)?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before you spontaneously combust, let&amp;rsquo;s go through your options and add some notes from the smart people writing about the subject on the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-1&#34;&gt;.COM, the big Kahuna&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-2&#34;&gt;Beware spam indicators&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-3&#34;&gt;Local ccTLDs and gTLDs can be good for business&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-4&#34;&gt;.IO and the TLDs for tech&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-5&#34;&gt;Are some TLDs better for reaching an international audience?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-6&#34;&gt;Is it ok to use a new gTLD?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-7&#34;&gt;Does your TLD really matter?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-1&#34;&gt;.COM, the big Kahuna&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/media/2015-07-23-big-kahuna.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Big Kahuna Burger&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not a mind reader, but my guess is that you&amp;rsquo;re here to have someone like me tell you it&amp;rsquo;s ok to get something other than a .COM. So, sure, you certainly can run a successful business using any TLD. But for many people, .COM &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; the internet, especially if you live in the US. And it goes beyond simple. familiarity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take John Smith, a hypothetical 49-year-old insurance adjuster in Columbus, Ohio (in the US). On a given day, he browses through his typical sites: cnn.com, espn.com, facebook.com, and his work website, then he checks his email through Apple Mail which was set up for him at the Apple Store when he got his computer. The only thing he&amp;rsquo;ll come across that doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem &lt;em&gt;safe&lt;/em&gt; is the spam that sometimes makes it to his inbox. And all that spam usually has one thing in common—garbledygook. The text is sometimes in a foreign language, or at best, a broken attempt at his primary language. The email address probably has hyphens and numbers. And the links (if there is a link) often have misspellings and unfamiliar TLDs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now imagine marketing your brand to John Smith. You could have a clean site with a clear business plan, but your non-.COM instantly registers as something out of the ordinary. Something potentially unsafe. And because John has been trained at his office for the last two decades to avoid anything remotely unfamiliar on the web (people are deathly afraid of getting hacked), he might not click.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Always remember that while more and more people are working tech jobs and building websites every day, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cheatsheet.com/business/millennials-are-more-scared-of-the-internet-than-their-grandparents.html/?a=viewall&#34;&gt;a big portion of the public still sees the internet as a dangerous place&lt;/a&gt; too often run by teenage wunderkinds. And with every new story that breaks about privacy concerns and data theft, that fear of the unknown grows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that said, people do gradually adapt to change. 15 years ago, buying something online with a credit card seemed like science fiction, and now we all have so many monthly subscriptions we can&amp;rsquo;t even keep up. What seems weird and dangerous today could be the societal norm by the end of the year, and everyone knows it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-2&#34;&gt;Beware spam indicators&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/media/2015-07-23-scary-rails.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;scary&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As stated about, if your website looks like it could be spam, that&amp;rsquo;s not a good thing. Here&amp;rsquo;s what &lt;a href=&#34;https://moz.com/learn/seo/domain&#34;&gt;Moz&lt;/a&gt;, the popular SEO site, says:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For best ranking results, avoid uncommon top-level domains (TLDs). Like hyphens, TLDs such as .info, .cc, .ws, and .name are spam indicators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to that short list, the new gTLDs have created so many new outlets for spammers to exploit (although it looks like the new gTLDs are still &lt;a href=&#34;http://domainincite.com/17447-phishers-prefer-free-cctlds-to-new-gtlds&#34;&gt;less commonly used than discount/free ccTLDs&lt;/a&gt;). My recommendation would be to avoid unnecessarily generic TLDs, like .COMPANY, .COUNTRY, and .WEBSITE. This isn&amp;rsquo;t a set rule though—as the .COM namespace gets more crowded, people will have to gravitate &lt;em&gt;somewhere&lt;/em&gt;. My guess is that they&amp;rsquo;ll gravitate towards the more specific options, but who knows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before you register a domain, I&amp;rsquo;d recommend doing a little search to see if the TLD you&amp;rsquo;re looking at is appearing on email block lists (like &lt;a href=&#34;http://vamsoft.com/forum/topic/597/existing-list-of-garbage-new-tlds&#34;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt; I found while searching for &amp;ldquo;which tlds are spam indicators&amp;rdquo;). If you start noticing trends, that could be a bad sign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-3&#34;&gt;Local ccTLDs and gTLDs can be good for business&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/media/2015-07-23-restaurant.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;restaurant&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By design, the internet is a global marketplace. No matter where your website is being hosted, anyone in the world can check out what you&amp;rsquo;re offering. But in many instances, people and businesses don&amp;rsquo;t need a global reach. Restaurants, regional banks, local politicians—these people and places are focused locally, and can often benefit from local TLDs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://moz.com/learn/seo/cctlds&#34;&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what Moz has to say:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Important in international SEO, ccTLDs are the single strongest way to show search engines and users where the site originates. This means that, all things being equal, example.fr will likely rank better in a French user&amp;rsquo;s SERP than example.us or example.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that Google Webmaster Tools will not let you geotarget a ccTLD because it is, by definition, already geotargeted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Worrying about SEO might be a few steps beyond where your mind is, but thinking about where you&amp;rsquo;ll appear in search results early is the best way to make sure you&amp;rsquo;ll rank well later on. Let&amp;rsquo;s put it in human terms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Say you have a restaurant named MUCH MEAT (all caps for emphasis) in Canada, but somewhere in the US there&amp;rsquo;s a slightly more popular restaurant with a very similar name using the .COM. Because of their popularity, their domain name would likely show up before yours in search results&amp;hellip;&lt;em&gt;unless&lt;/em&gt; you&amp;rsquo;re using the .CA ccTLD, which would give you a slight advantage when people are searching for you in Canada (&lt;a href=&#34;https://support.google.com/webmasters/answer/62399&#34;&gt;although you can target generic TLDs like .COM to specific places, too&lt;/a&gt;&amp;hellip;it&amp;rsquo;s just an extra step). Basically, if you&amp;rsquo;re not an international company, your local ccTLD is a wonderful option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(&amp;hellip;Unless you live in the US. If you travel to just about any country on the planet, you&amp;rsquo;ll see tons of signs with ccTLDs. In Wellington, signs with .NZ and .CO.NZ might outnumber .COMs—but in the US, people don&amp;rsquo;t use .US at all. It&amp;rsquo;s just one of those quirks.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other advantage to using your local ccTLD is that the namespace is &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; less crowded than .COM. &lt;a href=&#34;http://w3techs.com/technologies/overview/top_level_domain/all&#34;&gt;This chart&lt;/a&gt; shows 50.8% of all websites use .COM, while most other TLDs account for less than 0.1%. That&amp;rsquo;s a big popularity gap, which likely means prime names are still up for grabs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if the name you want &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; taken in your local ccTLD namespace, there are a bunch of new TLDs coming out for specific cities. .BERLIN, .PARIS, .LONDON, .NYC—all are currently available, and their relative newness likely means you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to find the domain you&amp;rsquo;re looking for. Plus, if you&amp;rsquo;re only targeting people from the city you&amp;rsquo;re in, you&amp;rsquo;re looking at a nice potential SEO bump for being hyperlocal (although Google is currently treating city extensions as standard gTLDs).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;When going local goes wrong&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few instances where trying to go local doesn&amp;rsquo;t actually mean the internet thinks you&amp;rsquo;re local. Here are a few hypotheticals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The common initials for the state of Delaware are DE, but .DE is the ccTLD for Germany. Your customers might think it&amp;rsquo;s cool, but Google&amp;rsquo;s never going to geotarget you correctly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Like Delaware, Sussex in England uses SX as their abbreviation, but .SX is the ccTLD for Sint Maarten.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best rule to follow is to know what your TLD stands for before you register it (if it&amp;rsquo;s a ccTLD that Google considers generic, you&amp;rsquo;re fine).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-4&#34;&gt;.IO and the TLDs for tech&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/media/2015-07-23-tech.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;tech&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all started with &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/04/everything-you-need-to-know-about-domain-hacks.html&#34;&gt;domain hacks&lt;/a&gt;. As .COM got more and more crowded, the rapidly growing startup scene had to go somewhere, but the where wasn&amp;rsquo;t so obvious—until the ever-so-creative founders started blending their company names and their domain names together. So started a trend where every new startup ended with &amp;ldquo;ly&amp;rdquo; while using the .LY ccTLD (here&amp;rsquo;s a great Pinterest board, aptly named &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;Names That End in -ly&#34;&gt;Names That End in -ly&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somewhere along the way though, startups started moving to .IO en masse (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.russellbeattie.com/blog/artisanal-websites-the-rise-of-io-domains-for-well-crafted-web-services&#34;&gt;here&amp;rsquo;s a great list of .IO domains in the wild&lt;/a&gt;, and another list of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://hack.ly/articles/the-most-popular-dot-io-domains-2015/&#34;&gt;1457 most popular .IO domains in existence&lt;/a&gt;). It had a lot going for it—I/O commonly stands for Input/Output, Io is a pretty awesome moon and is big in Greek mythology, and it makes for a pretty nice domain hack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also going for .IO was the fact that it&amp;rsquo;s on the list of ccTLDs Google treats as gTLDs because they&amp;rsquo;re so commonly used (g stands for generic). &lt;a href=&#34;https://support.google.com/webmasters/answer/1347922?hl=en&#34;&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the list:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;.ad, .as, .bz, .cc, .cd, .co, .dj, .fm, .io, .la, .me, .ms, .nu, .sc, .sr, .su, .tv, .tk, .ws, .eu, .asia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But with all the new gTLDs available today, startups and tech sites have more options than ever. .SOFTWARE, .TECHNOLOGY, .DIGITAL, .CODES, .CONSULTING, .BUILD—the list goes on and on and on. And my guess is that, like the rise of .LY and .IO, it&amp;rsquo;s only going to take a few big startups to start using the new gTLDs to get the whole train moving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-5&#34;&gt;Are some TLDs better for reaching an international audience?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re in the process of starting a new website and want to go with a shorter domain extension than any of the new gTLDs (or .COM), there are a few nice options. As stated above, Google treats .ad, .as, .bz, .cc, .cd, .co, .dj, .fm, .io, .la, .me, .ms, .nu, .sc, .sr, .su, .tv, .tk, .ws, and .eu as generic, meaning you can &lt;a href=&#34;https://support.google.com/webmasters/answer/1347922?hl=en&#34;&gt;set a geographic target through Google Webmaster Tools&lt;/a&gt;, e.g. use a .co domain and be listed in search results in the United States, Canada or France although it is actually Colombia’s top-level domain. The same is true if you don’t want to target a specific country, i.e. have a .me domain for your personal online profile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But which ones of these so-called gccTLDs (generic country code top-level domains) are the most popular and more likely to be recognized by visitors?Let’s take a look at Verisign’s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.verisigninc.com/assets/domain-name-report-march2015.pdf&#34;&gt;latest domain industry brief&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/media/2015-04-21-gcctld-chart.png&#34; alt=&#34;verisign graph&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some ccTLDs, including .tk, .co, .me and .tv are frequently used by registrants and treated by search engines as gTLDs. This chart ranks the zone size of both gTLDs and ccTLDs marketed as gTLDs, as of Dec. 31, 2014, with that classification taken into account. The top 10 largest gTLDs and ccTLDs marketed as gTLDs by zone size were .com, .tk, .net, .org, .info, .biz, .co, .mobi, .me and .tv, as of Dec. 31, 2014, which account for 180.6 million domain name registrations, or 62.8 percent of the total global domain name registrations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we have &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/tk-tokelauan-domain-name-registration-for-tokelau&#34;&gt;.TK&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/co-colombian-domain-name-registration-for-colombia&#34;&gt;.CO&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/me-montenegrean-domain-name-registration-for-montenegro&#34;&gt;.ME&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/tv-tuvaluan-domain-name-registration-for-tuvalu&#34;&gt;.TV&lt;/a&gt; as the most popular gccTLDs in that list. Not surprising, except .TK, which offers free domains—but with certain usage restrictions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other popular ones you may have seen are &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/io-domain-name-registration-for-british-indian-ocean-territory&#34;&gt;.IO&lt;/a&gt; for tech sites (which is &lt;a href=&#34;http://hack.ly/articles/the-most-popular-dot-io-domains-2015/&#34;&gt;still on the rise&lt;/a&gt;), &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/fm-domain-name-registration-for-federated-states-of-micronesia&#34;&gt;.FM&lt;/a&gt; for music websites, &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/cc-domain-name-registration-for-cocos-keeling-islands&#34;&gt;.CC&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/ws-samoan-domain-name-registration-for-western-samoa&#34;&gt;.WS&lt;/a&gt; for general use, as well as &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/nu-domain-name-registration-for-niue&#34;&gt;.NU&lt;/a&gt; (popular in Scandinavian countries).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lesser known gccTLDs, but often registered for &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2013/10/what-is-a-domain-hack-and-how-can-i-make-one.html&#34;&gt;domain hacks&lt;/a&gt; because they don’t require any special documentation or local address in the country, are the &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/la-lao-domain-name-registration-for-laos&#34;&gt;.LA&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/ms-domain-name-registration-for-montserrat&#34;&gt;.MS&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/ms-domain-name-registration-for-montserrat&#34;&gt;.SC&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/as-samoan-domain-name-registration-for-american-samoa&#34;&gt;.AS&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/bz-belizean-domain-name-registration-for-belize&#34;&gt;.BZ&lt;/a&gt; suffixes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That leaves us with the remaining geo-targetable domain extensions from Google’s list: .AD, .CD, .DJ, .SR, and .SU. Unfortunately, we don&amp;rsquo;t carry these domains because they&amp;rsquo;re not easy to purchase and maintain, so you&amp;rsquo;d have to choose another registrar (our friends at &lt;a href=&#34;https://domainr.com&#34;&gt;Domainr&lt;/a&gt; may be able to help with that.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-6&#34;&gt;Is it ok to use a new gTLD?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/media/2015-07-23-pizza-menu.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;pizza menu&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the biggest question of the day. As I stated at the beginning of this post, for many people, .COM &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; the internet, and that&amp;rsquo;s a hard nut to crack. So when the new gTLDs launched, many thought the assumed SEO bump would kickstart the system. But not so fast. Here&amp;rsquo;s a short post from &lt;a href=&#34;https://plus.google.com/+MattCutts/posts/4VaWg4TMM5F&#34;&gt;Matt Cutts:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read a post by someone offering new top-level domain (TLDs). They made this claim: &amp;ldquo;Will a new TLD web address automatically be favoured by Google over a .com equivalent? Quite simply, yes it will.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sorry, but that&amp;rsquo;s just not true, and as an engineer in the search quality team at Google, I feel the need to debunk this misconception. Google has a lot of experience in returning relevant web pages, regardless of the top-level domain (TLD). Google will attempt to rank new TLDs appropriately, but I don&amp;rsquo;t expect a new TLD to get any kind of initial preference over .com, and I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t bet on that happening in the long-term either. If you want to register an entirely new TLD for other reasons, that&amp;rsquo;s your choice, but you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t register a TLD in the mistaken belief that you&amp;rsquo;ll get some sort of boost in search engine rankings.﻿&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(And if that&amp;rsquo;s not enough, &lt;a href=&#34;http://googlewebmastercentral.blogspot.fr/2015/07/googles-handling-of-new-top-level.html&#34;&gt;here&amp;rsquo;s another, more recent, Google comment on the subject.&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So aside from being potentially confusing and not providing any sort of built-in SEO advantage, the reason I (and others) like the new gTLDs so much is because they &lt;em&gt;just make sense&lt;/em&gt;. Here&amp;rsquo;s a good bit by &lt;a href=&#34;http://thenextweb.com/entrepreneur/2015/06/14/how-to-name-your-startup/&#34;&gt;Karn Jajoo for The Next Web&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new TLD is often just a natural fit: take the example of ‘Lily’, the world’s first self-flying camera drone. ‘Lily’ could refer to the flowering plant, a common first name, or a small town, and its .com is registered by Lily Transportation Corp. Therefore, the Menlo Park robotics startup behind this drone used a simple, elegant domain to disambiguate its product – lily.camera.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ever heard of the case of Nissan computer vs. Nissan motors? Uzi Nissan, a reseller of computer hardware and peripherals, registered Nissan.com on June 4, 1994.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Five years later, the Nissan Motor Corporation (which was called Datsun in the late 1970s) filed a $10 million lawsuit against Nissan Computer claiming cyber-squatting, trademark infringement and trademark dilution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps if new TLDs had existed back then, Nissan.computer and Nissan.auto would have solved this contention without the lengthy legal dispute that has allegedly already cost Mr. Uzi $2.2 million in legal fees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to providing endless new namespaces for people to register short, memorable domain names, the new gTLDs act as a natural category structure for the web. In a perfect world where people like myself didn&amp;rsquo;t register .PIZZA domains for everything, you could theoretically know what the site you&amp;rsquo;re about to click on is all about, just from its TLD. And that&amp;rsquo;s cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-7&#34;&gt;Does your TLD really matter?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/media/2015-07-23-telescope.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;discovery&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From Pando Daily, in an article titled &lt;a href=&#34;http://pando.com/2014/10/09/whats-in-a-name-the-fading-tyranny-of-dot-com/&#34;&gt;“What’s In A Name? The fading tyranny of dot com”&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For someone like Michael Heyward, who co-founded anonymous social networking app Whisper in 2012, as a mobile first company, he says, there was not an ounce of trepidation at not having the Whisper.com domain name. (Whisper.com itself is a junk address, filled with spam links.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heyward says that 99 percent of Whisper’s exposure comes from its app. The company has a Whisper.sh landing page, to showcase popular posts from the app and publish legal and company information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2014, Americans spend more time in apps than they do using the Internet on desktop. With social media sites becoming a greater engine for content discovery, new sites such as Quartz are popping up that don’t really even have an official homepage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about that. For the foreseeable future, we&amp;rsquo;ll all need domain names to run our platforms and blogs, but discovery is changing &lt;em&gt;fast&lt;/em&gt;. Really fast. On a given day, almost all the content I personally read online comes from links on content aggregators like Techmeme and Hacker News, or social platforms like Facebook and Twitter. And because I trust the sources I&amp;rsquo;m finding sites and articles with, the domain itself doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter. It could be &amp;ldquo;ten words long dot anything&amp;rdquo; and I likely wouldn&amp;rsquo;t know the difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Putting on my future hat, my advice would be to find the TLD that &lt;em&gt;you&amp;rsquo;re&lt;/em&gt; most comfortable with and go with it. .COM, .IO, .LIMO—no matter what it is, if you commit to it, you&amp;rsquo;ll probably be fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photo credits:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(header): &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/stijlfoto/18974847222/in/photolist-uUK41j-6HLQcm-bvSMX6-6mYJDg-aAja77-4Qze8a-pS676-4rdKd2-3qRKWF-8M8NCJ-az8Xvt-cVGU-4hnENR-2Kx3Sk-JKL6s-2APAPe-5f3dQQ-5WmyyA-raDzoM-JKFcw-nBGwTX-5cJfyN-4Uy7Vn-5Q5F66-6MR8Lq-adazQA-9nNSP5-6mYJAt-oTt9c8-4qbcmN-mig52v-sWYA85-dcTeB-vozpP-rtnuB4-GbY6Y-dutmdM-4QDq8U-5Sqz9E-5Ukkoh-rg1UgP-dExGt-8BqeA2-sgKZs-5TZyJM-84UZ22-6tHL2w-6KkJLY-6mdgwq-6mdgCm&#34;&gt;Jan Willem van Wessel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Big Kahuna mural): &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/wallyg/8779127308/in/photolist-enMjFW-kNjgs-encFka-5o77AJ-5o2SbD-pUgsbW-pUun9K-6dCCeT-dXfYeF-6imprQ-9iVMh3-o1mSA-njhUi-8hqVus-8hnEoB-8hnCQH-8hqTAS-3K6VGH-8cJd5d-njhP5-bs9hsM-4d28TU-3PthMM-9iSDLg-68nBPx-jjVqJ-5vGTTn-4F63hu-9iVLXC-9iSE3p-9iVLEu-3PxvuG-re9K2A-6rrofP-3EM2Hj-8Dkmmz-6Tn28u-9CqKLb-9YN2A1-6JijYX-4F64bh-ceAgaS-bXdTZB-ceAfZj-bXdTpX-ceAgKo-bXdSTg-ceAfyq-brS5Dk-fZCq8t&#34;&gt;Wally Gobetz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Questions? Comments?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/iwantmyname/posts/10155815306170471&#34;&gt;Say something on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/iwantmyname/status/625731469676163072&#34;&gt;Tweet us a reply&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/support&#34;&gt;Send us a message&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 11:33:26 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/06/how-to-pick-the-right-domain-extension.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/06/how-to-pick-the-right-domain-extension.html</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
