<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>iwantmyname Domain Blog</title>
		<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/</link>
		<atom:link href="https://iwantmyname.com/blog/feeds/posts/recent.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Are people moving into .APARTMENTS?</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apartments will never go out of style. They&amp;rsquo;re the cogs that keep low-density cities moving—an affordable option for those who don&amp;rsquo;t need the space a house provides. But what can you do with a &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-apartments&#34;&gt;.APARTMENTS&lt;/a&gt; domain? It&amp;rsquo;s not a job title, personal identifier, or generic business category. Apartments are simply a type of higher-density housing unit, making the TLD a specialized option to the extreme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;.APARTMENTS are for apartments&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though apartment complexes are all unique entities, apartment naming isn&amp;rsquo;t exactly an exercise in high creativity. In &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apartmentguide.com/blog/apartment-names/&#34;&gt;Apartment Guide&amp;rsquo;s analysis&lt;/a&gt; of the community names in their system, they found more than a thousand complexes using the word &amp;ldquo;Park&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Village.&amp;rdquo; And nearly as many use words like &amp;ldquo;Place,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Creek,&amp;rdquo; Ridge,&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Square.&amp;rdquo; That&amp;rsquo;s a lot of redundancy, and on a namespace like .COM, you&amp;rsquo;re looking at a lot of varied domains using words like &amp;ldquo;apartments,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;community,&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;apts&amp;rdquo; to separate themselves from unrelated companies using similar naming structures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With .APARTMENTS, builders can simply use &amp;ldquo;name.APARTMENTS,&amp;rdquo; leaving out the identifiers needed in crowded, generic namespaces. Some creativity may come into play if 200 different &amp;ldquo;Village Pointe&amp;rdquo; apartments try to go after the same domain name, but at least the naming competition will be kept within the industry—not the world at large.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Will that be enough?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, each of these new generic TLDs is a business. Some, like &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-club&#34;&gt;.CLUB&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-xyz&#34;&gt;.XYZ&lt;/a&gt; seem to have a bright future due to their mass appeal. But others, like .APARTMENTS, are really going to have to fight to capture their niche audience. The underlying registry, Donuts, has hundreds of TLDs in their portfolio though, so it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t surprise me at all to see a major ad push for extensions like &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-guru&#34;&gt;.GURU&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-photography&#34;&gt;.PHOTOGRAPHY&lt;/a&gt;, and the aforementioned .APARTMENTS in the future. And who knows, maybe your .APARTMENTS domain will get featured!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 11:49:17 UTC</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/06/are-people-moving-into-apartments.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/06/are-people-moving-into-apartments.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>.CHAT is perfect for podcasts, forums, and chat rooms</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the casual observer, chat rooms are likely a thing of the past. A relic of the early internet where people discussed big topics, sometimes took on bizarre identities, and quickly discovered how connected we could all be. But while term &amp;ldquo;chat room&amp;rdquo; has largely been removed from our vernacular, countless people are still chatting away online, making &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-chat&#34;&gt;.CHAT&lt;/a&gt; the perfect TLD for your next great forum, podcast, or chat room (they still exist!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;.CHAT for forums&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as TLDs go, forums don&amp;rsquo;t really have a go-to namespace. Some use .COM, as it&amp;rsquo;s the most popular TLD. Some use .ORG and .NET, as forums are, by nature, networks and organizations. But with the .CHAT TLD, forums have a unique namespace that is relatively free from naming competition, informally describes what&amp;rsquo;s going on, and is familiar to those of us who began their web lives in the 90&amp;rsquo;s. Sure, it&amp;rsquo;s not as direct as &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-forum&#34;&gt;.FORUM&lt;/a&gt;, but .CHAT clearly has a place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;.CHAT for podcasts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These days, podcasts come in all shapes and sizes. Some feature investigative stories, some feature very specific advice—but some are just people talking to each other. It&amp;rsquo;s clear that a formal conversation would probably use something a little less loose than .CHAT, but any show featuring casual conversations would work perfectly. Think morning.CHAT, work.CHAT, or chrisandtimo.CHAT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;.CHAT definitely still works for chat rooms&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Backtracking a bit, just because chat rooms are less popular today than they once were doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean they don&amp;rsquo;t exist. Surprisingly, using Google Keyword Planner, the term &amp;ldquo;chat room&amp;rdquo; still gets 246,000 searches a month, and if you do a simple search for &amp;ldquo;chat room&amp;rdquo; you&amp;rsquo;ll find a huge collection of chat rooms waiting to be discovered. So if you&amp;rsquo;re looking to start a chat room anytime soon, there&amp;rsquo;s clearly still a demand (or maybe there&amp;rsquo;s just a large legacy supply&amp;hellip; do your research)—and .CHAT is as perfect a TLD as you&amp;rsquo;ll ever find (maybe we&amp;rsquo;ll even chime in if you go on to create domain.CHAT).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2015 11:53:03 UTC</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/05/chat-is-perfect-for-podcast-forums-and-chat-rooms.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/05/chat-is-perfect-for-podcast-forums-and-chat-rooms.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>.STYLE on the web is subjective</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as TLDs go, style is an interesting word. It&amp;rsquo;s not a job description or a thing you do—instead, it&amp;rsquo;s more of a process. Style can be the way you make something, or a specific form that&amp;rsquo;s trying to be achieved. You can have good style, bad style, correct style, or maybe you just want your haircuts styled a certain way. But what can you do with a .STYLE domain name?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;.STYLE blogs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blogs, particularly online collections (think long Tumblr sites), are perhaps the best place for .STYLE domains to live. Unlike a business or brand, a style blog can be a collection of anything about a movement. Mid-century style could live on midcentury.STYLE. Your collection of Mannerist style architecture could easily find a home on mannerist.STYLE. Or if your love is typography, typographic.STYLE might be just what you&amp;rsquo;re after.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;.STYLE is for writers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the world of professional writing, style is what keeps the world consistent. But style reference books, like the AP Stylebook, Oxford Manual of Style, and the The Chicago Manual of Style, aren&amp;rsquo;t exactly the easiest things to get through (the AP Stylebook is nearly 400 pages)—so this is where the internet comes in. There are style sites online for every type of writing you could imagine, and with a .STYLE domain, they could all move to a namespace free of clutter (and grammar mistakes).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;.STYLE makes for a great domain hack&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/04/everything-you-need-to-know-about-domain-hacks.html&#34;&gt;domain hack&lt;/a&gt; thought starters using .STYLE:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hair.STYLE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;life.STYLE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;free.STYLE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pro.STYLE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;old.STYLE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photo credit: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/15216811@N06/5509031671/in/photolist-4chykp-8ZwLv8-fRURPy-9oPebF-azNvT8-9gZ5Nt-bDjQfK-6vMUSN-6vKWK9-6vPxGe-6vNuq2-6vMjPr-6vRBTh-dZctDF-gd18ym-gd1Cqr-gcZQBz-bDjkZg-5pXY4G-6vSfFz-bqpuNm-6vYRRV-bqpySb-bqpwds-4mABp-4JFyw-4JFQ9-4JSxX-jUTUJy-bDjoX8-5pTyhu-6vTDTw-owbsut-our1Hq-8QAb2-fuWrYf-fEWwtR-6R32uT-8qtoR3-fEVaj8-9h3dwf-nj34gy-6vYXBF-6w3QVG-6vHsip-9gZ5YF-2mHVF-2mJbv-fEVQNZ-fEVPTM&#34;&gt;N i c o l a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2015 13:35:14 UTC</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/05/style-on-the-web-is-subjective.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/05/style-on-the-web-is-subjective.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>.TENNIS just makes sense for the largely web-adverse tennis community</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among the &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/domain-name-registration-list-of-extensions&#34;&gt;hundreds of TLDs&lt;/a&gt; (the part after the dot, like COM in .COM) available now, sports TLDs are some of the hardest to find uses for. At this point, many of the world&amp;rsquo;s major sports leagues are enormous commercial entities, making .COM an ideal solution. Individual players are also unlikely to come over in droves, given the extreme specificity of an ending like .TENNIS. But &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-tennis&#34;&gt;.TENNIS&lt;/a&gt; in particular does have a couple important uses—providing open namespaces for local tennis associations/clubs and tournaments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;.TENNIS for local tennis associations/clubs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like many sports associations, organized tennis is a big tangle of domain naming practices. Long names, assorted TLDs, jumbled words—it&amp;rsquo;s a mess. For example, here are a few from around the world:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the Wellington Tennis Club uses wellingtontennisclub.org.nz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the Auckland Tennis Association uses tennisauckland.co.nz (notice the .co.nz instead of the .org.nz Wellington uses)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the Houston Tennis Association uses houstontennis.org&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the Ontario Tennis Association uses tennisontario.com&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of these assorted naming practices, imagine if they all used this—cityname.TENNIS? It&amp;rsquo;s nice and short, and aside from small cities with the same names as larger cities, the naming could be standardized around the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;.TENNIS for tournaments&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just going through the USTA (US Tennis Association) Tennis Link, it&amp;rsquo;s amazing how many local tournaments simply don&amp;rsquo;t have websites. The tournament information pages clearly have a place for a tournament website to go, but more often than not, these tournaments are run, organized, and managed without a web presence (hopefully it&amp;rsquo;s better in other countries). And that&amp;rsquo;s insane.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If anyone attached to a tennis tournament happens to read this, might I recommend creating a quick &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/services/website-builder/&#34;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/services/blog-hosting/&#34;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; (we have so many available for one-click installs) and using a domain name like tournamentname.TENNIS? The younger generations would greatly appreciate it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2015 10:50:18 UTC</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/05/tennis-just-makes-sense-for-the-largely-web-adverse-tennis-community.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/05/tennis-just-makes-sense-for-the-largely-web-adverse-tennis-community.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>The guide to getting the right domain name for your brand (and what to do if someone else owns it)</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ve started your own business, club, or blog, and you can&amp;rsquo;t wait to share it with the world. There&amp;rsquo;s still work to be done, but the primary focus is now on branding. You do some critical thinking about your product and your industry, come up with a list of potential brand names, and pick one that fits perfectly—it&amp;rsquo;s clever, descriptive, and extremely easy to remember. Now to register the domain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or not. It&amp;rsquo;s taken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trying to get &amp;ldquo;the perfect domain&amp;rdquo; can be really frustrating, or, at the very least, really expensive. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thedomains.com/2014/03/24/after-losing-over-25000-registrations-in-two-days-com-back-below-113-million-berlin-top-40k/&#34;&gt;Well over 100 million .COM domains are currently registered,&lt;/a&gt;, and the estimated total of registered domains topped a quarter of a &lt;em&gt;billion&lt;/em&gt; last year. More likely than not, &amp;ldquo;the good ones&amp;rdquo; are already taken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s a person to do? Well, there are a few options, which we&amp;rsquo;ll break down for you in this series on getting the right domain for your brand, even if the name you really want is already registered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-1&#34;&gt;I think the domain I want is taken. Help!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-2&#34;&gt;What is domain squatting/cybersquatting?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-3&#34;&gt;Someone has registered a domain with my trademark. What do I do?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-4&#34;&gt;How do I find out if the domain I want becomes available?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-5&#34;&gt;If I can&amp;rsquo;t get the domain I want, how do I pick a memorable alternative?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-1&#34;&gt;I think the domain I want is taken. Help!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your first step is to enter the domain name you&amp;rsquo;re interested in &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. The list provided will show you which domain extensions (like .COM and .CO) are available with your desired name, and also which have already been registered. (And keep in mind that not every registered domain has an active website. You can have as many domains as you want as long as you keep paying for them.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a domain name is not showing as available, some reasons might be that the owner:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;is using it for a website&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;is planning to use it on a site that&amp;rsquo;s not launched yet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;is only using the domain for email addresses (e.g. hello@theperfectdomain.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;is keeping it because the name is similar to a domain he/she is actively using and the domain is being redirected to their site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;has an idea for the future and registered the domain in advance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;is just fond of the name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;wants to prevent other entities from using his/her name or brand&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Can I just register the same name with a different domain extension?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, if &amp;ldquo;theperfectdomain&lt;em&gt;.com&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; is already registered, you could always just register the same domain name with a different extension, e.g. &amp;ldquo;theperfectdomain&lt;em&gt;.info&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;. The biggest potential problem with using alternative extensions is that people could forget your domain, and by default go to the .COM domain instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slowly but surely though, people are embracing top-level domains (TLDs) other than .COM. (In case you&amp;rsquo;re wondering, the TLD is the part of the domain after the dot, e.g. the &amp;ldquo;COM&amp;rdquo; in theperfectdomain.com) And with &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/new-gtld-domain-extensions&#34;&gt;hundreds of new generic top-level domains (gTLDs)&lt;/a&gt; hitting the market, ranging from city names (e.g. &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-london&#34;&gt;.LONDON&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-berlin&#34;&gt;.BERLIN&lt;/a&gt;) to hobbies and professions (e.g. &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-photography&#34;&gt;.PHOTOGRAPHY&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-accountants&#34;&gt;.ACCOUNTANTS&lt;/a&gt;) to surnames (e.g. &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-kim&#34;&gt;.KIM&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-wang&#34;&gt;.WANG&lt;/a&gt;), it&amp;rsquo;s becoming more normal by the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, it will take time for people to get used to this new world where anything is .POSSIBLE. (Note: .POSSIBLE is not actually one of the new gTLDs, though it should be.) Just be aware of the hopefully short-term drawbacks to using a TLD other than .COM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Couldn&amp;rsquo;t I just get a username on a big web platform?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having your own domain name, even if it&amp;rsquo;s not perfect, is a far better option than building your online presence on top of another service&amp;rsquo;s URL, e.g. yourshop.shopify.com or facebook.com/yourcompany. This practice of building your brand, service, or web presence on another organization&amp;rsquo;s platform is an example of &amp;ldquo;sharecropping&amp;rdquo;, and can be problematic for a number of reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this sharecropping setup, the platform you&amp;rsquo;re hosted on:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;controls how your presence can look or function (e.g. templates and tiered feature offerings depending on how much you pay).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;can change services or raise rates, leaving you little recourse, since not accepting/paying could mean losing your site.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;can control how much exposure you get. There&amp;rsquo;ve been lots of articles about issues with brands on Facebook getting ever-lessening exposure of their content to their fans if they don&amp;rsquo;t pay for advertising.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;can limit your access to analytics, making it hard to know how large your audience is, what they&amp;rsquo;re doing on your site, or where they&amp;rsquo;re engaging when they&amp;rsquo;re there.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;can simply take your site offline without much notice, explanation or recourse if you are deemed to have violated terms of service or other issues. It can take a lot of time and frustration to get these issues sorted out, and all the while your site is unavailable to anyone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can always switch domains later, but it&amp;rsquo;s a good idea to start with a web address you control while you build up your search engine visibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;If someone isn&amp;rsquo;t using the domain I want, is there a way I can just have it?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No. Well, not without the owner agreeing to transfer it to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a domain is registered to someone else, they have paid for it and own it. Having an active website isn&amp;rsquo;t required to own a domain, and as long as the person pays to renew ownership, no one else can have the domain, even if they don&amp;rsquo;t appear to be using it—unless that person agrees to transfer or sell the domain, or lets it expire. (Or, in some cases, if their ownership or usage of the domain violates someone else&amp;rsquo;s trademark.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Asking a registrar to take a domain for you won&amp;rsquo;t work, either. Registrars have no more legal right to remove it from the owner than you do, and this applies globally, not just in a specific country. Think of it in reverse: if someone else decided they wanted &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; domain, would you be okay with us just taking it from you and giving it to them, regardless of what you were doing with it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-2&#34;&gt;What is domain squatting/cybersquatting?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, domain squatting (occasionally still called cybersquatting) is where people register domains that are closely related to a trademark or brand, with the intention of selling them off for (sometimes very large) profit. By doing this, squatters are gambling that the company or person targeted will just pay what the squatter wants to avoid expensive legal proceedings and the risk of being denied the rights to that domain name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, a registrant might register &amp;ldquo;thisismycompany.ca&amp;rdquo; in hopes that the company, which is based in New Zealand, for example, would start doing a lot of business in Canada and want to buy that domain. Or if a company was launching a new product called SuperNamer, and a registrant who didn&amp;rsquo;t represent the company registered &amp;ldquo;supernamer.com&amp;rdquo; to try and make the company pay for that domain so they could launch their new product with the most recognizable domain name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Domain squatting can also be done accidentally by someone with good intentions, e.g. a big fan of a particular celebrity, character or sports team. That person could register the domain, e.g. &amp;ldquo;batman.com&amp;rdquo; and set up a fan site dedicated to all things Batman, even though the site isn&amp;rsquo;t owned by DC Comics, who own the rights to the Batman character.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As noted, the person who set up the site might just be a huge Batman fan, but the person could also be hoping that DC will offer them a lot of money for the domain to avoid legal wrangling (though, in this case, the squatter wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have much of a case).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Legally, resolving domain squatting requires determining several things. Is the domain name part of someone&amp;rsquo;s trademark? Is the domain name part of a well-known brand, even if not trademarked? (Like a celebrity&amp;rsquo;s identity, e.g. it&amp;rsquo;s unlikely anyone&amp;rsquo;s going to assume &amp;ldquo;georgeclooney.com&amp;rdquo; is about anyone other than the actor.) Was the person who bought the domain acting in &amp;ldquo;good faith&amp;rdquo; (e.g. big fan) or &amp;ldquo;bad faith&amp;rdquo; (i.e. hoping to profit from identity assumptions or sale)?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bad faith domain squatting is illegal, but can still be expensive to resolve through legal channels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What is the difference between domain speculation and squatting?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no single, definitive (i.e. legally binding) definition, but generally squatting implies &amp;ldquo;bad faith&amp;rdquo; intent on the part of the person or company that has registered the domain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That means they have no interest in or intentions of creating a website for the domain or otherwise using it (like it becoming the main web presence for their business). That person just bought it to sell it for more than they paid for it (ideally much more).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Domain speculation, on the other hand, involves registering domains that might be useful or of interest, but which don&amp;rsquo;t block an existing trademark or brand. For example, instead of registering a variant of an existing company&amp;rsquo;s domain, a domain speculator would register something more general, like &amp;ldquo;weselldomains.com&amp;rdquo;, in hopes that some domain registrar might want it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speculators are often more open about the fact that the domains in their portfolio are for sale, as well. Whereas squatters might set up a basic page to make it marginally look like the domain is in use, or create a parking page (a temporary page, usually used to as a placeholder until a real site is ready) full of ads to try to get click traffic for extra revenue until they can sell the domain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some squatters own many domains, though some will only target a few, since the more domains you own that haven&amp;rsquo;t sold yet, the more money you&amp;rsquo;ve invested without return. Speculators often own a large portfolio of domains, targeting various industries with a selection of relevant terms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Domain squatting, if a person&amp;rsquo;s or company&amp;rsquo;s actions are deemed to be that, is illegal. Some countries have specific laws against squatting that are more specific than standard trademark law. However, since the internet is a global entity, issues of jurisdiction can arise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-3&#34;&gt;What do I do if has registered a domain with my trademark?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will need to follow the instructions outlined in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.icann.org/en/help/dndr/udrp&#34;&gt;ICANN&amp;rsquo;s Uniform Domain-Name Dispute-Resolution Policy&lt;/a&gt; (UDRP). Consulting a lawyer may also be useful in ensuring your case is as strong as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note, however, that even though you own the trademark, a domain squatter will still likely fight to keep the domain, since it was purchased in the first place to make money. Getting the domain name may be expensive, but if you own the trademark (or are a celebrity), you have a good chance of getting the domain from the squatter. Really, it comes down to whether it&amp;rsquo;s worth the trouble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Can I buy the domain I want from the owner?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Possibly. Certainly you can contact the person or company and see if they&amp;rsquo;re interested in selling it. Be aware though that the person who owns the domain is under no obligation to sell it, may want a lot more money for it than you&amp;rsquo;re willing or able to pay, and may not be very interested in negotiating the price. Best to start off by casually (and politely) asking if the owner would be interested in selling without sharing too much about who you are and why you want the domain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an interested buyer, your only leverage is how much you&amp;rsquo;re willing or able to spend, and your ability to walk away if you can&amp;rsquo;t come to agreeable terms. It&amp;rsquo;s always a good idea to have other options available to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, don&amp;rsquo;t order business cards or marketing collateral with a specific domain name on them if you don&amp;rsquo;t absolutely positively own the domain already. That&amp;rsquo;s just setting yourself up for failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;How do I find out who owns the domain I want?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To find out who owns a domain, try a &lt;a href=&#34;http://whois.domaintools.com/&#34;&gt;WHOIS lookup&lt;/a&gt;. Typically the contact information of the person who owns the domain will appear on the search results page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if they are using a privacy service, there should still be an email address you can use to contact the owner, or at least a domain holding company. If a domain is held by a company wanting to make money on selling domains, they&amp;rsquo;re probably going to make it easy to get a hold of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;How much is the domain I want worth?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That depends on a lot of factors. There is no service you can check to see what a given domain should be worth. Any site that claims to tell you what your domain name or social media account is worth is just using some arbitrary calculation. They are just for fun and have no legal use or bearing on actual domain value or prices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any domain is worth what a buyer is willing to pay for it (assuming the owner is interested in selling at all). Note that some domain owners have pretty grandiose ideas about what their domain is worth, or think they can get rich quick off some desperate buyer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many things that can influence the cost of a domain name. Some examples:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the word(s) in the name are simple, clear and common, including standard spellings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the word(s) is a recognizable person, company, product, etc. (i.e. don&amp;rsquo;t expect to get &amp;ldquo;coke.com&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the domain is already in use (as noted, there&amp;rsquo;s a website, email addresses, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the domain name is related to something that may become important in the future, e.g. an event, new product, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how badly the owner can tell that you want it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how badly the owner needs or wants the money&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how much you appear to be willing or able to pay for it (e.g. there&amp;rsquo;s a good chance that the price may be higher if a company wants a domain than if just an individual person does)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the legal status of the domain (e.g. is it a registered trademark)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the state of the industry or economy (e.g. during a tech bubble, like many things, domain name prices may become inflated).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-4&#34;&gt;How do I find out if the domain I want becomes available?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re not comfortable contacting the domain owner directly, or you tried and didn&amp;rsquo;t get a response, you can attempt to procure the domain when it expires.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is anything but a guaranteed strategy, however. Most registrars remind their customers early and often prior to domains expiring. Many registrars also auto-renew domains by default as long as the customer&amp;rsquo;s payment details are accurate and up to date. (&lt;a href=&#34;http://help.iwantmyname.com/customer/portal/articles/184422&#34;&gt;iwantmyname does both of these things for their customers.&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if a domain&amp;rsquo;s ownership does expire, many registrars give their customers a grace period after expiration so they can still renew it, sometimes at a considerably increased cost. (This pricing is set by the registries, not registrars like iwantmyname.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could also try a domain monitoring service, which alerts you to status changes and expirations for your domains, or others that are of interest to you. Be aware though that this offering can be an upsell attempt by some registrars. (iwantmyname does not offer this service.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Backordering services are also popular, and if you want a maximum chance of getting the domain if/when it expires, we recommend using all of them. Most of these services will only charge you if they manage to procure the domain, but some charge in advance. Here are a few popular options:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://namejet.com&#34;&gt;NameJet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://snapnames.com&#34;&gt;SnapNames&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://backorderzone.com&#34;&gt;BackorderZone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://pool.com&#34;&gt;Pool.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Can you make an offer for a domain name for me?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This service is called brokerage, and iwantmyname does not offer any domain brokerage services. We recommend contacting &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sedo.com/us/buy-domains/domain-brokerage/&#34;&gt;Sedo&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://domainagents.com/&#34;&gt;DomainAgents&lt;/a&gt; to assist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What brokers will do is contact the domain owner (if they can), then make an offer for the domain for you, handle negotiations, and finalize the agreement to purchase and transfer the domain. You will pay the broker a fee in addition to whatever price you pay for the domain name itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-5&#34;&gt;If I can&#39;t get the domain I want, how do I pick a memorable alternative?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned before, you could look for a variant of &amp;ldquo;theperfectdomain&amp;rdquo;. But be aware of potential confusion if the domain extension (e.g. .NET / .GURU / .CA) is the only difference between your domain and someone else&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could try small changes to the domain name you want, like adding or dropping an article. Instead of &amp;ldquo;companyname&amp;rdquo;, use &amp;ldquo;thecompanyname&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;getproductname&amp;rdquo;. Again, there is still a good chance people will get confused.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of directly referring to your company, group, or topic name, you could focus on something relevant and important, like what the product or service enables you to do. A photographer could register a domain using &amp;ldquo;shoot&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;snap&amp;rdquo;, or referencing &amp;ldquo;memories&amp;rdquo;. A group of pilots could use &amp;ldquo;fly&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;wings,&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;soar&amp;rdquo;. Using slang or terminology common among your group could make for a memorable domain name as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another consideration is where you or your organization is located geographically. Should you embrace the international nature of the Internet, or stay local? Should you use a gTLD or a country code top-level domain (ccTLD) that shows your roots, like &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/ca-canadian-domain-name-registration-for-canada&#34;&gt;.CA&lt;/a&gt; for Canada or &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-nz&#34;&gt;.NZ&lt;/a&gt; for New Zealand?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could also use a TLD to &amp;ldquo;hack&amp;rdquo; the domain and create an interesting and relevant phrase. For example, if you wanted to register &amp;ldquo;bobswaffles.com&amp;rdquo;, but it was taken, instead you could register &amp;ldquo;bobswaffl.es&amp;rdquo; (using &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/es-spanish-domain-name-registration-for-spain&#34;&gt;.ES&lt;/a&gt;, Spain&amp;rsquo;s ccTLD). Be sure to read our &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/04/everything-you-need-to-know-about-domain-hacks.html&#34;&gt;guide to everything you need to know about domain hacks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photo credit: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/emilymills/3586292198/in/photolist-6sUFJ7-Cn1Ze-dj4RAk-dQjT8A-7CJaeC-huuCjX-nY6QF8-e9VnmW-dUsAAu-dUsAAj-dskac2-oy2U8q-6sfdfY-dUH3Ph-baJNi2-8Hp6A7-dWZixW-fxEKMN-pDAPVf-aW5VHR-9cvW1B-eh2vj3-opkJi-eJJwjw-9AHjr1-5uSeNW-dYbL63-5SLYBT-aCHr3L-aCEHmr-aCHpzh-8HkXak-gaE57n-aCECXt-aCHjgC-aCHi4w-a5GYRn-7Wb521-29ULM-5vUPbT-e1f58-fkgL8M-edn9BV-oXb7vY-qPGzyn-dNPjNx-f8NKt-65CrBC-4m3Gp-fxrB84&#34;&gt;Emily Mills&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2015 14:56:45 UTC</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/05/the-guide-to-getting-the-right-domain-name-for-your-brand.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/05/the-guide-to-getting-the-right-domain-name-for-your-brand.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Using .DESIGN to solve real online problems</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Designers. Friends. Frienemies. For too long you&amp;rsquo;ve been using domain names like fullnamedesign.com (or the slightly more mysterious *lastname*design.com) to show off your online portfolios. So many letters! So much waste! Before you spend one more day fiddling around with this madness, let&amp;rsquo;s get down to clearly identifying the problem you probably don&amp;rsquo;t even know you&amp;rsquo;re facing. Then let&amp;rsquo;s fix it. Together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this example, let&amp;rsquo;s pretend that all the letters in a domain name before the &amp;ldquo;.&amp;rdquo; are pieces of furniture&amp;hellip; and they&amp;rsquo;re all beautiful. Here&amp;rsquo;s the question. In a well-designed space, how many beautiful pieces of furniture do you want? Five? Six? Eight? Yes, yes, yes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;14?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Woah, woah. That&amp;rsquo;s a lot of furniture before the dot—but that&amp;rsquo;s how many letters there are in &amp;ldquo;fullnamedesign.&amp;rdquo; And if your name happened to be Nathaniel Tabernacle (which would come to nathanieltabernacledesign.com), you&amp;rsquo;re looking at a whopping 25!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how do we fix this? Just nix the word &amp;ldquo;design&amp;rdquo; before the dot and go with the brand new &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-design&#34;&gt;.DESIGN&lt;/a&gt; top-level domain (TLD), the designiest TLD on the market today (although &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/nl-dutch-domain-name-registration-for-netherlands&#34;&gt;.NL&lt;/a&gt; might give you some Dutch designery street cred). Instead of fullnamedesign.com, you could just have fullname.design! Beautiful spacing. Clean, legible words. It&amp;rsquo;s everything you could ever want from your domain name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And from May 18-31, we&amp;rsquo;re dropping the price of .DESIGN from $69 USD to $39 USD. That&amp;rsquo;s less than some people spend over the summer on a week of morning cold brews (coffee, not beer&amp;hellip; although morning beer is delicious).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s make this happen, designers. Your domain names are all cluttered with excess and it&amp;rsquo;s giving people anxiety attacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photo Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/mcinteractivity/13033013324/in/photolist-kRFANh-dqgU8-2Svg1v-LQmKM-MCB3v-6zJagD-6VJvq6-LQb3m-dqgYt-dqgTf-6Hswze-8QRqEW-8QRqx1-8QNkxa-dqgYM-MCtyw-MCtyh-MCtxC-MCtwf-diMYjG-6CEyhw-p5Z936-93Q4XY-6ZJQ9A-6ZEPC4-4ZwPqo-6HwzC1-oNua8R-4ZsACT-LQkwt-6HwzzC-6HwzyU-6zJ62p-2Svf9z-dqgTP-oNuiLd-p5HNRr-p5Z6HM-p5HNkB-p5HMZg-au4v3X-cg3Kj5-dqgUs-p5HT1P-2SveHg-dqgQ5-MCB66-6ZEPUg-MCtBL-dqgNG&#34;&gt;Mathieu Cheviron&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2015 11:28:33 UTC</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/05/using-design-to-solve-real-online-problems.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/05/using-design-to-solve-real-online-problems.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>The guide to adding Squarespace to your iwantmyname domain</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/features/applications/custom-domain-apps/websites/squarespace-build-your-website-with-own-url&#34;&gt;Squarespace&lt;/a&gt; is an amazing, all-in-one site builder that makes top-end web design accessible to everyone. Seriously, with no skill going in, you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to build sites, stores, photo galleries, and blogs in minutes. It&amp;rsquo;s that intuitive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s not quite as intuitive though is the domain setup. We pride ourselves in providing one-click installs to a ton of platforms, but sometimes there&amp;rsquo;s an extra step involved that can turn that one click into a bunch of clicks. Have no fear though, with this short guide, you&amp;rsquo;ll have your domain working with your Squarespace site in no time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-1&#34;&gt;Start your Squarespace site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-2&#34;&gt;Go to Settings &amp;gt; Domains &amp;gt; Connect Third-Party Domain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-3&#34;&gt;Enter your domain name&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-4&#34;&gt;Select iwantmyname from the Domain Provider list&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-5&#34;&gt;Click okay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-6&#34;&gt;Copy your verification code (it&amp;rsquo;s right under Host)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-7&#34;&gt;Add Squarespace to your domain in iwantmyname&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-8&#34;&gt;Paste your verification code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-9&#34;&gt;Back to Squarespace, hit refresh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-10&#34;&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re all done!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;section-1&#34;&gt;1. Start your Squarespace site&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get started with Squarespace by clicking &lt;strong&gt;Get Started&lt;/strong&gt; on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://squarespace.com&#34;&gt;Squarespace homepage&lt;/a&gt;, choosing a template, then clicking the &lt;strong&gt;Start With This Design&lt;/strong&gt; button. There are a couple quick questions you can answer after that, or you can skip them for now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/media/2015-05-11-squarespace-home.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Squarespace home&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;section-2&#34;&gt;2. Go to Settings &gt; Domains &gt; Connect Third-Party Domain&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From Squarespace&amp;rsquo;s side navigation, click &lt;strong&gt;Settings&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;gt; &lt;strong&gt;Domains&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;gt; &lt;strong&gt;Connect a Third-Party Domain&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/media/2015-05-11-squarespace-settings.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Settings&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;section-3&#34;&gt;3. Enter your domain name&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enter your domain name in the Domain Name field provided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/media/2015-05-11-squarespace-domain-iwantmyblog.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Add domain&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;section-4&#34;&gt;4. Select iwantmyname from the Domain Provider list&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Select &lt;strong&gt;iwantmyname&lt;/strong&gt; from the Domain Provider dropdown list. Click &lt;strong&gt;Connect Domain&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/media/2015-05-11-squarespace-select-iwantmyname.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Dropdown iwantmyname&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;section-5&#34;&gt;5. Click okay&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Squarespace is now linking your domain. Click &lt;strong&gt;okay&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/media/2015-05-11-squarespace-in-progress.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Click okay&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;section-6&#34;&gt;6. Copy your verification code (it&#39;s right under Host)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Copy that long string of letters and numbers listed first under the Host column (it&amp;rsquo;ll look somehting like: abcde1fg2h3ijk4lmn5o). This is the verification code you&amp;rsquo;ll add in the iwantmyname dashboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/media/2015-05-11-squarespace-host.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Copy string&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;section-7&#34;&gt;7. Add Squarespace to your domain in iwantmyname&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open a new window and log into your iwantmyname account, then head to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/dashboard/apps/setup/Squarespace/&#34;&gt;Squarespace app setup page&lt;/a&gt;. Click Add Squarespace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;section-8&#34;&gt;8. Paste your verification code&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ve already signed up for squarespace, so now add the verification code to the &amp;lsquo;Unique verification code&amp;rsquo; input. Then click &lt;strong&gt;Install Squarespace&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/media/2015-05-11-squarespace-unique-ver.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Unique Code&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;section-9&#34;&gt;9. Back to Squarespace, hit refresh&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back on your Squarespace window, if you click &lt;strong&gt;Refresh&lt;/strong&gt;, everything should now say Correct. Sometimes it takes a bit (up to a few hours) for these things to work through the internet though, so don&amp;rsquo;t be alarmed if things don&amp;rsquo;t look correct right away. Just jump to the next step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/media/2015-05-11-squarespace-correct.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Correct&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;section-10&#34;&gt;10. You&#39;re all done!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re all done! Have fun building your Squarespace site!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2015 15:48:53 UTC</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/05/the-guide-to-adding-squarespace-to-your-domain.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/05/the-guide-to-adding-squarespace-to-your-domain.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Taking stock of our 2015 community involvement</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being involved in the local community is vastly important to us, so this year we made a conscious decision to support more events that at least some of the iwantmyname team could actively participate in. Since we are already one-third of the way through 2015, I think it&amp;rsquo;s about time to take stock of what has been achieved so far and look at where we plan to go in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Startup Weekends loom large in our consciousness, and this year has been no exception. Organisers of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.startupweekend.co.nz/&#34;&gt;Startup Weekends here in New Zealand&lt;/a&gt; have a busy schedule planned, and we&amp;rsquo;ve already been lucky enough to sponsor and participate in the recent Wellington event. Lenz and I put on our mentor hats, Kevin Ingersoll participated in a team, and Coco the domain dog lent moral support by snoozing blissfully throughout. So imagine our excitement when the judges announced that Kevin&amp;rsquo;s team had &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/iwantmynameNZ/status/587195037274005504&#34;&gt;scored a well-earned win&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thrills of Startup Weekend were soon followed by intellectual debate and thorough workshopping of the open source paradigm at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://opensourceopensociety.com/&#34;&gt;Open Source Open Society conference&lt;/a&gt;, held in conjunction with Github and Enspiral. We employ open source technologies and open thinking &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/03/does-open-source-contribute-to-a-more-open-society.html&#34;&gt;throughout our business&lt;/a&gt;, so it seemed like the perfect event for us to be a part of. There was also a cool closing party with a funky, indie DJ on tap, so nobody wanted to leave—but that&amp;rsquo;s another story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also remain keen backers of the PHP Meetup and JavaScript Meetup in our city, and have been helping out with the R9 initiative, an experimental incubator aiming to solve important business problems in the government sector by using lean methodologies. Many of these events have our local tech business incubator &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativehq.co.nz/&#34;&gt;Creative HQ&lt;/a&gt; at their heart, so we&amp;rsquo;re more than thrilled to be announcing a strategic partnership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From this week on, we will be shouting the beers at the highly popular &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/StartupGarage/&#34;&gt;Startup Garage&lt;/a&gt; Meetup. Each month, Creative HQ hosts an interesting speaker from the start-up world, many of whom bring wisdom from afar. Recent appearances have included SXSW organiser Shawn O&amp;rsquo;Keefe and President of Y Combinator, Sam Altman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2015 is shaping up to be a big year for community involvement here at iwantmyname, and we&amp;rsquo;re excited to make further inroads in the local start-up ecosystem. If you see us around, come say hi! We&amp;rsquo;d love to chat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photo Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://marktantrum.photoshelter.com/gallery-image/Startup-Weekend-Wellington-2015/G0000kh_BLuFtiHg/I0000cpYprJxO9W8/C00009qyVsLVsm0o&#34;&gt;Mark Tantrum Photography&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2015 14:27:22 UTC</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/04/taking-stock-of-our-community-involvement.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/04/taking-stock-of-our-community-involvement.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Making customer support sustainable with a small team based on a tiny island</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter what service you offer or product you sell, a good chunk of any business is customer support. But unlike many other aspects of running a business, how companies handle customer support can vary widely, even among companies in the same industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our little corner of the Internet, the domain industry, we have a couple of unique challenges. First, domain registration is a comparatively low margin business, so to keep our business afloat, we rely on the support of a lot of customers. Tens of thousands, with 150,000+ domains under management. And no matter how stable your platform, when you&amp;rsquo;re dealing with that many moving parts, any flaw, bug, or confusing process will be uncovered very quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second challenge is the clock. Most of the iwantmyname team is in New Zealand, but what happens when it&amp;rsquo;s 10pm, and someone has an issue in London, where it&amp;rsquo;s only 11am? Is it acceptable to pass on the expectation that people need sleep? It&amp;rsquo;s an honest question, and a concern for many small companies that can&amp;rsquo;t afford to have 24-hour call centers or offices all around the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Web is an instant answer world without any face-to-face dialogue, which strips a lot of the humanity out of the process. And we all fall into it—if my website breaks, I expect instant answers, but if my car breaks, I know I have to set an appointment during business hours. It&amp;rsquo;s all about setting expectations, and that&amp;rsquo;s one of the hardest things for businesses to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{{ template &amp;ldquo;iframe&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://giphy.com/embed/j62Hmj6SMpJV6?html5=true&amp;quot;&#34;&gt;https://giphy.com/embed/j62Hmj6SMpJV6?html5=true&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt; }}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To handle the support load, companies can go a few different directions. As I stated before, they can stock up a support team or outsource all the support to a third party, but that&amp;rsquo;s expensive, impersonal, and honestly, a little underwhelming in the experience department. Sure, there are a lot of quick Q&amp;amp;A type issues that can be handled quickly by anyone with basic knowledge of the domain industry, but if you have a real problem, you want real solutions. Nothing is more aggravating than dealing with a support layer that clearly won&amp;rsquo;t be able to solve your problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another issue with stocking up a support team is our rather unique salary structure. &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2014/05/culture-at-iwmn-part-one.html&#34;&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve written about it before&lt;/a&gt;, but our philosophy from the start has been to pay everyone on the team a flat wage. On the customer side, it may be frustrating to not see us hire 20 low-wage support specialists, but we strongly believe in companies providing livable wages to their employees. As Lenz, one of our co-founders, has said in the past, the wellbeing of the team is just as important as the well-being of the company. People are important, and as they grow, the company grows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So after years of dual roles and unsustainable hours, it was clear that a distributed support team was a must. We needed a better way to support the Americas on Fridays (which are Saturdays in NZ), and we needed a way to cover the middle of the world during normal business hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, we hired Melle (last year), who in eastern Canada could take on American business hours—and what a difference it made. With her in Canada and the rest of the dual-role supporters in NZ, we could roughly cover 17 hours of the day, Tuesday-Friday, with people working a typical 8am-5pm day, then nine hours on NZ Mondays and Saturdays (Fridays in Canada). But still, if someone had an issue in London on Monday at 9am, it would be in the wee early morning for Melle, and well past dinner for the New Zealanders. Life was certainly better, but there were still support gaps—and our brave co-founder Paul was still sometimes working seven days a week to make sure the support load never got out of hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Growth is a tricky thing with a small, bootstrapped team, but our trajectory for 2015 and beyond led us to two very important decisions. To create the best possible experience for our customers, we&amp;rsquo;d need:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a UI designer to help build a solid interface (which, through organization and clear instructions, will hopefully cut down our future support load quite a bit)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a second supporter in Europe to cover our gaps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, Kevin, who was hired a few months back, has been hard at work on new interface ideas. And our newest iwantmynamer, Steffi, is working through support cases from her house in Germany (and she&amp;rsquo;s quite awesome at it).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now, with three support &amp;ldquo;teams&amp;rdquo; scattered around the planet, we&amp;rsquo;re roughly covering 23 hours of the day, Tuesday-Friday, then 15 hours on Saturday, all without stretching any of our work schedules beyond a reasonable amount. New Zealand Sundays are still a hole for us, so we typically only cover urgent cases then, but as long as we set the right expectations, our email-based support system is perfect for getting everything worked out in a timely manner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We often get asked why we don&amp;rsquo;t offer a phone service or an instant-on online chat, and the answer is simple—instant communication is inefficient, and often leads to answers that aren&amp;rsquo;t fully thought out or articulated well. Quite a few things have to happen to answer a support question successfully. We have to get the problem, understand the problem, find the problem, take the steps to fix it, and then break down an easily actionable solution. Sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s as easy as sending a link, but other times issues need to be handled by multiple people in multiple places (registries, platforms, etc.), which aren&amp;rsquo;t always under our control. And that takes time—especially when there are questions in the queue coming in from all over the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With our &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/support&#34;&gt;email-only support&lt;/a&gt;, we can get to each question as fast as humanly possible without wasting our customers&amp;rsquo; valuable time sitting on hold or finding their way through strange automated systems. And with our support answers all in written form, we can easily build a &lt;a href=&#34;https://help.iwantmyname.com&#34;&gt;knowledge base&lt;/a&gt; full of quick answers to common questions. It&amp;rsquo;s been working well for us so far (&lt;a href=&#34;http://public.nicereply.com/iwantmyname&#34;&gt;96% love it!&lt;/a&gt;), and hopefully it&amp;rsquo;ll only get better as our interface becomes easier and easier to use and navigate.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2015 10:39:40 UTC</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/04/making-customer-support-sustainable-with-a-small-team-based-on-a-tiny-island.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/04/making-customer-support-sustainable-with-a-small-team-based-on-a-tiny-island.html</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
