<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>iwantmyname Domain Blog</title>
		<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/</link>
		<atom:link href="https://iwantmyname.com/blog/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>New plugin: GitLab Pages</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re using GitLab as your Git repository manager and want to create a quick, static site about a project (or anything, really), GitLab Pages is your ticket. Much like GitHub Pages, GitLab Pages lets you host static sites directly on your GitLab instance. Just choose a static site generator, use a free shared runner (or your own), and start editing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is it for everyone? No. If you&amp;rsquo;re a casual blogger or someone looking at do-it-all site builders like Squarespace, GitLab Pages probably isn&amp;rsquo;t for you. But if you&amp;rsquo;re already using GitLab, or have been waiting for a Pages-type feature to coerce you into switching over from Github, this is perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/services/developer/gitlab-pages&#34;&gt;Get a new domain with GitLab Pages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/services/developer/&#34;&gt;Check out all of our Developer plugins&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;From the web:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://venturebeat.com/2015/12/22/gitlab-just-launched-another-feature-that-will-help-it-compete-with-github/&#34;&gt;Venture Beat&lt;/a&gt;: &amp;ldquo;Step by step, GitLab, the startup behind the GitLab open source software for managing source code, is becoming more competitive with GitHub, the company well known for hosting source code for many applications.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2016 08:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2016/04/new-plugin-gitlab-pages.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2016/04/new-plugin-gitlab-pages.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Make .MOM the perfect Mother&#39;s Day gift, and more domain extension news</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;We often think of domains as these forever pieces of property meant for big sites that attract as many eyes as humanly possible, but what if you just want to make one person happy? Domains can do that, too! Here&amp;rsquo;s a mini gift guide for Mom, perfect for Mother&amp;rsquo;s Day (May 8th&amp;hellip; put it on your calendar).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pre-order a &lt;a href=&#34;[.MOM](https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-mom)&#34;&gt;.MOM domain&lt;/a&gt;. Make it something your mom will go &amp;ldquo;awwwwww&amp;rdquo; over.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On May 3rd, when you get your domain, find as many great pictures of you and your mom as you can. (Bonus points for grandchildren pics, if you&amp;rsquo;re into that).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a quick &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/services/portfolio-hosting/&#34;&gt;photo site&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/services/blog-hosting/&#34;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; out of the pics, or be ambitious and create an &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/services/portfolio-hosting/exposure-photo-websites&#34;&gt;Exposure&lt;/a&gt; story. Exposure is a cool platform for piecing together photos to create a little (or long) narrative – it&amp;rsquo;s a guaranteed crowd pleaser. (And since your site will be public, your mom can send it to all her friends to show them how creative you are.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can take the site down anytime, but as long as you renew the domain, you can reuse it every year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Send flowers. Always send flowers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Other domain extension goodies&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Popular Top-Level Domains (TLDs)*&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-krd&#34;&gt;.KRD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-game&#34;&gt;.GAME&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-free&#34;&gt;.FREE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/io-domain-sale-promo-offer&#34;&gt;.IO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-now&#34;&gt;.NOW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*&lt;em&gt;Methodology: Popularity rankings based on last week&amp;rsquo;s pageviews. This means the TLD list isn&amp;rsquo;t based on actual domains registered, just traffic to the landing pages.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Upcoming launch dates for new extensions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;May 3 - &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-mom&#34;&gt;.MOM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;May 17 - &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-game&#34;&gt;.GAME&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;May 23 - &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-vip&#34;&gt;.VIP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;June 7 - &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-salon&#34;&gt;.SALON&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;June 13 - &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-store&#34;&gt;.STORE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 11:48:00 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2016/04/make-mom-the-perfect-mothers-day-gift.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2016/04/make-mom-the-perfect-mothers-day-gift.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Get your domain branding strategies in order</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was mid-2015. There was a bit of a tempest in a teapot online over the launch of the .SUCKS TLD. Did every brand need to buy up all variations of their company/product/service with the .SUCKS TLD to keep them away from technically savvy ne&amp;rsquo;er-do-wells?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not really, no. Maybe the negative .SUCKS sites are out there, but they seriously lack Google juice and audience engagement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The truth is, there are a million domain branding strategies that are potentially more important than focusing on whether someone might not like you. Such as? Glad you asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-1&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s in a name?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-2&#34;&gt;Be aware of your location, and growth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-3&#34;&gt;Planning for name changes and product success&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-4&#34;&gt;That doesn&amp;rsquo;t belong to you&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-5&#34;&gt;Think it through&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-1&#34;&gt;What&#39;s in a name?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First impressions are important, and company and product names are no exception. Do you go with a strong, descriptive name that may reflect your product, service, or industry, or a fun, memorable, one intended to make a statement, like &amp;ldquo;Google&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many companies invest a lot of resources – time, money, brain power – coming up with naming solutions, so we&amp;rsquo;ll leave company naming for another day, but modern society has given us a new level of complexity that directly ties to your domain strategy. Availability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Availability comes in many flavors. Let&amp;rsquo;s say your brand is &amp;ldquo;Bob&amp;rsquo;s Concrete&amp;rdquo;. In addition to worrying about trademarks (more on that later), it&amp;rsquo;s probably safe to assume bobsconcrete.com is already taken. It&amp;rsquo;s also probably safe to assume that the corresponding social handles are gone as well (which is perhaps a bigger deal, because Twitter and Facebook don&amp;rsquo;t have &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/domain-name-registration-list-of-extensions&#34;&gt;500+ domain extensions&lt;/a&gt; to expand the naming pool).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the last 15+ years, startups have gone through a number of naming trends to get around the availability issue (not in any sort of chronological order):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;provide a directive like getproductname.com&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://domain.me/how-thefacebook-com-became-facebook-com/&#34;&gt;adding the word &amp;ldquo;the&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;use a trendy domain extension like .ly or .io&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;use a &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/04/everything-you-need-to-know-about-domain-hacks.html&#34;&gt;domain hack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;remove vowels?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before becoming the next company that attaches itself to a trend, ask around and see what your choices make people think of, if anything. And when you arrive on a name you like, secure it everywhere (domain, social handles, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-2&#34;&gt;Be aware of your location, and growth&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today you may be a couple people in a garage in Wellington or Waterloo, but tomorrow you could be the next Compu-Global-Hyper-Mega-Net, with offices around the world. Obviously, there&amp;rsquo;s a lot to do between A and B, but something to keep in mind as you name your company, products, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, when you start off, piesofpittsburgh.com or snacksinabox.nz may be the perfect domain for your company. But what happens when you have shops in New York, and Hong Kong, and London? Maybe your brand will be so strong that it&amp;rsquo;ll work around the world, but maybe not. When starting out, even if you&amp;rsquo;re using a local domain for SEO purposes, securing and simultaneously using a global domain extension like .COM is good practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conversely, if you&amp;rsquo;re only using a .COM (and you&amp;rsquo;re not in the US, where the ccTLD is rarely used), relevant localization with .DE, .CN, .BR, etc. can be a smart investment. It can even be a helpful identifier for things like corporate email. Keep in mind though that some ccTLD registries restrict words that can be used in domain names, whether they reference place names, are on a reserved list, or are deemed offensive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-3&#34;&gt;Planning for name changes and product success&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Companies tend to grow over time. Sure, some do the same thing and offer the same product or service for 100 years. But especially in tech, the odds are good that you&amp;rsquo;re going to expand or pivot at some point. It&amp;rsquo;s good to consider this early on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t necessarily predict the future, but you can think about it now (Will your products or services follow a naming convention, a la Apple? Or will your company diversify to the point that it splits into more focused entities, a la Google/Alphabet?). Maybe there is an obvious domain name or two that it would be prudent to secure now. Or perhaps you just want to keep an eye on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/new-gtld-domain-extensions&#34;&gt;newly delegated and launched gTLDs&lt;/a&gt; so that if one relevant to you comes up, you&amp;rsquo;re ready to grab some domains. (.BAKER&amp;hellip; one day&amp;hellip;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, a funny thing can happen if you have a product that becomes popular. It eclipses your company. I&amp;rsquo;ve worked at two companies where this has been the case. People knew BlackBerry, but who outside of locals knew RIM? Eventually, both companies I worked for ended up changing the company name to the name of the flagship product. (This is a big, fiddly, and expensive project.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, if you do that, it means you&amp;rsquo;ll need to procure a whole new set of online names. And if you want to buy an already-registered domain name, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to have a budget in mind and be very careful about &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/04/contacting-the-owner-of-a-domain-you-want-to-buy.html&#34;&gt;how you approach the owner&lt;/a&gt;, since it will be pretty obvious that they have something you want, and can basically set whatever price they want to sell it for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good practice, if you&amp;rsquo;re a product-based company with easily identifiable flagship items, is to secure their domain/social names at the beginning of the production cycle. And it&amp;rsquo;s easy to see why – a new .COM is a whole lot more affordable than the same domain, years later, on the aftermarket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-4&#34;&gt;That doesn&#39;t belong to you&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trademarks are serious business, and while there can be loopholes, it&amp;rsquo;s often a situation of &amp;ldquo;just because you can, doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean you should&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;supername.com is taken, supername.co isn&amp;rsquo;t. Is registering the second one a good idea? No, it isn&amp;rsquo;t (that&amp;rsquo;s phishing site behavior). Or AwesomeCompany might be well established in Japan, but you live in Peru, and AwesomeCompany is the &lt;em&gt;perfect&lt;/em&gt; name. Should you use it? Well, depends. You&amp;rsquo;ll need to check on what rights AwesomeCompany has already registered for the name, and where. (It&amp;rsquo;s rare that companies register trademarks &lt;em&gt;everywhere&lt;/em&gt;, but it&amp;rsquo;s not unusual for major markets to be well covered.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, if AwesomeCompany is a small, local outfit (like Bob&amp;rsquo;s Concrete) and isn&amp;rsquo;t likely to ever be trademarked or expand globally, then perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s okay to establish your company using that name. Generally, though, unless there are absolutely no better options, being as original as you can is a good idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, be aware of typo targeting. To protect yourself, it&amp;rsquo;s good to think of typos as your friend. Not as your company or product name, per se, but because everyone falls victim to fat fingers and tiny mobile keyboards sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How many misspelled variations of &amp;ldquo;google&amp;rdquo; do you think there are out there? And how many has Google bought up or registered themselves? You don&amp;rsquo;t want to have some parasitic site siphoning off your traffic – or worse, phishing – because your customers misspelled your domain name and didn&amp;rsquo;t realize it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time, don&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; try registering typo versions of another person or company&amp;rsquo;s domains, either. People might have gotten away with it more a decade ago, but any company of reasonable size now keeps an eye on such things, and you&amp;rsquo;re just begging to be slapped with a complaint and have your site and domain deleted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-5&#34;&gt;Think it through&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously, you&amp;rsquo;re never going to be able to predict every twist and turn your branding adventures will take. But you can give these things some thought and do some research. Even if you just end up knowing what to leave off of your short-lists, it&amp;rsquo;s time and effort well spent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like most things in life, getting naming and domains selection right the first time is a lot less work, expense, and headaches than trying to change something already launched. It&amp;rsquo;s hard work building a brand, and having to undo and redo all that for reasons you could have guarded against just .SUCKs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2016 10:21:09 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2016/04/get-your-domain-branding-strategy-in-order.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2016/04/get-your-domain-branding-strategy-in-order.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Popular last week on iwantmyname: March 28-April 3, 2016</title>
				<description>&lt;h3&gt;Top-Level Domains (TLDs)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-boo&#34;&gt;.BOO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-free&#34;&gt;.FREE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-ing&#34;&gt;.ING&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/com-domain-name-registration-for-commercial&#34;&gt;.COM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-app&#34;&gt;.APP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Plugins&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/services/hosted-email/fastmail-mail-hosting-own-domain&#34;&gt;FastMail&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/services/email-hosting/protonmail-custom-domain&#34;&gt;ProtonMail&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/services/url-shortener/bit.ly-pro-custom-domain-short-url-forwarding-service&#34;&gt;Bitly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/services/email-hosting/rackspace-apps&#34;&gt;Rackspace Apps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/services/email-hosting/pobox-mail-forwarding&#34;&gt;Pobox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Guides&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/06/the-guide-to-getting-your-own-custom-email-address.html&#34;&gt;The guide to getting your own custom email address&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/06/how-to-pick-the-right-domain-extension.html&#34;&gt;.COM? .IO? .PIZZA? How to pick the right domain extension (TLD)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/05/the-guide-to-getting-the-right-domain-name-for-your-brand.html&#34;&gt;What to do if the domain name you want is taken&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/04/contacting-the-owner-of-a-domain-you-want-to-buy.html&#34;&gt;Contacting the owner of a domain you want to buy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/04/everything-you-need-to-know-about-domain-hacks.html&#34;&gt;Everything you need to know about domain hacks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methodology: These popularity rankings are based entirely on pageviews on Google Analytics. This means the TLD list isn&amp;rsquo;t based on actual domains registered, just traffic to its landing page.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 09:07:00 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2016/04/popular-last-week-on-iwantmyname-march-28-april-3-2016.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2016/04/popular-last-week-on-iwantmyname-march-28-april-3-2016.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Popular last week on iwantmyname: March 21-27, 2016</title>
				<description>&lt;h3&gt;Guides&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/06/the-guide-to-getting-your-own-custom-email-address.html&#34;&gt;The guide to getting your own custom email address&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/06/how-to-pick-the-right-domain-extension.html&#34;&gt;.COM? .IO? .PIZZA? How to pick the right domain extension (TLD)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/05/the-guide-to-getting-the-right-domain-name-for-your-brand.html&#34;&gt;What to do if the domain name you want is taken&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/04/contacting-the-owner-of-a-domain-you-want-to-buy.html&#34;&gt;Contacting the owner of a domain you want to buy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/04/everything-you-need-to-know-about-domain-hacks.html&#34;&gt;Everything you need to know about domain hacks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Plugins&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/services/hosted-email/fastmail-mail-hosting-own-domain&#34;&gt;FastMail&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/services/email-hosting/protonmail-custom-domain&#34;&gt;ProtonMail&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/services/url-shortener/bit.ly-pro-custom-domain-short-url-forwarding-service&#34;&gt;Bitly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/services/email-hosting/rackspace-apps&#34;&gt;Rackspace Apps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/services/email-hosting/pobox-mail-forwarding&#34;&gt;Pobox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Top-Level Domains (TLDs)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-free&#34;&gt;.FREE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-game&#34;&gt;.GAME&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-now&#34;&gt;.NOW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-app&#34;&gt;.APP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-art&#34;&gt;.ART&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methodology: These popularity rankings are based entirely on pageviews on Google Analytics. This means the TLD list isn&amp;rsquo;t based on actual domains registered, just traffic to its landing page.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2016 15:30:00 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2016/03/popular-last-week-on-iwantmyname-march-21-27.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2016/03/popular-last-week-on-iwantmyname-march-21-27.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Friday break - &#34;Reply All #59: Good Job, Alex&#34;</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;If you like podcasts, this is one of my favorites. And this episode is about domain names!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gimletmedia.com/episode/59-good-job-alex/&#34;&gt;From Reply All, episode #59&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ALEX: So I was thinking, “Wow.” So Alisa had this website. She had it professionally designed many moons ago. When it was still really hard to design a website. So had someone design it for her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PJ: Like HTML days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ALEX: Yes. But it was really clunky and difficult to use, so she started getting notices from GoDaddy, and she was just like, fine, this thing can expire. But the thing is, that she didn’t quite understand what would happen when you let your domain name expire. I think she just assumed that the site itself would go away, but nothing would happen to the domain name. Like she could come back to it whenever she wanted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PJ: Mm mm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ALEX: Are you saying, “No she didn’t think that,” or “No that’s not what happens?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PJ: I’m saying the thing she believed in the past was not true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2016 09:50:21 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2016/03/friday-break-reply-all.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2016/03/friday-break-reply-all.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Meet Merlene, the newest iwantmynamer</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/media/2016-03-16-merlene.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Merlene&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Merlene is a self-described hoarder. Fortunately, she hoards domains, and not cats or anything weird. (She insists that two cats do not qualify as a hoard).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having been self-employed for a long time, Merlene is familiar with all sides of the online business game, from registering domains to teaching customers how to post content and use their email accounts. She has extensive experience working with everyone from IT staff to small business people to complete newbs, so she can help figure out what you need and get it built.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She can also help with your social media and marketing efforts, mix you a killer cocktail, and knit you cool stuff. (She&amp;rsquo;s a hobbyist yarn entrepreneur at &lt;a href=&#34;https://knitcreek.com/&#34;&gt;knitcreek.com&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amazingly, even though Merlene didn&amp;rsquo;t mention in her interviews the fact that long ago, in the mists of Internet time, she contributed to one of the Internets for Dummies books, we were totally jazzed to hire her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In her first weeks on board, we threw her in the deep end with support, and she&amp;rsquo;s done swimmingly. She even tackles tricky ccTLD edge cases with gusto. Unfortunately, while she&amp;rsquo;s with us in New Zealand, her home is without tech support, and the residents may end up forced to converse with each other, or just post cat gifs&amp;hellip; assuming internet access holds&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS. It is, indeed, Merlene with three Es.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2016 09:19:00 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2016/03/meet-merlene-the-newest-iwantmynamer.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2016/03/meet-merlene-the-newest-iwantmynamer.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Writing on the web, as an individual, is changing (probably for the better)</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;There was a time, not so long ago, when building a grand personal website sounded like a great idea. People – regular people – were committing a few hours a day to it, and actually making money. But somewhere around the middle of the 2000&amp;rsquo;s, social media got big, people started expressing themselves with shortform content, and consistently writing medium-to-longform posts became a major chore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, when I go and poll my friends and coworkers, the ones who still have traditional blogs are almost all living with a touch of guilt. Their online castles are outdated, their latest posts are collecting cobwebs, and the majority of their real writing is either going to their work or their social media accounts. (BTW, if this describes you, Timo recently &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2016/03/struggling-to-update-your-site.html&#34;&gt;wrote a great post&lt;/a&gt; about some alternative things you can do with your domain(s).)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But blogging isn&amp;rsquo;t dead. Far from it. It&amp;rsquo;s just different. Sure, there are those who still have dedicated personal blogs, but the newest trend is to push infrequent content to platforms that already have a huge reach, like Medium. Here&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;a href=&#34;http://venturebeat.com/2016/03/03/medium-plans-publisher-monetization-within-a-month-considers-paywalls-and-premium-content/&#34;&gt;recent quote&lt;/a&gt; from Medium founder, Ev Williams,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I think publishers who are experimenting with Medium are seeing a world where it’s not about having a website,” said Williams. “There are not going to be tens of millions of websites that lots of people go to every day.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What Medium offers is a way for people to write what they want with a solid CMS, on a platform that takes style decisions away from the author. That probably sounds terrible to some, but for many people, it&amp;rsquo;s a way to express themselves without having to worry about the stuff they&amp;rsquo;re not good at. Just write something up, hit publish, and let people read. Once they&amp;rsquo;re done, they won&amp;rsquo;t judge you for not updating often enough or having an outdated site, they&amp;rsquo;ll just hit next and read one of the other million posts Medium has to offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s how I see it. The dream of the internet is to be able to share yourself – your ideas, your art, your dreams – with like-minded peope everywhere. It connects us. But what we&amp;rsquo;ve learned is that not everyone needs a castle for their personal thoughts. A castle requires a ton of upkeep. Instead, a lot of us might just need a small house to store stuff in. If you&amp;rsquo;re writing tweets, Facebook posts, Medium entries, taking pictures with Instagram, and trying out a handful of other platforms, you probably don&amp;rsquo;t need a personal blog on a personal website to feel guilty about not keeping up with. All you need is a little &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2016/03/struggling-to-update-your-site.html#section-3&#34;&gt;one-pager&lt;/a&gt; that links to all the things you do so you can keep track of it all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing a new resume and need to find that link to that great post you wrote last year? With a good one-pager, it&amp;rsquo;ll be easy to find. Can&amp;rsquo;t remember what photo app that good picture of your dog is on? With a good one-pager, it&amp;rsquo;ll be easy to find. Want to direct a new friend, client, or employer to a place where they can see all the work you do without needing to sift through ten different web platforms? One-pager. Seriously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To sum this up (I like a good, clear takeaway), stop feeling guilty, as I always do, about spending your time writing on platforms that aren&amp;rsquo;t owned and designed by you. Getting your thoughts out there is more important than worrying about the authenticity of writing on a personal blog. If you want a blog, great! But if you just feel like writing every once in a while, publish it anywhere! Just, for the sake of not writing something you&amp;rsquo;ll forget about in a year, get a little website that links to your stuff wherever it&amp;rsquo;s posted.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 12:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2016/03/writing-on-the-web-is-changing.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2016/03/writing-on-the-web-is-changing.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>How to help us solve your domain and account questions faster</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you contact us about a question or problem you&amp;rsquo;re having, obviously you want it sorted out quickly. We want that, too. So here&amp;rsquo;s an outline of what we need to know to help you as quickly and painlessly as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of it will be pretty straightforward, but on the off chance you have an issue that can&amp;rsquo;t be fixed immediately, you&amp;rsquo;ll now have a better understanding of why that is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-1&#34;&gt;About you&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-2&#34;&gt;About your domain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-3&#34;&gt;About the problem&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-4&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;ll work, don&amp;rsquo;t worry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-1&#34;&gt;About you&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you contact support, the most fundamental thing we need to know is that you are, in fact, the real account holder (or, at least, someone like a web developer who the account holder has granted access).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The easiest way to do this is to log in to your account and then use &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/support&#34;&gt;our support form&lt;/a&gt; to contact us. When you do that, it verifies that you have access to the account and lets us know the login email address. For some things, we don&amp;rsquo;t need to authenticate you. Some questions we can just answer. But we can&amp;rsquo;t share account, payment, or domain ownership information without authentication (for both security and privacy reasons).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your problem is that you&amp;rsquo;re not able to log in though, sending us an authenticated request is nearly impossible. In these situations, we have to do an account holder authentication. We&amp;rsquo;ll need documentation that matches what we have on record to prove your identity, such as something with your name and contact details, or possibly your credit card holder name, card type, number, etc. for a billing issue, depending on the situation. (Once we&amp;rsquo;ve confirmed who you are, we don&amp;rsquo;t keep or use that documentation for anything else.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We take our customers&amp;rsquo; account security very seriously, and without sufficient proof, we&amp;rsquo;re not going to give anyone access to an account. We know that can be frustrating and take extra time, but remember, your personal and financial information and intellectual property are in your account. You &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; us to be sticklers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-2&#34;&gt;About your domain&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we&amp;rsquo;ve confirmed who you are, we now need to know which domain we need to look at (you&amp;rsquo;d be amazed how often people forget to mention that part).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To help us find the domain faster, there are a few things to be mindful of. Is the problem with the .COM or .CO version? Are you sure it&amp;rsquo;s registered with us? If it expired &amp;ldquo;a while ago&amp;rdquo;, was that a couple of months, or a couple of years? Also, if you have more than one account with us, mentioning that is helpful, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re not sure of a detail listed above, logging in to your account to check can help. Or you can do a &lt;a href=&#34;http://whois.domaintools.com/&#34;&gt;WHOIS lookup&lt;/a&gt; to see the domain&amp;rsquo;s registration information in many cases. (Don&amp;rsquo;t stress out too much though, if you forget a bit of information, we&amp;rsquo;re pretty good at figuring domain stuff out.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-3&#34;&gt;About the problem&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we know which domain we&amp;rsquo;re looking at, the goal is for you to be like a detective when you tell us about the problem. Obviously we don&amp;rsquo;t expect you to know everything (that&amp;rsquo;s our job), but try to give us all the information you can. Things like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My website was working this morning, and now it isn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Before it stopped working, I made X changes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Things stopped working right after setting up new DNS records or nameservers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had trouble paying for a renewal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more details we have, the faster we can hunt down and sort out the issue for you. As mentioned, it&amp;rsquo;s okay if you don&amp;rsquo;t know what&amp;rsquo;s wrong. We just need to know what you wanted (or didn&amp;rsquo;t want) to happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(&lt;a href=&#34;https://help.iwantmyname.com/&#34;&gt;We also have a comprehensive help centre to assist you as well.&lt;/a&gt; There&amp;rsquo;s a good chance your issue or question is covered there. And if your problem is new, we&amp;rsquo;ll probably use the experience to add more articles to explain it.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, though, there are limits to what we can fix. Here are some things we can&amp;rsquo;t do:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We can&amp;rsquo;t do anything with domains registered at other registrars&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We can&amp;rsquo;t edit DNS records when your hosting is with a different provider. (We don&amp;rsquo;t have access to that account even if your domain is registered with us.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We can&amp;rsquo;t make changes in your accounts on other platforms or services, like website or email.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In these situations, we can ask a few questions and maybe make a recommendation, but usually we&amp;rsquo;ll advise contacting their support for a more definitive answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-4&#34;&gt;It&#39;ll work, don&#39;t worry&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the time we can answer questions or fix things right away. Sure, it can take a little bit of time for settings to propagate, services to start working, or new sites to come online, but for the most part, things go pretty quick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Occasionally though, the problem is outside of our system, like an issue with a ccTLD registry where they need to update or fix something on their end. We do our best to communicate with them (and you) to resolve these issues as quickly as possible, but cases like that can take more time than we&amp;rsquo;d like – sometimes even a few days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as site update requests and feedback go, we read every message. After talking things over with the team, suggestions either get added to our update queue, get fixed or built right away (usually critical issues or easy things to accomplish), or just aren&amp;rsquo;t possible (yet&amp;hellip; we love hearing pie-in-the-sky ideas). We&amp;rsquo;re always listening though, and considering how we can make our service better for customers, so &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/support&#34;&gt;please don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to send us a message&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2016 13:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2016/03/how-to-help-us-solve-your-domain-and-account-questions-faster.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2016/03/how-to-help-us-solve-your-domain-and-account-questions-faster.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Struggling to update your site? Maybe it&#39;s time to do something different with your domain name</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s face it – most people who have their own website struggle to keep it up-to-date and post new content regularly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You probably started out with the best of intentions, even posted for months or years religiously, but now it seems like a chore to get anything up. Perhaps your site doesn’t reflect you any longer, or you&amp;rsquo;ve simply said everything you had to say about a topic. Or maybe you&amp;rsquo;ve moved on to a more social writing platform like Medium.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question now is, what should you do with your domain name? Having a dormant site isn&amp;rsquo;t doing you much good, but getting rid of a domain that has real brand equity is a total waste.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, unlike a username on a social platform, you can do lots of things with a domain name – it can go anywhere and become just about anything. Let&amp;rsquo;s explore some options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-1&#34;&gt;Use the domain for email only&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-2&#34;&gt;Forward your domain somewhere else&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-3&#34;&gt;Set up a basic one-page site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-4&#34;&gt;Try getting into writing again&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-5&#34;&gt;Change direction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-1&#34;&gt;Use the domain for email only&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a blog for years which I shut down recently because I wanted to focus more on personal connections in real life. It was such a huge relief to not feel guilty about not posting any longer. But instead of completely shutting the name down, it dawned on me that it&amp;rsquo;s perfectly okay to use my personal domain just for email. Nobody says there needs to be a website attached to it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using your own domain for email has some big advantages over the free offerings you can get from Gmail, iCloud, etc. The first of which is the perceived professionalism a custom domain provides. If you&amp;rsquo;re ever in a situation where you&amp;rsquo;re exchanging email addresses with a client (or potential client), having your own brand attached makes it seem like you&amp;rsquo;re taking yourself seriously. It takes five minutes for anyone to get a Gmail address – they&amp;rsquo;re completely generic – but a custom email address means you&amp;rsquo;ve put a bit of effort in (even if our &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/services/email-hosting/&#34;&gt;simplified email installations&lt;/a&gt; make it really easy).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using your own domain for email also gives you infinite portability. If you don’t like Gmail anymore, you can’t just switch to another service and keep your username@gmail.com address. However, with your own domain name you can exactly do that. Want to move from one email hosting provider to another while keeping the same address? Simply change the DNS settings of your domain and voilà.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-2&#34;&gt;Forward your domain somewhere else&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you maintain any active online profiles, &lt;a href=&#34;https://help.iwantmyname.com/customer/en/portal/articles/1418597-how-do-i-set-up-domain-forwarding-&#34;&gt;forwarding your domain&lt;/a&gt; to the one reflecting you most is an easy way to show people where they can find you and what you’re passionate about. And best of all, forwarding domains is free of charge with most domain registrars and hosting companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, designers could forward their domain to Dribbble and show off their latest work, or developers to GitHub for their latest contributions to Open Source projects. Twitter is also an obvious choice if you&amp;rsquo;re still into it. Any public web address works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the main advantages with redirecting your domain to another profile is the same as for email again: portability! Your interest in Twitter is fading away? Forward it to another location instead!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-3&#34;&gt;Set up a basic one-page site&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Struggling to update your own blog doesn’t necessarily mean you&amp;rsquo;ve stopped posting everywhere else. So why not have a single website pointing to your tweets, Instagram photos, and Facebook profile?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a one-pager from services like &lt;a href=&#34;https://about.me&#34;&gt;about.me&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://branded.me&#34;&gt;branded.me&lt;/a&gt;, you don’t have to do anything to update your website regularly. Just set it up once, write a short bio, and link to your other online profiles. Many platforms will even pull in your content from around the internet so parts of your website will update automatically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-4&#34;&gt;Try getting into writing again&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It sounds easier than it really is, but getting into a healthy writing habit is key when trying to get out of a writing funk. Start small with just a few minutes per day, e.g. by writing a few tweet-like short fictional status updates and expand from there. Don’t worry about publishing what you’ve written – all that matters is that you get back into the routine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve established the habit, start thinking of posting to your blog again. Just make sure you focus on the writing and not other details like layouts and &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/services/blog-hosting&#34;&gt;blog hosting platforms&lt;/a&gt;. Also, before you get yourself into another block, accept that it&amp;rsquo;s ok to post infrequently. There&amp;rsquo;s no rule saying you need to publish daily, or even twice a week. It’s fine only to publish something once a month or twice a year. Don’t put too much pressure on yourself and only work on your biggest ideas that have the most impact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-5&#34;&gt;Change direction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you just need a fresh start. Last year, when I was searching for options to post shorter status updates on my own domain instead of Twitter or Facebook, I came across the &lt;a href=&#34;https://withknown.com&#34;&gt;Known&lt;/a&gt; platform. Their software allows you to post Twitter-like status updates, long-form writing, images, and check-ins to your site first before sending them to connected services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Known helped me to think of my site as a place where I can post everything without the constraints of a blog. I didn’t feel like posting longer articles all the time, which was why my previous blog stagnated and ultimately died.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes all you want is share a quick thought, photo, or location with the world. Sure, there&amp;rsquo;s Tumblr, but it’s just another free service owned by a large internet company (in trouble). With Known, it felt the same as posting to Twitter and Facebook, but on my own domain. That’s a subtle but very important difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Known platform is just one example how you could change direction with your blog. Invest some time in exploring your options and how you could change your workflows, software, or the topics you cover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whichever of the options you choose or come up with your own, I see owning a domain name as a life-long investment. The services you use with it will change over time. You will evolve over time. However, if you pick the right domain, it can stay with you for a very, very long time and in different reincarnations. Don’t give up on it just yet.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 11:00:21 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2016/03/struggling-to-update-your-site.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2016/03/struggling-to-update-your-site.html</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
