<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>iwantmyname Domain Blog</title>
		<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/</link>
		<atom:link href="https://iwantmyname.com/blog/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>How to help us solve your domain and account questions faster</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you contact us about a question or problem you&amp;rsquo;re having, obviously you want it sorted out quickly. We want that, too. So here&amp;rsquo;s an outline of what we need to know to help you as quickly and painlessly as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of it will be pretty straightforward, but on the off chance you have an issue that can&amp;rsquo;t be fixed immediately, you&amp;rsquo;ll now have a better understanding of why that is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-1&#34;&gt;About you&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-2&#34;&gt;About your domain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-3&#34;&gt;About the problem&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-4&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;ll work, don&amp;rsquo;t worry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-1&#34;&gt;About you&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you contact support, the most fundamental thing we need to know is that you are, in fact, the real account holder (or, at least, someone like a web developer who the account holder has granted access).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The easiest way to do this is to log in to your account and then use &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/support&#34;&gt;our support form&lt;/a&gt; to contact us. When you do that, it verifies that you have access to the account and lets us know the login email address. For some things, we don&amp;rsquo;t need to authenticate you. Some questions we can just answer. But we can&amp;rsquo;t share account, payment, or domain ownership information without authentication (for both security and privacy reasons).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your problem is that you&amp;rsquo;re not able to log in though, sending us an authenticated request is nearly impossible. In these situations, we have to do an account holder authentication. We&amp;rsquo;ll need documentation that matches what we have on record to prove your identity, such as something with your name and contact details, or possibly your credit card holder name, card type, number, etc. for a billing issue, depending on the situation. (Once we&amp;rsquo;ve confirmed who you are, we don&amp;rsquo;t keep or use that documentation for anything else.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We take our customers&amp;rsquo; account security very seriously, and without sufficient proof, we&amp;rsquo;re not going to give anyone access to an account. We know that can be frustrating and take extra time, but remember, your personal and financial information and intellectual property are in your account. You &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; us to be sticklers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-2&#34;&gt;About your domain&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we&amp;rsquo;ve confirmed who you are, we now need to know which domain we need to look at (you&amp;rsquo;d be amazed how often people forget to mention that part).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To help us find the domain faster, there are a few things to be mindful of. Is the problem with the .COM or .CO version? Are you sure it&amp;rsquo;s registered with us? If it expired &amp;ldquo;a while ago&amp;rdquo;, was that a couple of months, or a couple of years? Also, if you have more than one account with us, mentioning that is helpful, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re not sure of a detail listed above, logging in to your account to check can help. Or you can do a &lt;a href=&#34;http://whois.domaintools.com/&#34;&gt;WHOIS lookup&lt;/a&gt; to see the domain&amp;rsquo;s registration information in many cases. (Don&amp;rsquo;t stress out too much though, if you forget a bit of information, we&amp;rsquo;re pretty good at figuring domain stuff out.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-3&#34;&gt;About the problem&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we know which domain we&amp;rsquo;re looking at, the goal is for you to be like a detective when you tell us about the problem. Obviously we don&amp;rsquo;t expect you to know everything (that&amp;rsquo;s our job), but try to give us all the information you can. Things like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My website was working this morning, and now it isn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Before it stopped working, I made X changes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Things stopped working right after setting up new DNS records or nameservers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had trouble paying for a renewal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more details we have, the faster we can hunt down and sort out the issue for you. As mentioned, it&amp;rsquo;s okay if you don&amp;rsquo;t know what&amp;rsquo;s wrong. We just need to know what you wanted (or didn&amp;rsquo;t want) to happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(&lt;a href=&#34;https://help.iwantmyname.com/&#34;&gt;We also have a comprehensive help centre to assist you as well.&lt;/a&gt; There&amp;rsquo;s a good chance your issue or question is covered there. And if your problem is new, we&amp;rsquo;ll probably use the experience to add more articles to explain it.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, though, there are limits to what we can fix. Here are some things we can&amp;rsquo;t do:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We can&amp;rsquo;t do anything with domains registered at other registrars&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We can&amp;rsquo;t edit DNS records when your hosting is with a different provider. (We don&amp;rsquo;t have access to that account even if your domain is registered with us.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We can&amp;rsquo;t make changes in your accounts on other platforms or services, like website or email.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In these situations, we can ask a few questions and maybe make a recommendation, but usually we&amp;rsquo;ll advise contacting their support for a more definitive answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-4&#34;&gt;It&#39;ll work, don&#39;t worry&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the time we can answer questions or fix things right away. Sure, it can take a little bit of time for settings to propagate, services to start working, or new sites to come online, but for the most part, things go pretty quick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Occasionally though, the problem is outside of our system, like an issue with a ccTLD registry where they need to update or fix something on their end. We do our best to communicate with them (and you) to resolve these issues as quickly as possible, but cases like that can take more time than we&amp;rsquo;d like – sometimes even a few days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as site update requests and feedback go, we read every message. After talking things over with the team, suggestions either get added to our update queue, get fixed or built right away (usually critical issues or easy things to accomplish), or just aren&amp;rsquo;t possible (yet&amp;hellip; we love hearing pie-in-the-sky ideas). We&amp;rsquo;re always listening though, and considering how we can make our service better for customers, so &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/support&#34;&gt;please don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to send us a message&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 15:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2016/03/how-to-help-us-solve-your-domain-and-account-questions-faster.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2016/03/how-to-help-us-solve-your-domain-and-account-questions-faster.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Struggling to update your site? Maybe it&#39;s time to do something different with your domain name</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s face it – most people who have their own website struggle to keep it up-to-date and post new content regularly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You probably started out with the best of intentions, even posted for months or years religiously, but now it seems like a chore to get anything up. Perhaps your site doesn’t reflect you any longer, or you&amp;rsquo;ve simply said everything you had to say about a topic. Or maybe you&amp;rsquo;ve moved on to a more social writing platform like Medium.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question now is, what should you do with your domain name? Having a dormant site isn&amp;rsquo;t doing you much good, but getting rid of a domain that has real brand equity is a total waste.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, unlike a username on a social platform, you can do lots of things with a domain name – it can go anywhere and become just about anything. Let&amp;rsquo;s explore some options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-1&#34;&gt;Use the domain for email only&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-2&#34;&gt;Forward your domain somewhere else&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-3&#34;&gt;Set up a basic one-page site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-4&#34;&gt;Try getting into writing again&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-5&#34;&gt;Change direction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-1&#34;&gt;Use the domain for email only&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a blog for years which I shut down recently because I wanted to focus more on personal connections in real life. It was such a huge relief to not feel guilty about not posting any longer. But instead of completely shutting the name down, it dawned on me that it&amp;rsquo;s perfectly okay to use my personal domain just for email. Nobody says there needs to be a website attached to it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using your own domain for email has some big advantages over the free offerings you can get from Gmail, iCloud, etc. The first of which is the perceived professionalism a custom domain provides. If you&amp;rsquo;re ever in a situation where you&amp;rsquo;re exchanging email addresses with a client (or potential client), having your own brand attached makes it seem like you&amp;rsquo;re taking yourself seriously. It takes five minutes for anyone to get a Gmail address – they&amp;rsquo;re completely generic – but a custom email address means you&amp;rsquo;ve put a bit of effort in (even if our &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/services/email-hosting/&#34;&gt;simplified email installations&lt;/a&gt; make it really easy).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using your own domain for email also gives you infinite portability. If you don’t like Gmail anymore, you can’t just switch to another service and keep your username@gmail.com address. However, with your own domain name you can exactly do that. Want to move from one email hosting provider to another while keeping the same address? Simply change the DNS settings of your domain and voilà.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-2&#34;&gt;Forward your domain somewhere else&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you maintain any active online profiles, &lt;a href=&#34;https://help.iwantmyname.com/customer/en/portal/articles/1418597-how-do-i-set-up-domain-forwarding-&#34;&gt;forwarding your domain&lt;/a&gt; to the one reflecting you most is an easy way to show people where they can find you and what you’re passionate about. And best of all, forwarding domains is free of charge with most domain registrars and hosting companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, designers could forward their domain to Dribbble and show off their latest work, or developers to GitHub for their latest contributions to Open Source projects. Twitter is also an obvious choice if you&amp;rsquo;re still into it. Any public web address works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the main advantages with redirecting your domain to another profile is the same as for email again: portability! Your interest in Twitter is fading away? Forward it to another location instead!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-3&#34;&gt;Set up a basic one-page site&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Struggling to update your own blog doesn’t necessarily mean you&amp;rsquo;ve stopped posting everywhere else. So why not have a single website pointing to your tweets, Instagram photos, and Facebook profile?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a one-pager from services like &lt;a href=&#34;https://about.me&#34;&gt;about.me&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://branded.me&#34;&gt;branded.me&lt;/a&gt;, you don’t have to do anything to update your website regularly. Just set it up once, write a short bio, and link to your other online profiles. Many platforms will even pull in your content from around the internet so parts of your website will update automatically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-4&#34;&gt;Try getting into writing again&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It sounds easier than it really is, but getting into a healthy writing habit is key when trying to get out of a writing funk. Start small with just a few minutes per day, e.g. by writing a few tweet-like short fictional status updates and expand from there. Don’t worry about publishing what you’ve written – all that matters is that you get back into the routine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve established the habit, start thinking of posting to your blog again. Just make sure you focus on the writing and not other details like layouts and &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/services/blog-hosting&#34;&gt;blog hosting platforms&lt;/a&gt;. Also, before you get yourself into another block, accept that it&amp;rsquo;s ok to post infrequently. There&amp;rsquo;s no rule saying you need to publish daily, or even twice a week. It’s fine only to publish something once a month or twice a year. Don’t put too much pressure on yourself and only work on your biggest ideas that have the most impact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-5&#34;&gt;Change direction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you just need a fresh start. Last year, when I was searching for options to post shorter status updates on my own domain instead of Twitter or Facebook, I came across the &lt;a href=&#34;https://withknown.com&#34;&gt;Known&lt;/a&gt; platform. Their software allows you to post Twitter-like status updates, long-form writing, images, and check-ins to your site first before sending them to connected services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Known helped me to think of my site as a place where I can post everything without the constraints of a blog. I didn’t feel like posting longer articles all the time, which was why my previous blog stagnated and ultimately died.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes all you want is share a quick thought, photo, or location with the world. Sure, there&amp;rsquo;s Tumblr, but it’s just another free service owned by a large internet company (in trouble). With Known, it felt the same as posting to Twitter and Facebook, but on my own domain. That’s a subtle but very important difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Known platform is just one example how you could change direction with your blog. Invest some time in exploring your options and how you could change your workflows, software, or the topics you cover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whichever of the options you choose or come up with your own, I see owning a domain name as a life-long investment. The services you use with it will change over time. You will evolve over time. However, if you pick the right domain, it can stay with you for a very, very long time and in different reincarnations. Don’t give up on it just yet.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 11:00:21 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2016/03/struggling-to-update-your-site.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2016/03/struggling-to-update-your-site.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Why domain prices can vary among registrars</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are several reasons why some registrars may be able to offer lower prices for domain registrations. Some ccTLDs and new gTLDs can be quite expensive because the registries can set their own pricing. So we understand that your budget can be a concern.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Loss leader pricing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When domain prices are set very low, especially significantly lower than many other registrars, that&amp;rsquo;s typically what&amp;rsquo;s known as a &amp;ldquo;loss leader&amp;rdquo;. The price the customer pays to register the domain is often less than the price the registrar pays the registry for it. They aren&amp;rsquo;t making money on that registration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a sales tactic to encourage registration of lots of domains of that type. However, the registration price is very rarely the permanent price for the domain. It&amp;rsquo;s also sometimes because some registrars make their money selling a WHOIS privacy service or other value-adds. (Our WHOIS privacy service is free.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information on upselling and our thoughts about it, have a look at this article: &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2013/11/no-upselling-tactics-to-be-found-here.html&#34;&gt;No Upselling Tactics To Be Found Here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We recommend checking before registering a domain what the annual renewal price will be. It is typically much higher than the registration price. Registrars are well within their rights to change the price this way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Volume pricing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another reason is volume. There are a few very large registrars that can negotiate volume discounts with registries because they manage millions of domains. This generates big profits for registries. So the big registrars can negotiate lower base pricing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the big registrars also have special marketing agreements with the new domain registries. That means they get cash back from the source registry for promoting a specific domain type.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In these cases, the pricing may remain fairly low, but you&amp;rsquo;re also getting the experience of doing business with big companies, which can sometimes be a bit bureaucratic or impersonal&amp;hellip; and put their focus more on sales and marketing than helping customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Other sources of revenue (like customers&amp;hellip;)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is also the common adage that if you&amp;rsquo;re not paying for something, then &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; are the product. Companies need to make money to survive. If they&amp;rsquo;re not making much money selling domains (or are even losing money doing that), they need to make up profits elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some do that by using your data or selling your customer information. They get paid by their partners for this vetted information, and it&amp;rsquo;s basically a condition of your customer agreement with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Building a sustainable business&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started iwantmyname with really clear and strong ideas of what kind of company we wanted to build. And a lot of that had to do with ways we &lt;em&gt;didn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; want to run our businesses. (Even if the practices were common in the industry.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We list our beliefs and policy information &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/about&#34;&gt;on our About page&lt;/a&gt;, and we stand by it. We believe it&amp;rsquo;s the best way to build a sustainable company that customers &lt;em&gt;like&lt;/em&gt; to do business with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We don&amp;rsquo;t believe you can measure yourself or company successful if it results in &amp;ldquo;human roadkill&amp;rdquo; on that road to success. You&amp;rsquo;re in business because your customers are willing to do business with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarily, your business&amp;rsquo; existence and growth relies on your team. We&amp;rsquo;ve grown slowly and carefully, and have a lot of experience and deep knowledge of our industry. We believe that&amp;rsquo;s the best way to serve our customers. We haven&amp;rsquo;t outsourced support to places where we can amass lots of cheap–but low-skilled–labour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Be informed&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We always recommend doing your research. If domains seem &amp;ldquo;too good to be true&amp;rdquo; cheap, they very well might be. And if domains are a bit more expensive sometimes, see what that means in terms of the renewal pricing, &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/about&#34;&gt;the company you&amp;rsquo;re doing business with&lt;/a&gt;, their policies, and other things that may be important to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can&amp;rsquo;t and don&amp;rsquo;t do price matching. We do show current discounts on our &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/domain-name-registration-list-of-extensions&#34;&gt;domains pricing page&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/domain-transfer&#34;&gt;our transfers page&lt;/a&gt;, and on our &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/special-offer&#34;&gt;monthly discounts page&lt;/a&gt;. And we do our best to pass discounts and price reductions along to you whenever we can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about pricing or related issues, &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/support&#34;&gt;just let us know&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2016 16:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2016/02/why-domain-prices-can-vary-among-registrars.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2016/02/why-domain-prices-can-vary-among-registrars.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>We&#39;ve got your back with DNSSEC</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;At iwantmyname, we consider making it easy for you to control and own your online identity as one of our core principles. Hell, it&amp;rsquo;s in the branding. But what happens after that? Are we sure every time someone tries to connect to your identity, they&amp;rsquo;re actually connecting with you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can do that now with DNSSEC and DS records.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The easiest way to set this up is if your Nameserver provider supports DNSSEC (like Cloudflare, pictured below). Just enable it there, then grab your DS record to use with your domain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/media/2016-02-01-dnssec.png&#34; alt=&#34;Cloudflare interface&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On our site, copy the relevant bits, which is everything &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;domain&gt; 3600 IN DS&lt;/strong&gt;, of the DS record to the DS record page in your domain admin (you can find that at &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/dashboard/domains/dnssec/&#34;&gt;https://iwantmyname.com/dashboard/domains/dnssec/&lt;/a&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;strong&gt;domain name in question&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/media/2016-02-01-iwantmyname-dnssec.png&#34; alt=&#34;iwantmyname interface&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you&amp;rsquo;re done, &lt;em&gt;the internet&lt;/em&gt; will start double checking that the server people are connecting to is actually yours. Thus making sure that you and your name are synonymous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re interested, an in-depth explanation of what DNSSEC is (and why you might want it) can be found on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.cloudflare.com/dnssec-an-introduction/&#34;&gt;CloudFlare blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 09:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2016/02/we-have-your-back-with-dnssec.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2016/02/we-have-your-back-with-dnssec.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Now hiring: Customer support scholar</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Hi everyone -- We&amp;rsquo;ve had an amazing and overwhelming response. Over 300 applicants! So we&amp;rsquo;re booking interviews at this point and are no longer accepting further applications. Thanks so much for all your interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s break this down. We&amp;rsquo;re looking for a very patient person to help our global audience do great things with domains. You&amp;rsquo;ll help them register domains, you&amp;rsquo;ll help them with billing issues, you&amp;rsquo;ll help them use their domains, and you might even help them with an idea or two. Whatever they need, you&amp;rsquo;ll be there to help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;scholar&amp;rdquo; bit wasn&amp;rsquo;t just for fun though. To be great at this job, you have to want to learn. About domain names, our processes, our systems, and how people use them. The learning never stops, and the right person will love soaking it up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike many of our job openings, this job is for people in and around our timezone (we&amp;rsquo;re in Wellington, NZ). We could possibly make an exception for the right person elsewhere, but you must be available during New Zealand, Australian, or Asian business hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the list of the skills we&amp;rsquo;re looking for:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You absolutely have to have plus plus English language writing skills. You’ll be writing a lot, and English is our business communication language. (If you happen to speak/write another language, it would certainly be a bonus.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You must like people (like, actually like them). No matter how frustrated the customer, you need to be able to clearly and completely solve problems without becoming (noticeably) impatient.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Curiosity. You don’t have to be the world’s foremost domains expert to work here, but a little curiosity will go a long way in solving problems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That said, some knowledge of domains, DNS, and the internet would be advantageous. We&amp;rsquo;ll be teaching you a ton, but we&amp;rsquo;d rather not start with &amp;ldquo;this is what a Nameserver is.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is key - you need to be able to work without supervision. There will almost always be a someone to help you through problems (especially in the beginning), but for the most part, you need to be able to solve problems on your own.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you think this is the job for you, send a witty email with a quick rundown of relevant work history to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:jobs@ideegeo.com&#34;&gt;jobs@ideegeo.com&lt;/a&gt;. (Please don&amp;rsquo;t send any multi-page resumes&amp;hellip; brevity is a skill we admire.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2016 13:54:40 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2016/01/now-hiring-customer-support-scholar.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2016/01/now-hiring-customer-support-scholar.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Giving back in 2016</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;At a time when we seem to be confronted by images of human suffering on a daily basis, as bystanders, we can easily feel overwhelmed. With war, hunger, and climate change impacting millions globally - how can we possibly help?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At iwantmyname, we have a long-established policy of setting aside a small portion of revenue from each domain registration towards our charitable fund. About this time each year we have a discussion among the team about where we&amp;rsquo;d like to focus our efforts the following year. Our budget for 2016 will be around $10,000, so it&amp;rsquo;s important that we choose wisely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A particular theme this year has been the outpouring of refugees from North Africa. We&amp;rsquo;ve all seen the shocking media stories highlighting tragedies involving young children. So we&amp;rsquo;ve decided to donate to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.savethechildren.net/&#34;&gt;Save The Children&lt;/a&gt;, who do a fantastic job &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theguardian.com/world/ng-interactive/2015/dec/04/zaataris-children-life-in-a-refugee-camp-my-own-account-in-pictures&#34;&gt;supporting children at risk globally&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have also decided to provide some follow-up funding for a specific project that is dear to our hearts. In 2015 we visited beautiful Bali on our company retreat, held at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hubud.org/&#34;&gt;Hubud&lt;/a&gt; an emerging startup and co-working space on the island. There we learned of IDEP, which provides education and technical aid across Indonesia in support of ecological projects. Water is central to Balinese life and religion, but Bali faces a water crisis right now, so we will contribute additional funding to &lt;a href=&#34;http://idepfoundation.org/bwp&#34;&gt;IDEP&amp;rsquo;s water project&lt;/a&gt; on the island. (On a related note, we were also thrilled to support &lt;a href=&#34;http://e27.co/mental-health-app-design-day-wins-startup-weekend-bali-20151123/&#34;&gt;Bali Startup Weekend&lt;/a&gt; this year.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, we anticipate another active season for tropical storms in the Pacific Ocean, so we are setting aside some funds for emergency use, as and when the need arises. Last year we donated to cyclone relief in both Philippines and Vanuatu, and with a strong El Nino weather pattern in play, it seems likely that there will be more storms to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With your help, as our company grows, we will continue to expand our commitment to help others in need. We also challenge other companies to follow suit. Thank you for your support in 2015 and wishing you a safe and festive holiday season from all the team.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2015 12:00:11 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/12/giving-back.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/12/giving-back.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Who owns your domain name?</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;only register domains for yourself&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;create and use accounts that only you should be able to access&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;register domains only as an individual and not tied to any company or organization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t have any business partners, someone building your website, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;never die&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;congratulations! You &lt;em&gt;probably&lt;/em&gt; won&amp;rsquo;t end up in a sticky situation regarding who owns your domains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people never give a second thought to domain ownership after registration. It&amp;rsquo;s one of those things that might cross your mind or prompt you to log in once a year, but as we see on a fairly regular basis, things can become difficult, or downright contentious, pretty quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-1&#34;&gt;Who owns your domain name?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-2&#34;&gt;If a domain is registered by an ex-employee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-3&#34;&gt;If a domain is registered for a partner-run business/organization&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-4&#34;&gt;If a domain is registered by someone who is building a website for you&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-5&#34;&gt;If a domain is registered by someone who dies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-6&#34;&gt;If a domain is registered to be sold for profit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-7&#34;&gt;The bottom line&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-1&#34;&gt;Who owns your domain name?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s cover the basics first. The legal owner of a domain name is the person and/or organization listed as the domain&amp;rsquo;s registrant or owner contact. Domains typically have four contacts: registrant/owner, admin, technical, and billing. These can be the same person or different people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For most types of domain names, you can check the contacts listed &lt;a href=&#34;http://whois.domaintools.com/&#34;&gt;using a WHOIS lookup&lt;/a&gt; (note that for some ccTLDs, the registry does not display this information, and it won&amp;rsquo;t be displayed if you have a WHOIS privacy service in place, &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/whois-privacy&#34;&gt;if applicable&lt;/a&gt;, so you would need to login to your iwantmyname account to see the contact details) This means that if &lt;strong&gt;you&lt;/strong&gt; are the registrant contact for a domain, then &lt;strong&gt;you&lt;/strong&gt; are the legal owner of the domain. These people are not:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The person or people whose names are the admin, technical, or billing contacts for the domain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The person who &lt;em&gt;used&lt;/em&gt; to be listed as the registrant/owner (but it&amp;rsquo;s since been changed to your name).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The registrar with which you register the domain name unless they put their own details for the registrant contact, which is bad business practice and not allowed under many domain extensions, but still happens&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The web hosting provider you use to host your website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The person who paid for the domain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The person you hired to build and/or manage your website for you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A person who owns or has access to the account in which the domain resides.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The company or organization you work for, if not also listed in the registrant contact information (though this can be tricky).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A company or organization with the same name as the domain, if it&amp;rsquo;s not registered to them. (However, if they have a trademark or other rights to the name, they can come after you and potentially take it.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your business partner or another person who is or was running a company, club, or other organization with you if their name isn&amp;rsquo;t listed as the registrant contact.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A brokerage service used when buying/transferring the domain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-2&#34;&gt;If a domain is registered by an ex-employee&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most common issue we see is when employees register domains for an organization, then later leave. The domain often ends up marooned in an account no one has access to, and if the account login email no longer exists, no one can receive the account password reset emails, and no one will be alerted to any issues with domain renewal until the website or email stops working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here&amp;rsquo;s the worst-case scenario: if the employee who registered the domain does so completely in their name (where the organization isn&amp;rsquo;t listed on the account contact details, payment details, or domain registration details), there is absolutely no proof (aside from, &lt;em&gt;perhaps&lt;/em&gt; the domain name itself) that the organization has any right to the it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These situations are tricky, and we require &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt; of authentication and proof before we will allow anyone access to the domain. More likely, though, we tell these people to seek legal advice and/or work it out amongst themselves, or use the UDRP process (see below) because we are not in the position to decide who has the right to a domain name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if someone in your organization has been tasked with registering a domain name for the company, or a department, or a specific project, or whatever:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ensure that the organization&amp;rsquo;s name and contact information are on the account &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; on the domain registrant contacts, especially the registrant/owner one.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ensure that the email address to access the account is one accessible by more than one person, e.g. it_admin@mycompany.com, rather than jsmith@mycompany.com.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;make a list of organizational assets that includes domain names and their access details.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, if that employee leaves, you won&amp;rsquo;t get a rude awakening that there&amp;rsquo;s a problem when the website goes down and email stops working&amp;hellip; because the domain renewal couldn&amp;rsquo;t be billed to a deactivated credit card and expired months ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-3&#34;&gt;If a domain is registered for a partner-run business/organization&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you start a business, club, or organization with other people, similar principles apply. Things happen, businesses (sometimes) fail, and relationships can go south rather quickly. It&amp;rsquo;s like a divorce, but with your business at stake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If things get ugly and legal, assets can get frozen. And if we get conflicting information about an account or domain, we may be forced to block it until the issue is sorted out. That means no one can access the account or domain -- to take a website down or put it back up, to pay for a renewal, or any other function.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes we even find that people forget about domains once businesses fail, and their partners never receive expiry notifications because they were never on the account. There are all kinds of legal considerations, especially if a business is successful. So please, ensure that the domain and related accounts are not just in one person&amp;rsquo;s name with singular access. Ensure that the account shows proof of more than one principle, or is focused on the organization, rather than one founder&amp;rsquo;s name, payment, and contact details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(And for some additional reading, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.domaininvesting.com/buying-domain-names-with-a-partner/&#34;&gt;here&amp;rsquo;s is a good article with some things to think about regarding buying domains with partners.&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-4&#34;&gt;If a domain is registered by someone who is building a website for you&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having your own website is an important step in building a brand, business, or other online identity, but many people don&amp;rsquo;t have the skills or the time to build one. If you hire someone for the task, it&amp;rsquo;s important to ensure that they&amp;rsquo;re just responsible for the work and that they don&amp;rsquo;t actually own it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(For web designers/developers with a roster of clients, we recommend creating a separate account for each client. It can be a bit of extra work initially, but it&amp;rsquo;s valuable in the long run because it enables setting up the account in the client&amp;rsquo;s name with their billing and contact information. That way the client has access to the account to update contact or credit card details, transfer the domain, cancel renewal, etc., without having to rely on anyone else. And if the client parts ways, you won&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about scrubbing your credit card information from the account or forwarding billing renewal emails because it&amp;rsquo;ll already be under client control.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most important thing to remember is that domains are typically registered using account contact details, and if that&amp;rsquo;s someone else&amp;rsquo;s information, they are the legal owner of your domain. If you have someone building your website, make sure the account contact details are your own. They can be the technical contact for the domain, but it&amp;rsquo;s important that the registrant/owner is you or your company. If your designer/developer just disappears one day (it happens!), having primary account access and proof of ownership is so important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also recommend using an email address for account login, contact/notification, and domain registrant contacts that does NOT use your domain name. If you use info@mydomain.com, but mydomain.com accidentally expires, not only will your website go down, you won&amp;rsquo;t be able to receive emails at any addresses associated with that domain. A backup email address using another domain, mail server, or free account like Gmail can save you a lot of headaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We should also note that the reverse of this, or a combination of scenarios, have happened (i.e. we hear from a new technical contact who has been tasked with getting a website/email back up, or refreshing the site, etc., and they have pretty much zero idea how to access it. Don&amp;rsquo;t do this to the nice people. You&amp;rsquo;re paying them good money. Pay them to build you a great website; don&amp;rsquo;t end up paying them to waste time on a snipe hunt of administrivia and headaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-5&#34;&gt;If a domain is registered by someone who dies&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another situation is when people die. It&amp;rsquo;s going to happen to all of us, so there&amp;rsquo;s no excuse not to be prepared. Digital legacies are becoming an increasingly important estate consideration, especially in this day and age of social media, cloud storage, etc. (&lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/10/death-and-digital-properties.html&#34;&gt;We have a whole article on death and digital legacy&lt;/a&gt; if you&amp;rsquo;re interested. In short, you want to have a list of your online properties, login details, and what&amp;rsquo;s to be done with them if you die.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In many cases of death, the credit card on file will be canceled, the domain will expire, and the website will go offline. Done. In other cases, we&amp;rsquo;ll be contacted by people trying to close accounts, but who have no access. If they can access the deceased&amp;rsquo;s email account, they can send a password reset and log in to close things down, but otherwise authentication can be difficult and upsetting. And if the domain is for a site or enterprise run by more than one person, if one of them dies, you end up in a partner ownership situation, as outlined above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These situations are unfortunate and awkward for us, and we sympathize greatly with people trying to sort things out. But at the same time we can&amp;rsquo;t abandon our security procedures for any situation. Fussing over password resets or providing identity documentation or other administrivia when you&amp;rsquo;re dealing with grief is the &lt;em&gt;last&lt;/em&gt; thing anyone wants to deal with. Be kind to those who will survive you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-6&#34;&gt;If a domain is registered to be sold for profit&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people register domain names speculatively, and often go after domains that include the names of big companies, popular products, media enterprises, you name it. Or maybe you&amp;rsquo;re just a big fan and want to set up a fan site that the big media company that owns the popular product, franchise, etc. will want to pay you money for (there&amp;rsquo;s been some kerfuffle related to this regarding Star Wars in the past, for example).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Making money this way is possible, but you&amp;rsquo;re just as likely to get a legal notice. And if they own the trademark, which they very likely might, they have a much stronger case and can demand you hand over the domain for zero dollars. (&lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/05/the-guide-to-getting-the-right-domain-name-for-your-brand.html&#34;&gt;We have an extensive guide to options when someone else has a domain name you want.&lt;/a&gt; It provides reverse information as well, i.e. what likely options are if you have a domain you hope someone &lt;em&gt;else&lt;/em&gt; will want to procure.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes though, what looks like &amp;ldquo;domain squatting&amp;rdquo; can actually be a case of someone having a domain long before a company or product is created and wants its corresponding domain. In these cases, the new company may offer to buy the domain off of you, or they may lodge a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.icann.org/resources/pages/help/dndr/udrp-en&#34;&gt;UDRP complaint&lt;/a&gt; (Uniform Domain-Name Dispute-Resolution Policy), which basically claims that you own a domain you don&amp;rsquo;t really have rights to and aren&amp;rsquo;t using the best way, and the other company has a trademark or business case that is better suited to the domain&amp;rsquo;s ownership and use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time domain squatting and speculation were more common and easier to get away with, but those days are long past. Registering what you think is a hot domain in hopes of a big payday is not the likely windfall some people still think it is. You&amp;rsquo;re more likely to be threatened with legal action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-7&#34;&gt;The bottom line&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digital assets and property are something we need to get used to in this increasingly technical world. Items like domain names are often very closely tied to our identities, interests, families, income, and other parts of life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need to think of them as being as important as the physical items in our homes, or our financial assets, and plan to get organized accordingly. It&amp;rsquo;s really just a matter of being aware upon setup, and occasionally ensuring that things are up to date (perhaps an annual digital checkup around the New Year would work). Future you, and your descendants, will thank you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2015 13:52:11 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/12/who-owns-your-domain.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/12/who-owns-your-domain.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>A new way to use Bitcoin wherever Visa is accepted</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.coinbase.com/2015/11/20/introducing-the-shift-card/&#34;&gt;Coinbase on its new Shift Card:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, we’re excited to introduce the first US-issued bitcoin debit card, the Shift Card. The Shift Card is a VISA debit card that currently allows Coinbase users in twenty-four states in the U.S. to spend bitcoin online and offline at over 38 million merchants worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Merchant adoption has come a long way over the past few years, but it’s still difficult for people to make regular purchases with bitcoin. Buying gas at a local gas station or groceries at a neighborhood grocery store with bitcoin has not been possible in most cities in the U.S. Thanks to Shift Payments, it’s now possible to use bitcoin to buy gas, groceries, and much more. With the Shift Card, you can now spend bitcoin anywhere in the world that VISA is accepted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re a Coinbase user who lives in AL, AZ, CA, DE, DC, GA, ID, IA, KS, ME, MS, NE, NV, NJ, NC, ND, OK, PA, PR, SD, TX, VT, WA, or WV, I guess we&amp;rsquo;re sort of accepting Bitcoin now. Mazel tov!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2015 09:50:00 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/11/a-new-way-to-use-bitcoin-wherever-visa-is-accepted.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/11/a-new-way-to-use-bitcoin-wherever-visa-is-accepted.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>I plan to live a long time</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://well.blogs.nytimes.com/2015/11/18/coffee-tied-to-lower-risk-of-dying/?utm_source=nextdraft&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;_r=1&amp;amp;mtrref=undefined&amp;amp;gwh=6DBBED93DDD1953EA990CB3942CDFC43&amp;amp;gwt=pay&#34;&gt;Nicholas Bakalar on coffee reducing my risk of death by 6-15%:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compared with abstainers, nonsmokers who drank a cup of coffee a day had a 6 percent reduced risk of death, one to three cups an 8 percent reduced risk, three to five cups a 15 percent reduced risk, and more than five cups a 12 percent reduced risk. There was little difference whether they drank caffeinated or decaffeinated coffee. The association persisted after controlling for age, alcohol consumption, B.M.I. and other health and diet factors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coffee drinking was linked to a reduced risk of death from heart disease, stroke, diabetes, neurological diseases and suicide, although not from cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Life tip of the day.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2015 11:50:00 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/11/i-plan-to-live-a-long-time.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/11/i-plan-to-live-a-long-time.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Users are more than just a weak point of security</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://joelcalifa.com/blog/patronizing-passwords/&#34;&gt;Joel Califa of Digital Ocean on developing better password systems:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re a developer, focus your efforts on securing your backend. Hash and salt passwords, keep your database secure, implement throttling, check for changes in geolocation, offer a variety of mechanisms for enabling two-factor on your app, make sure your password recovery system is solid. Leave the password decision up to your users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have to remember that at the end of the day, users are more than just a weak point of security in our systems. Our services exist for our users, not despite them. I like to think there are ways to get people to use strong passwords without forcing their hands and negatively affecting their experience using our products. Let’s explore some of these ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;File this under: Top priorities of 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2015 13:50:00 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/11/users-are-more-than-just-a-weak-point-of-security.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/11/users-are-more-than-just-a-weak-point-of-security.html</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
