<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>iwantmyname Domain Blog</title>
		<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog</link>
		<atom:link href="https://iwantmyname.com/blog/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Things to know about domains before buying your first domain name</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s never more apparent how puzzling domain names are to people than when I get asked about my job. “A domain registrar? What the heck is that?” I get it all the time, but what surprises me most is that many of these same people already own domains in some form or another—usually brokered through legacy web-design firms charging $20-30/mo for Flash websites with glitzy visitor counters (seriously, if you&amp;#39;re paying $30/mo for a site built a decade ago, you&amp;#39;re getting ripped off).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So my goal of goals is to set them on the right path, usually with an abridged version of this very post—my spiel on domain names, what you’re buying, what the deal is with all the new domain extensions, what email has to do with it all, and a bit about Whois privacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#section-1&quot;&gt;Domain name? Domain registrar?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#section-2&quot;&gt;Domain extensions, or top-level domains (TLDs)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#section-3&quot;&gt;The new gTLDs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#section-4&quot;&gt;What to do with your domain name?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#section-5&quot;&gt;A final word about privacy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#section-6&quot;&gt;And please, don’t be shy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;section-1&quot;&gt;1. Domain name? Domain registrar?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just to get in the right frame of mind, let&amp;#39;s think of the internet at an entirely new planet Earth. Then, think of the domain extensions (like .com, ,net, .edu) as countries, and the individual domain names (like iwantmyname.com or yourname.com) as pieces of property within those countries. Then, as your domain registrar, iwantmyname is like a big real estate agency, able to sell you a piece of property in a ton of countries on the planet. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To recap:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The internet is a huge planet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Domain extensions are countries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Individual domain names are property&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Domain registrars are your real estate agents&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As the writer of this, I’m your content guide to internet real estate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;section-2&quot;&gt;2. Domain extensions, or top-level domains (TLDs)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the beginnings of the public internet, the web was filled with a fairly limited number of domain extensions (also called top-level domains (or TLDs)). In the US, most websites ended in .com, .net, .org, .edu, or .gov, and around the world, many sites adopted their country code top-level domains (or ccTLDs)—like .co.uk in the UK and .co.nz in New Zealand. No matter where you were though, .com was the clear popularity leader, and that popularity advantage still exists today. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But remember, .com is like a country, and like any country, there’s limited desirable space. And limited desirable space always leads to overcrowding. The problem is twofold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With more and more people getting on the internet, we’re starting to run out of short, memorable domain names. And by run out, I mean that by 2014, every two, three, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2013/12/four-letter-coms-are-a-four-letter-wordgone.html&quot;&gt;four letter .com domain had already been registered&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It’s not like all these domains are being used though. Basic rules of supply and demand brought countless opportunistic businessmen who bought up these domains and started selling them on the domain aftermarket for premium prices (some even went in the million-dollar range!).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of people blame these so-called cybersquatters for the lack of good .com names available, but it’s hard to blame them for wanting to be part of the action (do you blame real-estate speculators for the lack of cheap property in your area?). Just remember that this supply/demand issue is based on the fact that the only desirable TLD is .com, which was borderline true in years past. If the amount of good options multiply through...what then?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;section-3&quot;&gt;3. The new gTLDs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll spare you the details and backstory, but in 2014, &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/new-gtld-domain-extensions&quot;&gt;hundreds upon hundreds of new domain extensions&lt;/a&gt; were created (often called the new generic TLDs (gTLDs), or new TLDs (nTLDs)), making that lack of quality domain names a thing of the past. Now, if I want to use my name in a domain, I can get Chris.ninja, Chris.club, Chris.cool, Chris.enterprises, Chris.vodka, etc., etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I hinted at already, the problem we’re running into now isn’t a supply issue, it’s a human nature issue—people are afraid of the unknown. Sticking with the property analogy, if you open a shiny new store in a brand new place, will people find it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all depends on how you’re being discovered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If social media is your biggest traffic driver, your links will work fine no matter what your TLD is. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Depending on who you ask, there might actually be a small search engine optimization (SEO) advantage to using a new gTLD (but maybe none at all). As long as your brand is good and your copy isn’t spammy, your search engine results should be fine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The only potential harm is if people think your domain looks like a scam because of your TLD. There&amp;#39;s a fairly small (in the scheme of things) history of spam websites buying up domain names similar to real brand names on various TLDs, but as long as your brand doesn&amp;#39;t include fake looking strings of numbers, random characters (usually lots of dashes), or fishy misspellings, you should be fine. As more and more big/legitimate websites adopt these new domain extensions, that stigma should go away.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a ton of articles online that have research “proving” either side of the discoverability debate (whether the new gTLDs are good or bad for business), but my stance is that there are too many people with too much money invested into these new gTLDs for them to completely fail. Maybe none of them will reach the popularity of .com, but people’s attitude towards domains that don’t end in .com is definitely starting to shift. My best advice would be to worry about the name of your brand first, then find an applicable TLD to fit it. There are &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/domain-name-registration-list-of-extensions&quot;&gt;hundreds to choose from&lt;/a&gt; now, so there&amp;#39;s no reason to be bound to the crowded land of .com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;section-4&quot;&gt;4. What to do with your domain name&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we’ve established that domain names are property—what kinds of things can you build on it? Let’s run through a couple options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Build a website&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most common thing to do with a domain name is to build a website. And unless you’re deft at writing code (if so, you probably don’t need to be reading this), the best course of action is to use one of the many platforms available to build your site with ease (many have templates or some form of drag-and-drop tools available, making web design easy enough for everyone).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here’s the gist. On one end, you have your domain name, and on the other, you have a website built on a platform like Squarespace. To get your Squarespace site to pair with your domain, you have to add the correct DNS records to your domain name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here at iwantmyname, we make that part easy. Once you buy your domain, you can set it up to work with many of the web’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/services/ecommerce-hosting/&quot;&gt;most popular platforms&lt;/a&gt; with just a few clicks. So instead of worrying about editing DNS records, you can get started with a platform like Squarespace, Shopify, Tumblr, or Ghost in a snap. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seriously... it’s almost automatic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;A quick word about www.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every once in a while we get asked how much it costs to add the www. to a website. It’s totally free—the www. is just a subdomain that isn’t necessary, but still common because people got used to saying it in the 90’s. Our &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/services/email-hosting/&quot;&gt;platform setups&lt;/a&gt; add the www. option automatically, so there’s no need to worry about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Get an email address&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things we get asked most is how to get a custom email address. So first, let’s be clear about how your domain name fits into your email. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you look at an email address, it usually looks something like this—chris@yourname.com. To create this, the owner of yourname.com had to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get the yourname.com domain name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select and sign up for an &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/services/email-hosting/&quot;&gt;email hosting service&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Point the domain name to that email hosting service&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add individual email addresses (like chris@yourname.com) through the email hosting service admin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like anything on the web, there are a lot of different companies out there that do email hosting—Google, Fastmail, Zoho, etc. All of them will be able to get your mail from point A to point B, but they all offer slightly different features at different price points. My suggestion would be to head to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/services/email-hosting/&quot;&gt;email plugin page&lt;/a&gt;, then look at each platform’s website to see which features you’d be happiest with. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Sometimes you just need to wait for inspiration&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some people, getting a domain means there&amp;#39;s an immediate plan. For others, it’s important to wait for inspiration to strike. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This happens to me all the time. I’ll be driving home from lunch, thinking about how to best tell people about my awesome dining experience, then decide to create a restaurant review website. After an hour or so of quick naming exercises, I’ll grab a domain to kickstart the writing process (kind of like buying a guitar to guilt yourself into learning how to play). But sometimes, if I lose interest too fast, I’ll sit on the domain for a month or two while the ideas percolate—once you register a domain, it’s yours for a year, so there’s no big rush. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just remember that if you don’t decide to use the domain, be sure to turn renewals off so you won’t keep paying for it year after year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;section-5&quot;&gt;5. A final word about privacy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Online privacy has been all over the news lately (for good reason), and one of the easier things you can do to hide some of your information is to enable Whois privacy (it’s free) on your domain. &lt;a href=&quot;https://help.iwantmyname.com/customer/portal/articles/184425-do-you-offer-a-whois-privacy-service-&quot;&gt;Here’s a good guide&lt;/a&gt; to how Whois privacy works and how to enable it, but please note that only the domain extensions listed in that article support it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;section-6&quot;&gt;6. And please, don’t be shy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the uninitiated, the internet can be a big, scary place. If you ever run into any issues with your domain, or just can’t figure out how to link it to the platform you want, &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/support&quot;&gt;send us a message&lt;/a&gt; and we’ll be sure to help out. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2015 11:12:32 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/01/things-to-know-about-domains-before-buying-your-first-domain-name.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/01/things-to-know-about-domains-before-buying-your-first-domain-name.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>SEO penalties of moving our blog to a subdomain</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me start this article by confessing that we’re not SEO gurus at iwantmyname. Everything we&amp;#39;ve done in the last few years in terms of SEO was done with a basic understanding of the topic and by providing a good product with relevant content and landing pages. This always served us well and we were happy with our rankings overall. With that out of the way, I’d like to tell you about our experience with switching our blog to a subdomain. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the very beginning of July last year, we moved our blog from a subdirectory URL (&lt;code&gt;iwantmyname.com/blog&lt;/code&gt;) to a subdomain (&lt;code&gt;blog.iwantmyname.com&lt;/code&gt;) for better maintainability and performance with GitHub Pages&amp;#39; &lt;abbr title=&quot;content delivery network&quot;&gt;CDN&lt;/abbr&gt; and future-proofing in case we wanted to switch to a different platform down the road. We made this decision after doing lots of research and had long discussions about how it might impact our search engine rankings, but we ultimately agreed to make the change. After all, it was 2014 and Google should be clever enough that it wouldn’t make any difference because they know the blog (subdomain or not) is part of iwantmyname, right? As Matt Cutts said &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_MswMYk05tk&quot;&gt;in one of his webmaster videos&lt;/a&gt; “it’s a question which one is easier for you and whichever one makes you happier I would go and do it that way”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we expected an initial hit after making the subdomain switch and traffic slowly recovering, the turnaround didn’t happen after 6 months, as you can see in the following example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/assets/images/content/2015-01-16-blog-traffic-subdomain-switch.png&quot; alt=&quot;Blog traffic after switch to subdomain&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From what we can tell, we did everything by the books with &lt;code&gt;301&lt;/code&gt; redirects for all URLs - so what happened? Could it have been just coincidence that Google updated their algorithm and we got penalized for some reason?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One signal that Google introduced one month after us making the switch was to give SSL-secured sites a little ranking boost. Since &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/iwantmyname/blog&quot;&gt;our blog is running on GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;, which &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/isaacs/github/issues/156&quot;&gt;doesn’t currently support HTTPS&lt;/a&gt;, could that have prevented the traffic from recovering? Certainly it can’t be that much of a ranking signal—although they mentioned it would increase in importance over time?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So after waiting for six months, we reverted the change and switched our blog back to the previous &lt;code&gt;/blog&lt;/code&gt; subdirectory. It’s still hosted on GitHub Pages and we’re using a simple Nginx proxy to show the content under &lt;code&gt;iwantmyname.com/blog&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;location = /blog {
  # GitHub Pages doesn&amp;#39;t redirect this properly, so we&amp;#39;ll handle it
  return 301 /blog/;
}

# ^~ to allow /blog/ to match before our other regex locations
location ^~ /blog/ {
  proxy_pass https://iwantmyname.github.io;
  proxy_intercept_errors on;
  # serve custom 404 page from our blog repo instead of GitHub Pages&amp;#39; 404
  error_page  404  /blog/404.html;
  # allow GitHub to pass caching headers instead of using our own
  expires off;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An important side effect is that our blog pages are now secured under our primary SSL certificate again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on this experience and the following &lt;a href=&quot;http://moz.com/community/q/moz-s-official-stance-on-subdomain-vs-subfolder-does-it-need-updating#reply_217479&quot;&gt;recommendation from Moz’s Rand Fishkin&lt;/a&gt;, we decided it would be better for our long-term SEO strategy to put our blog back on our primary domain:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would still strongly urge folks to keep all content on a single subdomain. We recently were able to test this using a subdomain on Moz itself (when moving our beginner&amp;#39;s guide to SEO from guides.moz.com to the current URL http://moz.com/beginners-guide-to-seo). The results were astounding - rankings rose dramatically across the board for every keyword we tracked to the pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will certainly keep a close eye on traffic for the next few months and keep you updated. Hope this helps some of you when deciding on the age-old debate of whether you should have your blog on a subdomain or not!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2015 15:53:45 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/01/seo-penalties-of-moving-our-blog-to-a-subdomain.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/01/seo-penalties-of-moving-our-blog-to-a-subdomain.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>New gTLDs and SEO performance</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.circleid.com/posts/20150112_new_gtlds_show_promising_seo_performance/&quot;&gt;From Roland LaPlante - CircleID:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the arrival of hundreds of new generic top-level domains (gTLDs), many marketers are excited that they can now get a web address that best describes their business or brand. For instance, a company in the organic business can now get a web address on .ORGANIC, or a brand that&amp;#39;s all about passion and excitement can now get on .RED, etc. At the same time, many are also asking some important SEO related questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will Google crawl new gTLDs?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will new gTLDs automatically score higher in Google&amp;#39;s search algorithms?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the SEO best practices for migrating a site to a new gTLD?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Should brands REALLY get on new gTLDs and give up the status quo?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#39;s address them one by one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2015 15:32:01 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/01/new-gtlds-and-seo-performance.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/01/new-gtlds-and-seo-performance.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Say hi to the newest iwantmynamer, Kevin Layshock</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;With 2015 now in full swing, we&amp;#39;d like to announce our newest addition—Kevin Layshock. Over the course of the next year (decade(s)?), he&amp;#39;ll be designing his way around the iwantmyname universe, buttoning up the website, redesigning our emails, improving our branding, and generally making everything a bit more friendly and usable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to say hi, you can find him on Twitter &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/couthmonger&quot;&gt;@couthmonger&lt;/a&gt;. Conversation starters include: interesting UI/UX design, contemporary art, beautiful lettering, comic books, podcasts, good movies (only good ones), coffee, and of course, tasty beverages.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2015 13:30:05 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/01/say-hi-to-the-newest-iwantmynamer-kevin-layshock.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/01/say-hi-to-the-newest-iwantmynamer-kevin-layshock.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>How to use a standard Gmail account for free custom domain email</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://simplyian.com/2015/01/07/Hacking-GMail-to-use-custom-domains-for-free/&quot;&gt;From Ian Macalinao:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s pretty much common knowledge that GMail is awesome. It’s fast, connects seamlessly with the rest of your Google services such as Drive, has a cool app called Inbox, and is overall an extremely powerful email service. However, to use it with a custom domain, you need to purchase Google Apps for either $5 or $10/month, which for casual users is a bit unnecessary. On top of that, you don’t even get all of the features a personal account gets, e.g. Inbox.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there’s a free way to use your GMail account with a custom domain: Mailgun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Neat trick for more advanced users to set up custom domain email using a standard Gmail account and &lt;a href=&quot;http://mailgun.com&quot;&gt;Mailgun&lt;/a&gt; (for up to 10,000 emails a month). &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2014/06/yes-you-can-still-get-free-custom-email-addresses.html&quot;&gt;Yes, you can still get free custom domain email addresses&lt;/a&gt; — even in 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2015 18:25:06 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/01/how-to-use-a-standard-gmail-account-for-free-custom-domain-email.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/01/how-to-use-a-standard-gmail-account-for-free-custom-domain-email.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Doing is almost always more important than worrying</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thenameinspector.com/weird-startup-names-of-2014/&quot;&gt;From The Name Inspector:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Name Inspector has been reflecting on last year’s startup names while sipping on what’s left of the apple peel bourbon he made for the holidays. He’s got to say, it seems like some of these companies were named by people who sipped lots of bourbon. Here are some weird names of startups in CrunchBase that were founded in 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember when Nirvana (the band) first started getting played on the radio. Most of my friends were really into the music, but all I could think was “I’m pretty sure I have what it takes to sing incomprehensible lyrics, too! I’m definitely going to be a rock star.” And sure, naming your brand is a whole lot different than singing songs, but the message is similar—extreme talent aside, Nirvana was a success because they actually made music. I wasn’t because I was too worried about everything to ever get on stage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I’m trying to say, and what a lot of the startups mentioned in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thenameinspector.com/weird-startup-names-of-2014/&quot;&gt;the article&lt;/a&gt; prove, is that you shouldn’t let branding uncertainty (or even wackiness) prevent you from doing what you want to do. Sure, maybe you think it’s a mistake to name a brand &lt;em&gt;AssessUp&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;KeeeWeee&lt;/em&gt;, but look at all these brands. They exist...they’re real companies with profiles on CrunchBase! You just never know what might become the next big household brand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In many ways, that same thought process also works for domain extensions. I talk to people all the time who spend a lot of energy worrying about not getting the perfect .com, but the world is changing, and people’s comfort level with “strange” non-.com’s is growing by the day. If what you’re creating is good, people will find you wherever you’re at—.io, .co, your local country code top-level domain (ccTLD), or any of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/new-gtld-domain-extensions&quot;&gt;new domain extensions&lt;/a&gt; on the market. Just go with the domain that fits your brand best—the rest will often work itself out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2015 15:16:06 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/01/doing-is-almost-always-more-important-than-worrying.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/01/doing-is-almost-always-more-important-than-worrying.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>The January domain discounts, including .Vegas and .Asia</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s a new year, so let&amp;#39;s talk a bit about domain discounts. This month, we have a host of sales carrying over from December, plus two location-based TLDs moonlighting as cultural favorites. .Vegas, hailing from the US city of Las Vegas, is synonymous on the web (and elsewhere) with gambling culture, and will likely draw interest with gaming sites and travel microsites. And .Asia, the world&amp;#39;s largest continent, is attempting to bring online nations together for business and trade. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take a look at 2015&amp;#39;s first domain discount list, and start the new year right with a shiny new online space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;New this month&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-asia&quot;&gt;.asia&lt;/a&gt; - $14.90/yr (from $24.90)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-vegas&quot;&gt;.vegas&lt;/a&gt; - $24.90/yr (from $79.00)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Continued from last month&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-black&quot;&gt;.black&lt;/a&gt; - $9.90/yr (from $69.00)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-blue&quot;&gt;.blue&lt;/a&gt; - $9.90/yr (from $19.90)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-co&quot;&gt;.co&lt;/a&gt; - $15.50/yr (from $29.90)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-io&quot;&gt;.io&lt;/a&gt; - $49.00/yr (from $59.00)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-me&quot;&gt;.me&lt;/a&gt; - $19.90/yr (from $24.90)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-mobi&quot;&gt;.mobi&lt;/a&gt; - $9.90/yr (from $24.90)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-ninja&quot;&gt;.ninja&lt;/a&gt; - $15.50/yr (from $24.90)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-pink&quot;&gt;.pink&lt;/a&gt; - $9.90/yr (from $19.90)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-red&quot;&gt;.red&lt;/a&gt; - $9.90/yr (from $19.90)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-reviews&quot;&gt;.reviews&lt;/a&gt; - $19.00/yr (from $29.00)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-rocks&quot;&gt;.rocks&lt;/a&gt; - $15.50/yr (from $19.00)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-shiksha&quot;&gt;.shiksha&lt;/a&gt; - $9.90/yr (from 19.00)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-social&quot;&gt;.social&lt;/a&gt; - $22.50/yr (from $39.00)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-%E7%A7%BB%E5%8A%A8&quot;&gt;移动&lt;/a&gt; - $9.90/yr (from $19.90)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#39;t want to miss a deal? Be sure to check our &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/special-offer&quot;&gt;domain discounts page&lt;/a&gt; at the beginning of each month for the full list of what we have for sale. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 08:21:47 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/01/the-january-domain-discounts.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/01/the-january-domain-discounts.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Meet the domain extensions of January (2015!), including .degree, .space, and .band</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2014 is done, folks. Our new gTLD catalogue is now filled with &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/new-gtld-domain-extensions&quot;&gt;257 new generic top-level domains (gTLDs)&lt;/a&gt;, including the ever-popular &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-club&quot;&gt;.club&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-link&quot;&gt;.link&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-guru&quot;&gt;.guru&lt;/a&gt; (and of course, &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-kiwi&quot;&gt;.kiwi&lt;/a&gt;), and we have a ton more to come in 2015. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the big question...has the new gTLD launch been a success? Well, it depends what your metric is. .Xyz recently hit the 750,000 domains registered mark, making it the most registered new gTLD out there, and as Peter Roesler of Inc. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.inc.com/peter-roesler/will-new-top-level-domains-matter-in-2015.html&quot;&gt;put it&lt;/a&gt;, &amp;quot;If you want to use one of the new TLDs to build a site with an easy-to-remember name, you won&amp;#39;t be disappointed&amp;quot;. Sure, the registration numbers aren&amp;#39;t to the level of .com yet, but I think any gTLD registry owner would tell you it&amp;#39;s a marathon, not a sprint. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2015, I&amp;#39;d expect to see steady gTLD growth as more people become aware of their existence (if the general public knew about the glorious &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-pizza&quot;&gt;.pizza&lt;/a&gt; extension, we&amp;#39;d see an online pizza renaissance for sure). And with another year of new launches, paired with the ever-dwindling supply of good remaining .coms, the growth might be faster than people expect. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prognostication aside, we have a big year of gTLDs ahead of us, and it all begins with the 11 new extensions we&amp;#39;re launching this month. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;January 14&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-degree&quot;&gt;.degree&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-gives&quot;&gt;.gives&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-world&quot;&gt;.world&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;January 20&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-brussels&quot;&gt;.brussels&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-vlaanderen&quot;&gt;.vlaanderen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;January 21&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-forsale&quot;&gt;.forsale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;January 28&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-band&quot;&gt;.band&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-how&quot;&gt;.how&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-rip&quot;&gt;.rip&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-ryukyu&quot;&gt;.ryukyu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-space&quot;&gt;.space&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the full list of the gTLDs coming out (now updated through March 11th), be sure to visit our &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/new-gtld-launch-dates&quot;&gt;launch calendar&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 14:25:30 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/01/meet-the-domain-extensions-of-january.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/01/meet-the-domain-extensions-of-january.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Reply All covers Longform.org’s attempt to buy their corresponding .com</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve never resold or purchased a domain on an aftermarket in my life, but hearing stories about that side of the domain industry is vastly entertaining. There’s intrigue, secret internet dealings, big characters, big egos—it’s all there. And this week, one of my favorite new podcasts, Reply All, covered Longform.org’s attempt to purchase their corresponding .com from Michael Berkens, reseller extraordinaire and founder of The Domains. It’s a good one—give it a listen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Just a heads up...if you’re easily offended, there are a couple curse words in this episode. Nothing big, but they’re there.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/183982208&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=true&amp;amp;show_comments=false&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;visual=true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2015 11:35:28 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/01/reply-all-covers-longform-orgs-attempt-to-buy-their-corresponding-com.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/01/reply-all-covers-longform-orgs-attempt-to-buy-their-corresponding-com.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Dear internet, it’s time to fix your footer (again)</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are very few certainties in life—death, taxes, the fact that eggs always taste better with a dash of hot sauce, and that on January 1st, the little numbers in the year will change ever so slightly. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pre-internet, this wasn’t such a big deal. Sure, you might write the wrong year on a check or document, but it wasn’t an error the world would have to see on a daily basis. Not like on a website, where nearly all the footers in existence—the big footers, small footers, dark footers, and light footers—share one tiny trait. © 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I say “nearly” because every year there are those who forget to manually change the year from one to the next. It’s a bit of a minor tragedy, but entirely understandable. Fortunately, Mikko Järvenpää has your back, with a clever site called &lt;a href=&quot;http://updateyourfooter.com&quot;&gt;updateyourfooter.com&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever looked at a website and wondered if it is still in operation? Maybe a thing or two looked like they could have been updated – and then you notice the copyright notice the in the footer. &amp;quot;2012. Right, this site must be dead. Let&amp;#39;s move along.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, it could be that the owner just forgot to update the year in the footer. That happens a lot, especially if those years are hard-coded strings. To future-proof your footer, it&amp;#39;s better to just let computers take care of this. Grab one of these snippets and paste that on your page (or forward this site as a friendly reminder to someone who can do it for you).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So before the new year hits, grab a snippet for your site and leave your worries behind. Hakuna matata.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2014 09:31:06 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2014/12/dear-internet-its-time-to-fix-your-footer.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2014/12/dear-internet-its-time-to-fix-your-footer.html</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
