<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>iwantmyname Domain Blog</title>
		<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/</link>
		<atom:link href="https://iwantmyname.com/blog/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Progress report or it didn&#39;t happen</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apa.org/news/press/releases/2015/10/progress-goals.aspx&#34;&gt;Jim Sliwa on achieving goals:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are trying to achieve a goal, the more often that you monitor your progress, the greater the likelihood that you will succeed, according to research published by the American Psychological Association. Your chances of success are even more likely if you report your progress publicly or physically record it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Monitoring goal progress is a crucial process that comes into play between setting and attaining a goal, ensuring that the goals are translated into action,” said lead author Benjamin Harkin, PhD, of the University of Sheffield. The study appears in the journal Psychological Bulletin®. “This review suggests that prompting progress monitoring improves behavioral performance and the likelihood of attaining one’s goals.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 13:02:00 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/11/progress-report-or-it-didnt-happen.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/11/progress-report-or-it-didnt-happen.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Your office might be making you stupid</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://arstechnica.com/science/2015/10/stuffy-offices-can-halve-cognitive-scores/&#34;&gt;Beth Mole on how stale air can kill the brain cells:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compared with inhaling fresh air, gulping down the stale air found in conventional office buildings can stifle cognitive function by half, researchers report in Environmental Health Perspectives. The finding suggests that improving the performance, productivity, and health of many office workers could be done with just a fresh breeze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The results are striking,” lead researcher Joseph Allen, director of the Healthy Buildings program at Harvard, told Ars. Researchers knew that air quality would likely affect cognitive function and work performance, but earlier studies included few people and reported subjective data. We didn’t expect to see that high quality air could double cognitive scores, Allen said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m happy to report that iwantmyname allows me to do all my writing outside. In my pajamas.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 11:02:00 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/11/your-office-might-be-making-you-stupid.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/11/your-office-might-be-making-you-stupid.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Your password is probably pretty bad</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.technologyreview.com/news/542576/youve-been-misled-about-what-makes-a-good-password/&#34;&gt;Tom Simonite on why current password advice is misleading:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Password must include upper and lowercase letters, and at least one numeric character.” A common scold dished out by websites or software when you open an account or change a password—and one that new research suggests is misleading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A study that tested state-of-the-art password-guessing techniques found that requiring numbers and uppercase characters in passwords doesn’t do much to make them stronger. Making a password longer or including symbols was much more effective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2015, &amp;ldquo;password&amp;rdquo; is just slightly worse than &amp;ldquo;Password1&amp;rdquo;. Maybe try something like &amp;ldquo;I hate typing in passwords!&amp;rdquo; (or start using a tool like &lt;a href=&#34;https://agilebits.com/onepassword&#34;&gt;1Password&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 09:50:00 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/11/your-password-is-probably-pretty-bad.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/11/your-password-is-probably-pretty-bad.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>If your user interface promotes bad passwords, you&#39;re not doing it right</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hotdogsladies&#34;&gt;Two tweets by Merlin Mann on how technology promotes bad passwords:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tweet 1: If you can entirely set up an Apple TV without screaming at the sky, your passwords probably suck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tweet 2: I&amp;rsquo;m not saying all this merely to bitch. I&amp;rsquo;m concerned that stuff like Apple TV genuinely contributes to people&amp;rsquo;s shitty password choices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We (the tech industry) spend a lot of time: 1. promoting good user interfaces. 2. promoting good passwords. If your good user interface doesn&amp;rsquo;t promote good passwords, you&amp;rsquo;re not doing it right.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2015 15:30:00 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/10/youre-not-doing-it-right.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/10/youre-not-doing-it-right.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>We do domain names</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://radar.oreilly.com/2015/10/do-one-thing.html&#34;&gt;Mike Loukides on wanting tools that do one thing well, as opposed to a number of things not so well:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been lamenting the demise of the Unix philosophy: tools should do one thing, and do it well. The ability to connect many small tools is better than having a single tool that does everything poorly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That philosophy was great, but hasn’t survived into the Web age. Unfortunately, nothing better has come along to replace it. Instead, we have “convergence”: a lot of tools converging on doing all the same things poorly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We do domain names. That&amp;rsquo;s it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2015 15:10:00 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/10/we-do-domain-names.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/10/we-do-domain-names.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Quality of work-life should be a top priority</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/wonkblog/wp/2015/10/28/researchers-have-determined-how-many-years-of-life-you-lose-to-a-stressful-job/&#34;&gt;Ana Swanson on how job stress is literally killing people in the US:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People often like to groan about how their job is &amp;ldquo;killing&amp;rdquo; them. Tragically, for some groups of people in the U.S., that statement appears to be true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A new study by researchers at Harvard and Stanford has quantified just how much a stressful workplace may be shaving off of Americans&amp;rsquo; life spans. It suggests that the amount of life lost to stress varies significantly for people of different races, educational levels and genders, and ranges up to nearly three years of life lost for some groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech startups tend to spend a good deal of time talking about workplace culture and work/life balance, but it&amp;rsquo;s clearly something all business owners and managers need to be working on. These workplace decisions have long term effects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(On a related note, the US clearly needs to figure out its healthcare system. The amount of years shaved from lack of health care is insane.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2015 14:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/10/quality-of-work-life-should-be-a-top-priority.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/10/quality-of-work-life-should-be-a-top-priority.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Ad blockers and an-ugh-lytics</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://snipcart.com/blog/ad-blockers-saas-web-developers?utm_content=bufferd7420&amp;amp;utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_source=twitter.com&amp;amp;utm_campaign=buffer&#34;&gt;François Lanthier Nadeau on how ad blockers are messing with Snipcart&amp;rsquo;s metrics:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We quickly spotted a few listed third parties names that reminded us how effective those blockers can be. Especially when we read: Google Analytics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why the facepalm? Well, most of our website visitors and potential users are tech-savvy developers who are highly susceptible of running general purpose blocking software such as uBlock &amp;amp; uBlock Origin. In other words, we had just realized that a potentially substantial chunk of our website traffic were basically… ghosts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We learned something we should’ve learned a while ago: we can’t rely 100% on our tracking analytics. As a SaaS startup that focuses most of its growth on content marketing and website optimization, that’s not exactly good news. So for SaaS businesses, ads are just the tip of the ad-blocking/general purpose blocking iceberg. And what’s under the water here has a much more important potential impact on the businesses themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not that we care (I myself run ad blockers on desktop and mobile), but I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure our analytics are barely worth tracking these days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a related note, I think if we all turned off analytics and did marketing/site content solely based on what we think is most worthwhile for our customers, the internet would be a much more eclectic place. Maybe not measurably better, but certainly more interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2015 14:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/10/ad-blockers-and-anughlytics.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/10/ad-blockers-and-anughlytics.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Standing desks are for overachievers</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fastcoexist.com/3052273/instead-of-standing-why-not-lie-down-while-you-work-this-desk-lets-you-do-both&#34;&gt;Adele Peters on the new Altwork Station:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe you slouch in your Aeron chair. Maybe you tried—and failed—to make using a standing desk a habit. Maybe, like me, your preferred working position is curled up on a sofa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is it time for an ergonomic desk and chair that lazy people will actually want to use?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new Altwork Station, designed by aerospace engineers, has a standing and sitting position. But it also reclines fully into a &amp;ldquo;zero g&amp;rdquo; position—basically as comfortable as being in bed—with a monitor, laptop, and mouse floating the proper distance away above you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Out with your standing desk. Out with your upright chair. Out with your yoga ball. If you want to maximize my workplace happiness, I&amp;rsquo;d like to roll out of my real bed and into a work bed. (To be fair, I already do 75% of my work in a giant beanbag.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2015 10:10:00 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/10/standing-desks-are-for-overachievers.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/10/standing-desks-are-for-overachievers.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Sign me up!</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mailchimp.com/resources/guides/how-to-avoid-spam-filters/html/&#34;&gt;MailChimp on how spam filters work:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spam filters consider a long list of criteria when judging the “spamminess” of an email. They’ll weigh each factor and add them up to determine a spam score, which then determines whether a campaign will pass through the filter. They might look for spammy phrases like “CLICK HERE!” or “FREE! BUY NOW!” Then they&amp;rsquo;ll assign points every time they see one of those phrases. Certain criteria get more points than others. Here’s a sample of criteria from SpamAssassin:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Talks about lots of money (.193 points)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Describes some sort of breakthrough (.232 points)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Looks like mortgage pitch (.297 points)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contains urgent matter (.288 points)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Money back guarantee (2.051 points)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your campaign’s total “spam score” exceeds a certain threshold, then your email goes to the junk folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thought of this when &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aAYw69hU2Yc&#34;&gt;watching this&lt;/a&gt; (sign me up!).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2015 15:50:00 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/10/sign-me-up.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/10/sign-me-up.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>1API Abuse Domain Suspension Scam</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Recently we have been made aware of fraudulent emails that have been sent to a number of high profile domain registrars&amp;rsquo; customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These emails appear to be coming from abuse@1api.net or similar email addresses and attempt to impersonate the Spam and Abuse Department of our in-house domain name registrar 1API GmbH. These suspension emails are NOT being sent from Hexonet, 1API, or iwantmyname.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fraudulent emails claim your domain name has been suspended because you have failed to respond to previous email and telephone notices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The email message is an attempt to have you click on links and download files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DO NOT reply to the email directly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DO NOT click on any links.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DO NOT call the number listed in the email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just delete and ignore the email. If you have any questions or concerns, whether you have received the email or not, &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/support&#34;&gt;please don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a copy of one of the emails:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://iwmn.me/jcA7/1t06yaFS+&#34; alt=&#34;abuse spam email&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2015 11:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/10/oneapi-abuse-domain-suspension-scam.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/10/oneapi-abuse-domain-suspension-scam.html</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
