<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>iwantmyname Domain Blog</title>
		<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/</link>
		<atom:link href="https://iwantmyname.com/blog/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Getting the internet to the underdeveloped world without drones or high-altitude balloons</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lowtechmagazine.com/2015/10/how-to-build-a-low-tech-internet.html&#34;&gt;Kris De Decker on how to build a low-tech internet:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than half of the global population does not have access to the &amp;ldquo;worldwide&amp;rdquo; web. Up to now, the internet is mainly an urban phenomenon, especially in &amp;ldquo;developing&amp;rdquo; countries. Telecommunication companies are usually reluctant to extend their network outside cities due to a combination of high infrastructure costs, low population density, limited ability to pay for services, and an unreliable or non-existent electricity infrastructure. Even in remote regions of &amp;ldquo;developed&amp;rdquo; countries, internet connectivity isn&amp;rsquo;t always available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Internet companies such as Facebook and Google regularly make headlines with plans for connecting these remote regions to the internet. Facebook tries to achieve this with drones, while Google counts on high-altitude balloons. There are major technological challenges, but the main objection to these plans is their commercial character. Obviously, Google and Facebook want to connect more people to the internet because that would increase their revenues. Facebook especially receives lots of criticism because their network promotes their own site in particular, and blocks most other internet applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, several research groups and network enthusiasts have developed and implemented much cheaper alternative network technologies to solve these issues. Although these low-tech networks have proven their worth, they have received much less attention. Contrary to the projects of internet companies, they are set up by small organisations or by the users themselves. This guarantees an open network that benefits the users instead of a handful of corporations. At the same time, these low-tech networks are very energy efficient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2015 10:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/10/getting-the-internet-to-the-underdeveloped-world.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/10/getting-the-internet-to-the-underdeveloped-world.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>The machines have taken over (your search results)</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2015-10-26/google-turning-its-lucrative-web-search-over-to-ai-machines&#34;&gt;Jack Clark on Google using AI to figure out its search results:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the past few months, a “very large fraction” of the millions of queries a second that people type into the company’s search engine have been interpreted by an artificial intelligence system, nicknamed RankBrain, said Greg Corrado, a senior research scientist with the company, outlining for the first time the emerging role of AI in search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RankBrain uses artificial intelligence to embed vast amounts of written language into mathematical entities &amp;mdash; called vectors &amp;mdash; that the computer can understand. If RankBrain sees a word or phrase it isn’t familiar with, the machine can make a guess as to what words or phrases might have a similar meaning and filter the result accordingly, making it more effective at handling never-before-seen search queries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in the day I spent a lot of time thinking about SEO. I poured over SEO blogs, asked for advice on how I can improve my search results, and did everything in my power to game the (people-powered) Google system. But it&amp;rsquo;s 2015. The computers are taking over. All that matters now is making sites that perform their intended task with the least resistance possible.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 12:05:00 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/10/the-machines-have-taken-over.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/10/the-machines-have-taken-over.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>What if you don&#39;t talkie very clearly?</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://paulgraham.com/talk.html&#34;&gt;Paul Graham with some writing advice:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, so written and spoken language are different. Does that make written language worse?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want people to read and understand what you write, yes. Written language is more complex, which makes it more work to read. It&amp;rsquo;s also more formal and distant, which gives the reader&amp;rsquo;s attention permission to drift. But perhaps worst of all, the complex sentences and fancy words give you, the writer, the false impression that you&amp;rsquo;re saying more than you actually are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favorite is when arguments start in comment sections. They all start with similar troll statements followed by simple insults. But then they inevitably expand into a series of people trying to prove points with dissertation-style sentences that mean nothing. So many syllables, so little thought.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 08:05:21 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/10/what-if-you-dont-talkie-very-clearly.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/10/what-if-you-dont-talkie-very-clearly.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Every TLD has a story</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://priceonomics.com/the-rise-and-fall-of-ly/&#34;&gt;Rosie Cima on the rise and fall of .LY:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, in 2011, civil war broke out in Libya. One of the main registrars of .ly addresses, Libyan Spider, was shut down, apparently as part of UN/US sanctions on Libya. For a time, the owners of Libyan Spider were only able to revive these urls by leaving the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The start-up Letter.ly also announced that it had gone down because it had let its domain registration expire, and it could not establish contact with the registrar to renew it’s contract. “Sorry for the hassle,” they wrote in an email to their users. “it’s amazing that a physical war has affected our service in this way.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 07:00:21 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/10/every-tld-has-a-story.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/10/every-tld-has-a-story.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>An educated guess as to why domain name growth has been stalling</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.circleid.com/posts/20150716_where_has_the_domain_name_growth_gone/&#34;&gt;Jay Dailey, Chief Executive of the .nz registry, on slowing domain name growth:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The impact of new gTLDs has been to solve the &amp;lsquo;meaningfulness problem&amp;rsquo; by the creation of hundreds of new gTLDs and this in turn directly affects the perception of scarcity. This reduction in scarcity is in turn reducing the incentive to speculate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is my assertion that this speculative behaviour has been a significant factor in historical growth and so domain name growth prospects are partly dependent on what happens to that behaviour. At the macro level, global speculative behaviour in domain names will reduce and the money will switch to a different scarce asset, permanently leaving our industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the foreseeable future people will need domain names to create things on the internet, so registrars will be fine (although the days of bananas growth might be over). But the owners of these new gTLDs are probably sweating a bit. Their &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.geek.com/news/gtlds-whats-the-process-and-how-much-pay-icann-1392947/&#34;&gt;$185,000 investments&lt;/a&gt; might take much longer than expected to return a profit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2015 12:30:00 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/10/an-educated-guess-as-to-why-domain-name-growth-has-been-stalling.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/10/an-educated-guess-as-to-why-domain-name-growth-has-been-stalling.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Too much choice might be a bad thing</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2015/oct/21/choice-stressing-us-out-dating-partners-monopolies&#34;&gt;Stuart Jeffries on the stress that choice induces:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time in Springfield, the Simpson family visited a new supermarket. Monstromart’s slogan was “where shopping is a baffling ordeal”. Product choice was unlimited, shelving reached the ceiling, nutmeg came in 12lb boxes and the express checkout had a sign reading, “1,000 items or less”. In the end the Simpsons returned to Apu’s Kwik-E-Mart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In doing so, the Simpsons were making a choice to reduce their choice. It wasn’t quite a rational choice, but it made sense. In the parlance of economic theory, they were not rational utility maximisers but, in Herbert Simon’s term, “satisficers” – opting for what was good enough, rather than becoming confused to the point of inertia in front of Monstromart’s ranges of products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;d be interesting to see how the domain industry, as a whole, is faring with &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/new-gtld-domain-extensions&#34;&gt;500+ (and counting) new gTLDs&lt;/a&gt; on the shelves. (Sometimes I think we should just pick the top 25 and say, &amp;ldquo;This is what we&amp;rsquo;re selling because these are the good ones!&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2015 08:00:21 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/10/too-much-choice-might-be-a-bad-thing.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/10/too-much-choice-might-be-a-bad-thing.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Solving the new privacy Rubik’s Cube</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.microsoft.com/eupolicy/2015/10/20/the-collapse-of-the-u-s-eu-safe-harbor-solving-the-new-privacy-rubiks-cube/&#34;&gt;Brad Smith, Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s President and Chief Legal Officer, on the collapse of the EU-US Safe Harbor:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need to protect privacy as a fundamental human right. We need a global Internet. We need to keep the public safe. And we need to find a legal path that will work on both sides of the Atlantic. We need to do all four of these things together and simultaneously. This is the privacy version of a Rubik’s Cube.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we’re going to find a long-term and sustainable approach, we need to think afresh. The leading privacy law in the United States was adopted in 1986. The laws in Europe come from the same era. The approaches that were developed fifteen years before the 20th century ended are simply not adequate fifteen years after the 21st century began. It’s not just technology that has changed. The world has changed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2015 15:55:21 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/10/solving-the-new-privacy-rubiks-cube.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/10/solving-the-new-privacy-rubiks-cube.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Death and digital properties</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple hundred years ago, it was possible to live and die leaving pretty much zero physical evidence of your existence. Except perhaps some kids. Today, though, someone with no identity footprint would be nearly unheard of. I&amp;rsquo;m even skeptical of companies that don&amp;rsquo;t have websites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that so many of us have these broad digital presences — websites, email accounts, social media profiles, photos, videos, text — the footprints we leave behind may require some maintenance and planning. After all, your online self is as much a part of your life as your photo albums,  household items, and collectibles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond keeping payment details updated, domains renewed, passwords secure, etc., we need to consider life&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;what ifs?&amp;rdquo; Or &amp;ldquo;hit by a bus&amp;rdquo; scenarios, as we&amp;rsquo;ve called them at a few places I&amp;rsquo;ve worked. What happens if you&amp;rsquo;re not there tomorrow? Maybe you moved on to a new job, left a relationship, or actually were hit by a bus!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can anyone else access your accounts? Do you want them to? Did you want any of your online profiles or properties to be left accessible? Are there going to be business issues with websites or email accounts if domains were registered in your name and paid for by your credit card?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It doesn&amp;rsquo;t tend to be something we give a lot of thought to. Maybe once a year when you get a domain renewal notice. Or when a site has a security breach and you&amp;rsquo;re advised to change your password. But it&amp;rsquo;s something our team deals with regularly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;So and so has left the company and&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; begins a lot of emails we receive. Some employee has set up an account with their email address, registered the company&amp;rsquo;s domain(s), and paid for them with their credit card. And now no one knows the login, the email address no longer works, and the credit card has been cancelled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If they&amp;rsquo;re lucky, they figure this out &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; the website and email stop working, but not always. As often as not the emails we get are somewhat panicked. But while we understand customers&amp;rsquo; predicaments in these cases, we can&amp;rsquo;t just hand over the keys, so to speak. We need to authenticate who has access to the account, who owns the domains(s), etc., to prevent straight-up theft. You don&amp;rsquo;t want to end up dealing with one of these situations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, how can you keep your online properties up to date, and make sure those who need administrative access to accounts can get it when needed?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-1&#34;&gt;Avoid registering business accounts or domains with personal information&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-2&#34;&gt;What will happen if you can&amp;rsquo;t access an account or there&amp;rsquo;s a dispute&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-3&#34;&gt;What will happen if you die&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-4&#34;&gt;Just part of being a grownup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-1&#34;&gt;Avoid registering business accounts or domains with personal information&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s pretty common for things like domains and social media accounts to be assigned to a primary person. Since you&amp;rsquo;re asked for personal details like name and email address (and sometimes &lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; to provide an individual information rather than company information), it seems like a no-brainer to use your own details. If you can avoid that, do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use an organizational email address that more than one person has access to. That way others will have the login, or at the very least can get and use a password reset email if needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have to use an individual&amp;rsquo;s name on an account, so be it, use yours or an administrative one, but be sure to include the organization&amp;rsquo;s name in the &lt;em&gt;Company&lt;/em&gt; field as well. It provides some link to the company if we hear from someone who&amp;rsquo;s not the main contact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be aware when registering domains that the registrant or owner contact name is the legal owner of the domain. Even if the person worked for your company and registered the domain on behalf of the company. If the registrant contact says John Smith, it&amp;rsquo;s legally John Smith&amp;rsquo;s domain name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If possible, register the domain under the company name, not a person&amp;rsquo;s name. Note that our system automatically adds the account contact information as the registrant information, but you can update that in your dashboard under &lt;strong&gt;edit contacts&lt;/strong&gt;, or, in some cases (like ccTLDs), we can do it for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If possible, use a corporate credit card under the company or organization&amp;rsquo;s name. There&amp;rsquo;s (perhaps) a better chance of someone tracking its use and when expiry dates will need to be updated, for example. The more data points we have for the organization, the easier it will be to prove who owns or should have access to the account and domains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When there&amp;rsquo;s an issue of account access, we request proof of ID for the account holder and a partial scan of the card on the account. Take a look at your account details and ask yourself if anyone else would be able to provide them if you&amp;rsquo;re not around to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-2&#34;&gt;What will happen if you can&#39;t access an account or there&#39;s a dispute&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At best, we require an assortment of proof of identification and ownership. At worst, if there seems to be an issue, or information isn&amp;rsquo;t clear, we lock down accounts while we wait for more information (for as long as necessary&amp;hellip;even if your website and email are down).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That means no party can access it, which means if a credit card is invalid, domains can&amp;rsquo;t be renewed and may expire and be lost. If something goes wrong with DNS or hosting, a site may remain offline or emails will bounce. You can imagine this could be a serious problem for businesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it&amp;rsquo;s just a customer who&amp;rsquo;s forgotten a password, we can send a password reset email, or do our standard authentication to help them get back into their own account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If one party claims another party has left a company, for example, and they need access to the account for the domains, we will take a look at the account. We&amp;rsquo;ll see what evidence there is that the domains belong to the company. We&amp;rsquo;ll see what other domains are in the account. (We&amp;rsquo;re not going to hand over account access if there&amp;rsquo;s one company domain and 10 that appear to be personal and unrelated.) We will ask for authentication documentation for the company, alleged former employee, person asking for access, and whatever else we feel is necessary to prove ownership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We take customer account security very seriously, which can be frustrating for some people. But just imagine someone was trying to get access to &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; accounts or domains. Would you want us to hand over access just based on an email saying, &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Let me in&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-3&#34;&gt;What will happen if you die&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s up to you. Some people may want their web properties&amp;rsquo; content archived, or their friends or families might. Some people might want everything to eventually expire and be deleted. Some people might have secret accounts or profiles they don&amp;rsquo;t want anyone to know about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s pretty common, in addition to a formal will, to have a more informal list of requests, bequests, or instructions. We&amp;rsquo;d recommend adding a section about your digital properties there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re big fans of password management programs, and if you use one of those, there&amp;rsquo;s a good chance you just need to keep track of one password. Record it with your will and any related documents. Remember to update it when you update your password(s). Then someone will be able to maintain or remove your accounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thedigitalbeyond.com/online-services-list/&#34;&gt;There are also a variety of sites and tools to help manage digital legacies.&lt;/a&gt; Whether it&amp;rsquo;s checking regularly whether you&amp;rsquo;re still alive or not, sending out posthumous messages to loved ones, providing a place for those who cared about you to memorialize you, or wiping accounts or files you don&amp;rsquo;t want anyone else to know about, handling our digital afterlives can be well covered.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember, too, that a lot of work can go into sorting things out and tying up loose ends after someone dies, and the people left doing it are often tired, sad, and stressed. It&amp;rsquo;s a kindness to make these arrangements in advance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-4&#34;&gt;Just part of being a grownup&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Occasionally we complain that websites or apps want too much personal information from us when we try to set up accounts or start using them. But in general, it&amp;rsquo;s extremely easy to create new digital footprints online. It&amp;rsquo;s actually often harder to erase them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of this, many of us give little thought to how broad our digital presences and properties actually are. Sure, many of us have plenty of little-used and abandoned accounts. They don&amp;rsquo;t cost us time or money (maybe a little email spam). But many of us &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; have online presences and properties that are important to us, and to others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For various reasons, if and when we&amp;rsquo;re not around to take care of them, like any good property management, it&amp;rsquo;s the grownup and responsible thing to do to make sure someone else can.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2015 15:55:21 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/10/death-and-digital-properties.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/10/death-and-digital-properties.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Anyone can build a small business website (even you)</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The commonly told tale is that website building is for &amp;ldquo;computer geniuses&amp;rdquo; who&amp;rsquo;ve been churning out complicated code for much of their waking lives. But it&amp;rsquo;s not true. Sure, building a massive site for a global corporation is a huge undertaking, but the tools exist, right now, for small business owners of any computer skill level to quickly create beautiful sites and online stores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t believe me? Read on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-1&#34;&gt;Step 1: Get a domain name&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-2&#34;&gt;Step 2: Choose a website platform&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-3&#34;&gt;Step 3: Install your domain to your website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-4&#34;&gt;Step 4: Get a custom email address&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-1&#34;&gt;Step 1: Get a domain name&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choosing a domain name, particularly the part after the dot (as in BUSINESSNAME dot COM), may seem like an arbitrary task, but it&amp;rsquo;s your first step to establishing legitimacy. There&amp;rsquo;s plenty of content on the web that goes over this in some detail—including &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/06/how-to-pick-the-right-domain-extension.html&#34;&gt;our guide&lt;/a&gt;—but let&amp;rsquo;s reframe it here from a traditional business perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think of your domain as the location of your shop. As with a shop, you generally want to be front-and-center on the best street in town (location, location, location!) to get the most traffic. In the world of domains, here&amp;rsquo;s how the city is layed out:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;.COM = Main Street, and the shorter your domain is, the closer you are to the center of town&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Popular extensions (the ones you&amp;rsquo;ve probably heard of) like .CO, .NET, .IO, and your country&amp;rsquo;s ccTLD (like .NZ for New Zealand) = other streets near the center of town&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;.PIZZA, .CLUB, and the new gTLDs = the suburbs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like any business, if you&amp;rsquo;re on top of your game, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter where you&amp;rsquo;re located. But at the moment, businesses are thought to be more legitimate if they&amp;rsquo;re not in an obscure location. Legitimacy is a fickle thing though—new domain extensions, like new suburbs, can grow quickly. So don&amp;rsquo;t let the fact that the domain you want in the .COM namespace is taken hold you back from starting a website. (But if you&amp;rsquo;re interested in buying that killer .COM from its current owner, &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/05/the-guide-to-getting-the-right-domain-name-for-your-brand.html&#34;&gt;here&amp;rsquo;s our guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that&amp;rsquo;s perhaps more in your control is what goes before the dot. Here&amp;rsquo;s the basic rule: go with the name of your brand in its simplest form—don&amp;rsquo;t add identifiers that don&amp;rsquo;t belong like &amp;ldquo;buy&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;store&amp;rdquo;. So if your business name is Layshock Limo:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;layshocklimo.com = good
layshock.limo = in the suburbs, but it&amp;rsquo;s short and memorable, which is good
ridelayshocklimo.com = not as good&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Does your domain name have a sketchy past?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technically, you can name your website anything you want, but like all things, names come with histories. Even if you have a sparkling marketing plan, getting unfavorable search results when seeking your site can be a killer. So do your research. Here&amp;rsquo;s a little video guide from Matt Cutts of Google Webmasters on how you can protect yourself from registering domain names with iffy histories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/C-EdhaMDXho&#34; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To recap, here are his three three main tips:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do a &amp;ldquo;site: DOMAINNAME.com&amp;rdquo; search. If you see anything fishy, be weary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Search for the domain name without the domain extension. So instead of &amp;ldquo;site: DOMAINNAME.com&amp;rdquo;, just search for &amp;ldquo;DOMAINNAME.&amp;rdquo; You never know what you might find.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Search for your desired domain on &lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.org/&#34;&gt;archive.org&lt;/a&gt;. If your site used to be a scam site, you could suffer a continued SEO hit. Also note that if your site used to be something you find unsavory, you may get residual unsavory emails.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-2&#34;&gt;Step 2: Choose a website platform&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the complicated part—or what used to be the complicated part. Ten years ago, creating a website meant finding some server space, installing your platform of choice onto that server space, then messing with some combination of a template (which meant a good deal of trial and error, even after learning some rudimentary coding skills) and some plugins until you&amp;rsquo;ve created something you&amp;rsquo;re remotely happy with. E-commerce was always tricky, keeping things updated was always a chore, and if you forgot to backup your site&amp;hellip; kapow! All gone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things today are quite different. In the &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/services&#34;&gt;iwantmyname Marketplace&lt;/a&gt;, we&amp;rsquo;ve cultivated a number of platforms that do it all. The templates are all professionally made and are often able to be changed with simple drag-and-drop interfaces. And they come stock with tools that make online shopping, marketing, and once-difficult tasks like displaying photo galleries and menus as easy as could be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, be sure to do a little research before picking the platform to want to go with. Platforms vary greatly in price, features, and general ease-of-use, so it&amp;rsquo;s important to find what&amp;rsquo;s best for your needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a few to start your search with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/features/applications/custom-domain-apps/websites/squarespace-build-your-website-with-own-url&#34;&gt;Squarespace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter what kind of site you&amp;rsquo;re looking to build, Squarespace has the tools you need. Just to list, they have templates and tools designed for businesses, online shopping sites, physical stores, restaurants (with amazing location and menu features), musicians, podcast hosts (you can serve shows directly from Squarespace to iTunes), photographers, and painters. And they&amp;rsquo;re adding new tools and features all the time, so the platform never gets stale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/features/applications/custom-domain-apps/websites/weebly-create-free-website-with-own-address&#34;&gt;Weebly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Decisions, decisions. In a lot of ways, Weebly is a lot like Squarespace. They have great online shopping solutions, offer simple drag-and-drop tools for website creation, and have some beautiful templates to choose from. Fortunately, you can try both out for free before you decide to plop your money down—so we&amp;rsquo;d recommend that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/services/ecommerce-hosting/big-cartel-custom-domain&#34;&gt;Big Cartel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re an artist, photographer, builder, sewer, or anyone making beautiful goods, Big Cartel is an e-commerce-only solution to check out. Their platform is extremely easy to use (they&amp;rsquo;ve been building it up since 2005), they specialize in showing off independent makers, and they&amp;rsquo;re still small enough to give you some honest personal attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-3&#34;&gt;Step 3: Install your domain to your website&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Easy. As. Pie. When you log in and look at your domains, you&amp;rsquo;ll see an Apps &amp;amp; Services column to the right of your domains. Just click &amp;ldquo;Install new service,&amp;rdquo; pick the platform you want, and follow the simple directions (it&amp;rsquo;s pretty much a one-click solution). And that&amp;rsquo;s it! (If you have any trouble though, don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/support&#34;&gt;let us know&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-4&#34;&gt;Step 4: Get a custom email address&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the secret sauce for having a successful small business site. If you&amp;rsquo;re trying to do real business, contacting customers and clients with an @gmail.com, @me.com, or @yahoo.com address is a nightmare for legitimacy. Those are free email services that anyone can sign up and use! (Just think about it—would you be more likely to respond to tim@apple.com or appletim@me.com?) What you need is an email address that&amp;rsquo;s attached to your domain, and it&amp;rsquo;s way easier to setup than you think. Just &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/06/the-guide-to-getting-your-own-custom-email-address.html&#34;&gt;head over to our simple guide&lt;/a&gt; to get started.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 14:49:59 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/09/anyone-can-build-a-small-business-website.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/09/anyone-can-build-a-small-business-website.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>The iwantmyname guide to blogging (and actually owning your content)</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Math is hard. Running a marathon is hard. Writing on the web, no matter what anyone tells you, is not hard. In fact, it&amp;rsquo;s become so easy that you pick up a following writing nothing more than 140 character messages riddled with abbreviated words, hashtags, and @ replies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s hard is writing words that matter. Evergreen content. Posts that, in a decade, people will still be able to read and discuss. This kind of writing requires a bit of planning, a bit of structure, and a willingness to forego the immediate &amp;ldquo;viral-ness&amp;rdquo; of social media—but if you stick with it, you&amp;rsquo;ll have a real collection of content that&amp;rsquo;ll withstand the fickle nature of the social web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-1&#34;&gt;Beware purely social platforms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-2&#34;&gt;Unless you&amp;rsquo;re internet famous, branding is important&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-3&#34;&gt;Choosing the right blog hosting platform&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-4&#34;&gt;Always have an exit plan in mind&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#section-5&#34;&gt;Your domain name matters, but maybe less than you think&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-1&#34;&gt;Beware purely social platforms&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.businessinsider.com/robert-scoble-why-im-still-betting-my-future-on-google-2011-9&#34;&gt;From Robert Scoble, circa 2011:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do you best capture the EMOTION of your time? Blogging? Not for me anymore. Tweeting? Not for me anymore (I will continue being there, mostly to let people who won&amp;rsquo;t leave that system know what I&amp;rsquo;m doing and where I&amp;rsquo;m doing it &amp;mdash; it has turned into a UI for my Facebook and Google behaviors). Facebooking? Yes. I&amp;rsquo;m still there and will be for forseeable future at &lt;a href=&#34;http://facebook.com/robertscoble&#34;&gt;http://facebook.com/robertscoble&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But my hub is Google+.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a past life, Robert Scoble was one of the many go-to industry insiders worth reading. But for most of this decade, he&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;pivoted&amp;rdquo; from blogging to social media to pursue the active engagement social media brings—and has been a pretty vocal advocate for the rest of us doing the same. His results though don&amp;rsquo;t seem all that rewarding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exhibit 1 is his love affair with Google+. He poured years of content into that platform, amassed nearly seven million followers, and is now perhaps the biggest boat on a dried up lake. Google+ is pretty much a dead platform these days, and the content on it might as well not exist. Now, Scoble&amp;rsquo;s primarily on Facebook, posting multiple times a day on a platform known for spotty content delivery unless you&amp;rsquo;re willing to pay to promote it. (On a personal note, our Facebook posts routinely get delivered to only 15% of our audience—hardly something we&amp;rsquo;d like to pour too much time into.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exhibit 2 is his standing on Google Trends, which tracks news headlines over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/media/2015-08-31-scoble-trend.png&#34; alt=&#34;Scoble trend&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not saying there&amp;rsquo;s a one-to-one correlation between his move to social and his flagging popularity (on Google Trends), but from an outsider&amp;rsquo;s perspective, the move certainly doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem like it&amp;rsquo;s helping his newsworthiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-2&#34;&gt;Unless you&#39;re internet famous, branding is important&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the biggest negative with social media is that with it, you&amp;rsquo;re forever tied to the platform you&amp;rsquo;re on. Modern social sites have little-to-no customization (Facebook, Twitter, and Medium look the same no matter what page you&amp;rsquo;re on), their URL structure is almost universally www.platformname.com/username, and they all come with unique baggage. Platform X is for this clique; Platform Y used to be cool until the adults arrived, etc., etc. Really, unless you&amp;rsquo;re internet famous (like Robert Scoble), fighting this uphill branding battle on social media sites seems crazy. Having a blog on a custom domain might not give the immediate gratification of a Facebook Like, but it&amp;rsquo;s still the best way to seem like a person who should be taken seriously on the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus, with a custom domain name, you can &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/06/the-guide-to-getting-your-own-custom-email-address.html&#34;&gt;pair your credible blog with a custom email address&lt;/a&gt; (a big deal if your blog ever gets media attention).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-3&#34;&gt;Choosing the right blog hosting platform&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First off, it&amp;rsquo;s important to know that there is no &lt;em&gt;perfect&lt;/em&gt; blog platform. Every platform will have a different set of pros and cons, so it&amp;rsquo;s important to do a little research to match your needs. Do you like writing in Markdown? Do you want extra site-building features on top of general blogging? Do you want your files to be stored in a Dropbox folder instead of a closed cloud? Is price a concern?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a few options from our &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/services&#34;&gt;Marketplace&lt;/a&gt; to start with, broken down by what they do:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;General website builders (with blog functionality)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/features/applications/custom-domain-apps/websites/squarespace-build-your-website-with-own-url&#34;&gt;Squarespace&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/features/applications/custom-domain-apps/websites/weebly-create-free-website-with-own-address&#34;&gt;Weebly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Blog hosting platforms:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/services/blog-hosting/ghost-custom-domain&#34;&gt;Ghost&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/features/applications/custom-domain-apps/blogs/tumblr-tumblelog-easy-blog-with-own-url&#34;&gt;Tumblr&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/services/blog-hosting/postagon-custom-domain&#34;&gt;Postagon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/services/blog-hosting/posthaven-custom-domain&#34;&gt;Posthaven&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/services/blog-hosting/silvrback-custom-domain&#34;&gt;Silvrback&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;WordPress hosting:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/services/blog-hosting/wpengine-wordpress-custom-domain&#34;&gt;WP Engine&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/services/blog-hosting/register-custom-domain-page.ly&#34;&gt;Page.ly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Based on Dropbox or Evernote (content stays on your computer):&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/services/blog-hosting/postachio&#34;&gt;Postach.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;For developers:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/services/developer/setup-custom-domain-amazon-s3&#34;&gt;Amazon S3&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/services/developer/github-pages-custom-domain&#34;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-4&#34;&gt;Always have an exit plan in mind&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s nice about owning your own domain is that if you don&amp;rsquo;t like the blog platform you&amp;rsquo;re on, you can move without confusing your readers. For example, if you&amp;rsquo;re blogging on Ghost one day, then realize you want to start leveraging your personal brand to start selling things online the next, you can migrate your content to Squarespace without losing your domain. Plus, because you already have a domain and you&amp;rsquo;re not moving to a closed social platform, you won&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about your brand name being taken on the next platform you&amp;rsquo;re headed to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So before you make any platform decision, be sure to look for a solid import/export tool. Make sure you can easily take all your content with you in case you want to jump platforms—and don&amp;rsquo;t compromise. Better and better platforms are coming out all the time, so getting stuck with something you&amp;rsquo;re not happy with is solely on you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-5&#34;&gt;Your domain name matters, but maybe less than you think&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having a killer domain name is a nice thing when you&amp;rsquo;re telling your friends about your site, but as the spread of content moves to social, it matters less now than ever. Remember that while social media isn&amp;rsquo;t great as your primary content bucket, it&amp;rsquo;s definitely good for spreading your content. Articles from your blog might get tweeted, posted, retweeted, commented on, etc., and on social media, the quality of the domain names means a lot less than the quality of the person posting the message (for example, you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t click on an strange site sent from a complete stranger, but you might if it were sent from your best friend).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Social media sharing aside, your primary objective when choosing a domain name is to not look like a spam site. &lt;a href=&#34;https://moz.com/learn/seo/domain&#34;&gt;Here are some simple tips from Moz&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid hyphens. Hyphens detract from credibility and can act as a spam indicator.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Top-level domains (like .com) are the extensions associated with domain names. For best ranking results, avoid uncommon top-level domains (TLDs). Like hyphens, TLDs such as .info, .cc, .ws, and .name are spam indicators.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid domain names longer than 15 characters. Short domain names are easier to remember, easier to share, and have a smaller chance of resulting in typos.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want more of an in-depth look at our thoughts on which TLD you should be using for your site, &lt;a href=&#34;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/06/how-to-pick-the-right-domain-extension.html&#34;&gt;here&amp;rsquo;s the guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2015 13:30:58 UTC</pubDate>
				
					<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/08/the-iwantmyname-guide-to-blogging.html</link>
				
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/08/the-iwantmyname-guide-to-blogging.html</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
