<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>iwantmyname Domain Blog</title>
		<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog</link>
		<atom:link href="https://iwantmyname.com/blog/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Reach an international audience with these 19 country code top-level domains</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;If you’re in the process of starting a new website and want to go with a shorter country domain extension rather than any of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/new-gtld-domain-extensions&quot;&gt;new gTLDs&lt;/a&gt; (or .COM), there&amp;#39;s one thing you should know:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google treats some ccTLDs (such as .tv, .me, etc.) as gTLDs, as we’ve found that users and webmasters frequently see these more generic than country-targeted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/webmasters/answer/1347922?hl=en&quot;&gt;set a geographic target through Google Webmaster Tools&lt;/a&gt;, e.g. use a .co domain and be listed in search results in the United States, Canada or France although it is actually Colombia’s top-level domain. The same is true if you don’t want to target a specific country, i.e. have a .me domain for your personal online profile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But which ones of these so-called gccTLDs (generic country code top-level domains) are the most popular and more likely to be recognized by visitors?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s take a look at Verisign’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.verisigninc.com/assets/domain-name-report-march2015.pdf&quot;&gt;latest domain industry brief&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/assets/images/content/2015-04-21-gcctld-chart.png&quot; alt=&quot;verisign graph&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some ccTLDs, including .tk, .co, .me and .tv are frequently used by registrants and treated by search engines as gTLDs. This chart ranks the zone size of both gTLDs and ccTLDs marketed as gTLDs, as of Dec. 31, 2014, with that classification taken into account. The top 10 largest gTLDs and ccTLDs marketed as gTLDs by zone size were .com, .tk, .net, .org, .info, .biz, .co, .mobi, .me and .tv, as of Dec. 31, 2014, which account for 180.6 million domain name registrations, or 62.8 percent of the total global domain name registrations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we have &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/tk-tokelauan-domain-name-registration-for-tokelau&quot;&gt;.tk&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/co-colombian-domain-name-registration-for-colombia&quot;&gt;.co&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/me-montenegrean-domain-name-registration-for-montenegro&quot;&gt;.me&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/tv-tuvaluan-domain-name-registration-for-tuvalu&quot;&gt;.tv&lt;/a&gt; as the most popular gccTLDs in that list. Not surprising, except .tk which offers free domains—but with certain usage restrictions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other popular ones you may have seen are &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/io-domain-name-registration-for-british-indian-ocean-territory&quot;&gt;.io&lt;/a&gt; for tech sites (which is &lt;a href=&quot;http://hack.ly/articles/the-most-popular-dot-io-domains-2015/&quot;&gt;still on the rise&lt;/a&gt;), &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/fm-domain-name-registration-for-federated-states-of-micronesia&quot;&gt;.fm&lt;/a&gt; for music websites, &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/cc-domain-name-registration-for-cocos-keeling-islands&quot;&gt;.cc&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/ws-samoan-domain-name-registration-for-western-samoa&quot;&gt;.ws&lt;/a&gt; for general use, as well as &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/nu-domain-name-registration-for-niue&quot;&gt;.nu&lt;/a&gt; (popular in Scandinavian countries).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lesser known gccTLDs, but often registered for &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2013/10/what-is-a-domain-hack-and-how-can-i-make-one.html&quot;&gt;domain hacks&lt;/a&gt; because they don’t require any special documentation or local address in the country, are the &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/la-lao-domain-name-registration-for-laos&quot;&gt;.la&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/ms-domain-name-registration-for-montserrat&quot;&gt;.ms&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/ms-domain-name-registration-for-montserrat&quot;&gt;.sc&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/as-samoan-domain-name-registration-for-american-samoa&quot;&gt;.as&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/bz-belizean-domain-name-registration-for-belize&quot;&gt;.bz&lt;/a&gt; suffixes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That leaves us with the remaining geo-targetable domain extensions from Google’s list: .ad, .cd, .dj, .sr, and .su. Unfortunately, we don&amp;#39;t carry these domains because they&amp;#39;re not easy to purchase and maintain, so you&amp;#39;d have to choose another registrar (our friends at &lt;a href=&quot;https://domainr.com&quot;&gt;Domainr&lt;/a&gt; may be able to help with that.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the overall result if we were to rank the ccTLD&amp;#39;s by international popularity, user recognition, and how easy they are to obtain:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Best: .co, .me, .tv&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good: .io, .fm, .ws, .nu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maybe: .la, .ms, .sc, .as, .bz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Average: .ad, .cd, .dj, .sr, .su&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, it also depends on the type of website you are launching, but for businesses you should probably stick to the “best” and “good” categories.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2015 13:51:38 -0700</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/04/reach-an-international-audience-with-these-country-code-top-level-domains.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/04/reach-an-international-audience-with-these-country-code-top-level-domains.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Contacting the owner of a domain you want to buy</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/assets/images/content/2015-04-20-passing-domain.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Passing domain&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We published a fairly extensive series a while back to help you figure out what to do if there&amp;#39;s a domain you want that&amp;#39;s already been registered, or similar issues. Two of the most relevant posts for our purposes here are &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2014/06/domain-already-registered-pt5.html&quot;&gt;Part 5&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2014/06/domain-already-registered-pt6.html&quot;&gt;Part 6&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We didn&amp;#39;t go into a lot of detail about exactly &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; to contact the current owner of a domain that you&amp;#39;re interested in acquiring though. Or what to do if you do manage to get in touch and make an offer. We&amp;#39;ll start with the easy way. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Contacting a registrant - WHOIS lookup&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you go to your favorite &lt;a href=&quot;http://whois.domaintools.com/&quot;&gt;WHOIS lookup site&lt;/a&gt;, you can enter the domain and get the publicly available details of who owns the domain. Be aware that not all WHOIS lookups are official and present accurate information. Also be aware that sometimes registries (like for &lt;a href=&quot;http://nic.io/&quot;&gt;ccTLDs such as .IO&lt;/a&gt;) have their own WHOIS lookups, which may provide different or additional details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ideally you want the registrant contact email address, as the registrant is the domain&amp;#39;s legal owner. gTLDs have four registrant contacts: registrant/owner, admin, technical, and billing. These can all be the same person/organization, or four different ones. Some ccTLDs, like .UK, only have two contacts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Registrant email address considerations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, just finding an email address for the registrant doesn&amp;#39;t guarantee contact. Particularly if someone has owned a domain for a long time, they may not use the email address anymore that they provided for registration. Lots of things can change: leaving school, getting hacked, and changing addresses, or simply upgrading the email hosting you use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, many email clients have stringent spam filtering, and emails from addresses that they&amp;#39;ve never received email from before may not be allowed through automatically. There are lots of articles out there outlining other spam filter triggers. &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.mailchimp.com/most-common-spam-filter-triggers/&quot;&gt;Here&amp;#39;s a good example.&lt;/a&gt; These are good things to be aware of for how you craft your email to the owner of the domain you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people also use WHOIS privacy services, either provided by their registrar (&lt;a href=&quot;https://help.iwantmyname.com/customer/portal/articles/184425&quot;&gt;more information about ours&lt;/a&gt;) or by a third-party service. Sometimes it&amp;#39;s obvious when one of these services is in place. For example, for customers using our new WHOIS privacy service, information for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.whoistrustee.com/&quot;&gt;WhoisTrustee&lt;/a&gt; will be shown instead of a person or organization&amp;#39;s contact information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will be email addresses shown for the contacts when a WHOIS privacy service is in place, but there&amp;#39;s a chance that the registrant cannot receive email sent to them. (For example, if the underlying email address is outdated or the forwarding filters out certain messages.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Registrant is unreachable&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For whatever the reason, it is quite possible the registrant&amp;#39;s contact information is not available for the domain you want. Obviously, this presents a problem. Unfortunately, it&amp;#39;s not necessarily a solveable one. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From time to time people who can&amp;#39;t get contact information for a domain they want contact us to ask us for that information, or to ask us to contact the domain owner for them. We can&amp;#39;t speak for other registrars, but our policy is not to do this. We take customers&amp;#39; privacy very seriously. Additionally, we are not in the brokerage business. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is possible that unless the domain is allowed to expire and is released, you may have no way of acquiring it. In these cases we recommend having some viable alternatives. And make sure you&amp;#39;ve secured a domain name &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; printing signs, business cards, etc. (You&amp;#39;d be surprised how often people don&amp;#39;t do this...)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Domain brokerage&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in having a third party try to contact a domain&amp;#39;s owner for you, we recommend &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sedo.com/us/buy-domains/domain-brokerage/&quot;&gt;Sedo&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://domainagents.com/&quot;&gt;DomainAgents&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What brokerage services will do is contact the domain owner (if they can), then make an offer for the domain for you, handle negotiations, and finalize the agreement to purchase and transfer the domain. In addition to whatever price you pay for the domain, you will also pay a fee to the broker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;You&amp;#39;ve contacted the domain owner... now what?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#39;s up to you, really. First, you need to see if the person is interested in parting with the domain. It&amp;#39;s a good idea, when you&amp;#39;re looking up the WHOIS details, to check the date on which the domain was registered. If someone has had the domain for a decade, there may be pretty good odds that they&amp;#39;re not interested in getting rid of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, it&amp;#39;s possible the person registered the domain hoping to sell it, but the right buyer just hadn&amp;#39;t come along until you did. And, as we&amp;#39;ve previously mentioned, just because there is no website up for the domain doesn&amp;#39;t mean it&amp;#39;s not in use or not wanted. There are a lot of ways to use domains that don&amp;#39;t involve publicly accessible websites. (And even if the domain isn&amp;#39;t being used for anything, no, we (&lt;em&gt;nor any other registrar&lt;/em&gt;) can&amp;#39;t just take it for you.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All you can do is contact the owner and hope they receive the message and reply. If they don&amp;#39;t reply, or they say no, there&amp;#39;s not much you can do. If they are interested, then you have a chance. And typically, if someone is interested in selling a domain, they&amp;#39;ll make it quite easy to contact them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need to know beforehand how much you&amp;#39;re willing to spend on the domain. Some domains are quite reasonable, others very, very expensive. Essentially, the domain is worth what someone is willing to pay for it. Even if the owner says they&amp;#39;re willing to sell, if they want a million dollars and you don&amp;#39;t have or aren&amp;#39;t willing to pay that, then the domain might as well not be for sale at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often, sounding too interested (read: desperate) can make the asking price go up steeply and quickly. And there&amp;#39;s really nothing you can do about it, except walk away. So, again, having a budget and an alternative plan is important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;We&amp;#39;ve come to an agreement... now what?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Congratulations! You&amp;#39;ve managed to contact the domain owner, they were interested in selling, and now you&amp;#39;ve made a deal. How do you actually get the domain? Well, it depends. For gTLDs (e.g. .COM) the transfer process is standardized. &lt;a href=&quot;https://help.iwantmyname.com/customer/portal/articles/1336688&quot;&gt;There&amp;#39;s information on the requirements here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For ccTLDs there can be a lot of variance in what&amp;#39;s required to transfer, so if you have trouble figuring it out or getting started, &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/support&quot;&gt;let us know&lt;/a&gt;. We&amp;#39;re happy to help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the domain owner is an iwantmyname customer and so are you, you can do what&amp;#39;s called &lt;a href=&quot;https://help.iwantmyname.com/customer/portal/articles/184478&quot;&gt;an internal transfer or move.&lt;/a&gt;. (Provided the domain is old enough, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to transfer the domain from the owner&amp;#39;s account at another registrar to your account with iwantmyname, then the owner would unlock the domain, get the transfer auth code, remove any privacy services, and one of you (whomever has the auth code) would initiate the transfer at our website. (That is for gTLDs. As noted, the process may differ somewhat for ccTLDs.) &lt;a href=&quot;https://help.iwantmyname.com/customer/portal/articles/184465&quot;&gt;More information on transferring TO iwantmyname here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the owner is an iwantmyname customer and you want to transfer the domain to your account at another registrar, then the owner would unlock the domain, get the transfer auth code, remove any privacy services, and one of you (whomever has the auth code) would initiate the transfer at the new registrar&amp;#39;s website. &lt;a href=&quot;https://help.iwantmyname.com/customer/portal/articles/184477&quot;&gt;More information on transferring FROM iwantmyname here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Depending on the domain type and registrars involved, transfers can be immediate, or take up to 5 days to complete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, be sure that all payments and other arrangements have been made &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; initiating the transfer. Once a domain has been transferred, it&amp;#39;s likely no longer yours or accessible, and you have no way of getting it back or withholding it to demand payment if you get shafted. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Anything else?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be the legal owner of a domain, your name and/or organization&amp;#39;s name needs to be in the registrant/owner contact details. This information may not automatically change when a domain is transferred. Be sure to check.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At iwantmyname, you can update the registrant contacts for many types of domains in your dashboard, under &lt;em&gt;edit contacts&lt;/em&gt;. If you&amp;#39;re unable to do that, there may be an issue, or we may need to make the update for you, so let us know. If your domain is registered elsewhere, you&amp;#39;ll need to contact that registrar for help updating the details if needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be aware that changing the registrant contact details is often called an &lt;em&gt;owner change&lt;/em&gt;. For some types of domains, this change is considered by registries to be similar to a domain registration, so there may be a fee involved. Some registries also require identification and paperwork to be included. (We can help clarify this as well.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With hundreds of millions of domains registered, there is a pretty good chance that one you want is taken already. If it&amp;#39;s one you really want, you may be fortunate and able to procure it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If not, nowadays at least there are &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/new-gtld-domain-extensions&quot;&gt;hundreds of new TLDs&lt;/a&gt; to choose from to help you come up with just the right alternative. Good luck.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2015 12:21:32 -0700</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/04/contacting-the-owner-of-a-domain-you-want-to-buy.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/04/contacting-the-owner-of-a-domain-you-want-to-buy.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Cool Gary</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/assets/images/content/2015-04-17-gary-cool.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cool Gary&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2015 14:53:32 -0700</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/04/cool-gary.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/04/cool-gary.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Using the iwantmyname Marketplace to find your next blog, personal site, portfolio, or e-commerce platform</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is it useful? If so, how can we make it even &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; useful?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are the questions we&amp;#39;ve been asking a lot of ourselves lately, and they represent what I think is the goal of this vast world we call the internet. Just think of the progression from the pre-internet world to now:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1970&amp;#39;s - You read an album review in a magazine, then drive to the store to buy a record to play at home. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1990&amp;#39;s - You read an album review in a magazine, then drive to the store to buy a CD to play in your car. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2000&amp;#39;s - You read an album review online (quite useful), then download the album to listen on any of your devices (still a chore).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The future - The album you want and all the content around it are integrated. There are no barriers. Listen, discover, and share, instantly. I can&amp;#39;t think of anything more useful than that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#39;s the goal of the internet. Reduce the noise, reduce the work—all so you can instantly get what you want, right when you want it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before starting at iwantmyname, I used iwantmyname for one very specific reason. They had a &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/services&quot;&gt;big collection of platforms&lt;/a&gt; available for me to plug-in to without having to find any DNS instructions. When I think of an idea, the last thing I want to do is figure out how to get the thing I want to use up and running. With iwantmyname, I could start sites on platforms like Squarespace, Virb, and Tumblr in a snap. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what I only subconsciously realized was how much clutter I&amp;#39;d removed from my life. Instead of reading review after review of every new CMS under the sun, I had a place to go that had some cultivation going on. A place where I could quickly check out some of the coolest platforms on the web, and then add them to my domain with just a few clicks. iwantmyname bridged that gap from discovery to creation, and it saved me time. So much time. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/assets/images/content/2015-04-16-iwmn-marketplace.png&quot; alt=&quot;The Marketplace&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to today and we have so many hosted platforms to discover in the iwantmyname &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/services&quot;&gt;Marketplace&lt;/a&gt;. You&amp;#39;ll find big ones like &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/features/applications/custom-domain-apps/websites/squarespace-build-your-website-with-own-url&quot;&gt;Squarespace&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/services/portfolio-hosting/cargo-custom-domain&quot;&gt;Cargo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/features/applications/custom-domain-apps/blogs/tumblr-tumblelog-easy-blog-with-own-url&quot;&gt;Tumblr&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/features/applications/custom-domain-apps/e-commerce/shopify-hosted-online-store-platform-and-shop-software&quot;&gt;Shopify&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/services/ecommerce-hosting/big-cartel-custom-domain&quot;&gt;Big Cartel&lt;/a&gt;, as well as the platforms that tend to fly under the radar (but are still mighty useful) for non-developers, like &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/services/blog-hosting/ghost-custom-domain&quot;&gt;Ghost&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/services/developer/github-pages-custom-domain&quot;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;. Without needing to login or buy anything, you can browse through 100+ platforms, and when you&amp;#39;re ready, you can grab a domain and start creating content in a flash. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s easily one of the fastest ways to go from platform discovery to site creation on the web while still giving you the flexibility to change platforms in the future and add other useful things like &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/services/email-hosting/&quot;&gt;email&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/services/forum-hosting/&quot;&gt;custom forums&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The future of the Marketplace&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we come back to our original question. How can we make our &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/services&quot;&gt;Marketplace&lt;/a&gt; more useful than it is today? A couple weeks ago, the whole team met in Wellington to plan out the future of the site. Plenty of things were discussed, but one of our main focuses was the Marketplace—particularly, what we can do in the future to make it more useful. And the solution (well, at least one of the solutions) was content. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vigorously remove any content doesn&amp;#39;t help people get from point A to point B faster, and put a much larger content focus on the platforms we plug-in to than our own. We already have the tools in place to get you going on a platform, and we already have a large (and growing) selection of platforms available. What we&amp;#39;re missing is the added content needed to remove the initial research barrier. Not editorial, but useful content that breaks down what each platform does, and how their featuresets can uniquely work to bring what&amp;#39;s in your head to life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/assets/images/content/2015-04-16-future-marketplace.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Future Marketplace&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this future Marketplace, you should be able to have a solid idea of what a platform does without having to go searching elsewhere, and hopefully that extra level of information will translate to real time saved. And that&amp;#39;s what we&amp;#39;re after. Saving you time so you can get back to building. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enough about our plans though. Is there anything you&amp;#39;d like to see in the Marketplace to make it more useful? If so, &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/support&quot;&gt;drop us a message&lt;/a&gt;. We&amp;#39;re always open to suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2015 13:32:22 -0700</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/04/using-the-iwantmyname-marketplace-to-find-your-next-blog-personal-site-portfolio-or-e-commerce-platform.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/04/using-the-iwantmyname-marketplace-to-find-your-next-blog-personal-site-portfolio-or-e-commerce-platform.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>The nearly foolproof three-step test for determining the quality of a website</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/assets/images/content/2015-04-15-twitter-logo.png&quot; alt=&quot;Twitter Logos&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 1:&lt;/strong&gt; Go to a website&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 2:&lt;/strong&gt; Find the social icons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 3:&lt;/strong&gt; If the Twitter icon isn&amp;#39;t shaped like the birds above (angled slightly up), you&amp;#39;ve probably found a brand that either doesn&amp;#39;t understand the internet or doesn&amp;#39;t care about details (possibly worse?).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note that there are levels of terribleness here.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/assets/images/content/2015-04-15-twitter-logo-old.png&quot; alt=&quot;Old Twitter Logo&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quality Score -100:&lt;/strong&gt; Definitely the wrong logo, but I can see how someone could see this and not instantly think it&amp;#39;s wrong. If you see something like this on a personal site, politely send an email to the site owner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/assets/images/content/2015-04-15-twitter-logo-older.png&quot; alt=&quot;Older Twitter Logo&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quality Score -4000:&lt;/strong&gt; You know that feeling when you walk into a restaurant with carpet clearly from the 1980&amp;#39;s? &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2015 11:34:36 -0700</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/04/the-nearly-foolproof-three-step-test-for-determining-the-quality-of-a-website.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/04/the-nearly-foolproof-three-step-test-for-determining-the-quality-of-a-website.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Can non-devs be part of the open source community?</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=9307255&quot;&gt;From thomk - Hacker News:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask HN: How do technical non-developers help with open source projects?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used to code for a living but decided that I enjoy being a technical writer and PM much, much more. Things I enjoy:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Writing detailed functional specifications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating wireframes &amp;amp; mockups.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating flowcharts, BPMN docs &amp;amp; graphs to explain a project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Planning Poker, Creating sprints.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discussing technical issues with developers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simplifying technical issues for customers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learning about new technologies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explaining new technology to customers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My question is; Is there a need for someone like me in any open source projects and if so, how do I contribute?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Lenz &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/03/does-open-source-contribute-to-a-more-open-society.html&quot;&gt;recently wrote&lt;/a&gt;, &amp;quot;At iwantmyname, we not only use open-source technologies at the heart of our business, but we also strive to support the cultivation of a community based on the ethics of open source.&amp;quot; But as a non-developer, truly understanding what open source stands for is a hard thing to grasp. Writers, designers, and project managers can make educated guesses, but getting non-devs involved in the world of open source can only mean good things and more well-rounded ideas for the community. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, questions like the Hacker News thread above are definitely a step in the right direction. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 20:08:28 -0700</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/04/can-non-devs-be-part-of-the-open-source-community.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/04/can-non-devs-be-part-of-the-open-source-community.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Does open source contribute to a more open society?</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many companies say they love open source, but what does that actually mean? Does it mean they use a lot of software other people have written? Does it mean they like that they don&amp;#39;t have to pay for things? Or do they understand that &lt;em&gt;loving open source&lt;/em&gt; also means contributing back to the community the code came from?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#39;s start again. We at iwantmyname love open source! And when I say we love open source, I mean that we&amp;#39;re always trying to work and live up to its ethos—to continuously share the things we learn, and to approach challenges with facts instead of emotion. Open-source development is all about learning and developing in the open, with people we may never meet in real life—it doesn&amp;#39;t matter to any of us what we look like, who we are, what our gender is, our race, religious beliefs, or sexual preference. It&amp;#39;s all irrelevant. The only thing that matters is how we can work together to make projects awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having lived in this environment for many years, I&amp;#39;ve started to apply this same thinking to other parts of my life. With less time these days to contribute to actual code, I make efforts to talk at conferences and user groups, and, even more importantly, to grab coffee with people who ask for feedback (or are willing to give feedback) on ideas, architectures, and random happenings. The open source community I&amp;#39;m in has become a very real community, where the people I know can discuss, in the open, critical business-related things without fear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But why the trust? Well, open source also teaches ethics—to be able to work and share with a loose team of contributors. You need a level of trust to have someone you&amp;#39;ve never met in person contribute code to a project, and you need the right thought technology in place to create the expectation of not breaching that trust. If that trust is breached, projects get forked, communities split up, and egos clash until everyone gets back to the hard facts and finds new ways of implementation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At iwantmyname, we not only use open source technologies at the heart of our business, but we also strive to support the cultivation of a community based on the ethics of open-source. We actively do this by working closely with local tech incubators, hosting like-minded user groups and meetups, and sponsoring innovative events like the upcoming &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.opensourceopensociety.com&quot;&gt;OS//OS 2015&lt;/a&gt; conference here in Wellington, which is very much aligned with our core values.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s exciting to be part of a brand that makes such a large impact relative to our size, and I love that we&amp;#39;ve been given the opportunity to be so deeply embedded in what&amp;#39;s going on in New Zealand and the rest of the world.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2015 15:33:41 -0700</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/03/does-open-source-contribute-to-a-more-open-society.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/03/does-open-source-contribute-to-a-more-open-society.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Last chance to get your short .NZ domain before anyone else</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Time is running out, but you still have until 30 March 2015 to either register or reserve the shorter version of your .NZ domain name before anyone else. As you may know, all ‘second level’ domains like the .CO in ‘.CO.NZ’ and the .NET in ‘.NET.NZ’ are now optional, meaning you can register .NZ names with them, without them, or both (you can read more about it on &lt;a href=&quot;http://anyname.nz/&quot;&gt;anyname.nz&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please note that registering or reserving your corresponding .NZ name is entirely optional and will not affect your existing domain. However, it is important to remember that anyone can register domains directly under .NZ after 30 March 2015. For example, if you own the domain myperfectwebsite.CO.NZ and you do not register or reserve myperfectwebsite.NZ, anybody can buy that domain after the pre period ends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside from that little note, have a great weekend! And, as always, please let us know if you &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/support&quot;&gt;have any questions&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2015 14:52:31 -0700</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/03/last-chance-to-get-your-short-nz-domain-before-anyone-else.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/03/last-chance-to-get-your-short-nz-domain-before-anyone-else.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>.green is your new favorite color</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/hpiIWMWWVco&quot; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as colors go, green is a loaded word. It stands for sustainability, political movements, and money. Kermit the Frog feels green. Sick people look a little green. Green is everywhere, and now your favorite color has an online home—&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-green&quot;&gt;.green&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what should people do with it? Here are some suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Political Campaigns&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many countries have a green party, and adding .green to a name, country, or movement slogan could be a nice touch. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;name.green&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;country.green&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vote.green&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Investment Planners&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;d be careful not to be too forward, but if you&amp;#39;re &amp;quot;making green&amp;quot; for people and either have a sense of humor or are pretty blunt, .green could be a funny domain alternative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;investment.green&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;make.green&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;saving.green&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Sustainability&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sustainability is a buzzword that&amp;#39;s here to stay, and &amp;quot;being green&amp;quot; is something more and more people around the world are striving for. So if you&amp;#39;re looking to create a sustainability blog or a green company, .green is a perfect fit. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;COMPANY.green&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;home.green&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tips.green&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;And if you&amp;#39;re Kermit the Frog&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;itsnoteasybeing.green &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2015 15:29:02 -0700</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/03/green-is-your-new-favorite-color.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/03/green-is-your-new-favorite-color.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Is Medium the billionaire’s typewriter?</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://practicaltypography.com/billionaires-typewriter.html&quot;&gt;From Matthew Butterick, in an article titled, &amp;quot;The billionaire’s typewriter&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But un­like the Times, Medium pays for only a small fraction of its stories. The rest are sub­mit­ted—for free—by writ­ers like you. After a long time being elusive about its business model, Medium revealed that it plans to make money by—sur­prise!—sell­ing ad­ver­tis­ing. This means dis­play­ing ads, but also col­lect­ing and sell­ing data about read­ers and writ­ers. So Medium will extract rev­enue from every story, whether it paid for that story or not. (By the way, will that rev­enue be shared with writ­ers? Um, no.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And com­ing full cir­cle—what’s the in­dis­pens­able tool for cre­at­ing this il­lu­sion of an ed­i­to­r­ial ecosystem? The ho­mo­ge­neous de­sign. The but­ter­fly bal­lot of 2000 (de­picted in why ty­pog­ra­phy matters) proved that er­rors of ty­pog­ra­phy can have his­toric con­se­quences. Medium proves that typog­ra­phy can be used as a tool of eco­nomic lever­age and control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In truth, Medium’s main prod­uct is not a pub­lish­ing plat­form, but the pro­mo­tion of a pub­lish­ing platform. This pro­mo­tion brings read­ers and writ­ers onto the site. This, in turn, gen­er­ates the us­age data that’s valu­able to ad­ver­tis­ers. Boiled down, Medium is sim­ply mar­ket­ing in the ser­vice of more mar­ket­ing. It is not a “place for ideas.” It is a place for ad­ver­tis­ers. It is, there­fore, ut­terly superfluous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a writer, the state of writing on the web in 2015 is not good. That&amp;#39;s not to say the tools for writing have dried up (there are more now than ever)—it&amp;#39;s just that now, instead of simply writing, I have all sorts of internal issues. Who owns my content? If I don&amp;#39;t own it, who does? Does it matter? Is &amp;quot;homogeneous design&amp;quot; something I even care about?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here&amp;#39;s where I&amp;#39;m coming from. I have a job that pays the bills, so when I want to get some thoughts into the cloud, I&amp;#39;m not doing it for money, I&amp;#39;m doing it to be a citizen in the communities I care about. As Austin Kleon says in &lt;em&gt;Show Your Work!&lt;/em&gt;, &amp;quot;By generously sharing their ideas and their knowledge, they often gain an audience that they can leverage when they need it—for fellowship, feedback, or patronage.&amp;quot; For that goal, Medium, and social media platforms like Facebook and Twitter, are perfect. Sure, everything you see on the page looks exactly the same—same typography, same basic structure—but it&amp;#39;s an instant way for a writer to connect to, and discover, the people they care about. It&amp;#39;s not that I&amp;#39;m lazy, or that I&amp;#39;m unknowingly trading my freedom to be on some Big Brother marketing platform (the billionaire&amp;#39;s typewriter), I&amp;#39;m just in a place in my life where I&amp;#39;m happy to share my thoughts on a platform someone else has created because they&amp;#39;ve removed all the barriers and invited all my friends. It&amp;#39;s a party I didn&amp;#39;t have to plan... I just had to show up. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Medium, for example, has a CMS that anyone on the planet can use, and a design that certainly doesn&amp;#39;t insult my sensibilities. Call it minimalist, homogeneous, whatever—as a writer, I can get in, write something, and send it off to my friends without worrying if it looks good or not. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My only issue with Medium is that its users are fairly anonymous. If I want to find a writer, I have to figure out what their Medium username is, then toss it to the back of the standard Medium URL. Too often, I&amp;#39;m just cycling through articles without ever knowing who the author is—it&amp;#39;s just a mad shuffle of big ideas and original thoughts from people I might not ever know. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What Medium needs is custom domains.&lt;/strong&gt; I want to be able to tell a friend to check out chrishall.pizza, not medium.com/@hashtaghall. I&amp;#39;m far too Gen X to want to be a blatant &amp;quot;corporate stooge,&amp;quot; but the Millennial in me just needs a little recognition to be appeased. Give me that level of individuality and I could care less if they leverage my writing to make some money. It wasn&amp;#39;t written to be a profit center anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the piece linked above, Matthew Butterick paints a solid picture of why someone like himself shouldn&amp;#39;t use Medium. He, like many, value things like site individuality and varied typography more than I do. And he may have a soapbox with Practical Typography that pays the bills and connects him to more people than I will probably ever know. But I don&amp;#39;t think many people want to blog full-time (it&amp;#39;s harder than many think), and they&amp;#39;d probably do anything to avoid having to make design decisions and worry about server costs. They just want to write somewhere their work will be read. And Medium lets them do that. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2015 12:09:41 -0700</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/03/is-medium-the-billionaires-typewriter.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/03/is-medium-the-billionaires-typewriter.html</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
