<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>iwantmyname Domain Blog</title>
		<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog</link>
		<atom:link href="https://iwantmyname.com/blog/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>New In The Marketplace Quickmvp</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/assets/images/content/2015-02-12-quickmvp.png&quot; alt=&quot;5-Minute Technique&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How many times have you come up with a big idea, spent the money, time, and effort needed to get it going, only to watch it flame out after a few months due to a lack of traction. It&amp;#39;s hard to know how successful an idea will be before launch, but and easy way to find out is with &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/services/marketing/quickmvp&quot;&gt;QuickMVP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;QuickMVP&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;5-Minute Technique&amp;quot; is just about as simple as it sounds. You create a quick landing page that tests the demand for your idea, set up some Google Ads with their built-in ad creator to spread the word, then sit back and see what happens. It sounds ridiculously easy, but the methodology has been used successfully by many of today&amp;#39;s brightest entrepreneurs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#39;s a little case study from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://quickmvp.tumblr.com/post/88837748550/validating-an-ny-times-best-selling-title-with&quot;&gt;QuickMVP blog&lt;/a&gt; about Tim Ferriss&amp;#39; naming of The 4-Hour Workweek:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He bid on keywords related to the book’s content such as ‘401k’ and ‘language learning’: when those keywords formed part of someone’s search on Google the title popped up as a headline and the advertisement text would be the subtitle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ferriss was interested to see which of the advertisements would be clicked on most, knowing that he needed his title to compete with over 200,000 books published in the US each year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the week, for less than $200 Tim discovered that “The 4-Hour Workweek” had by far the best click-through rate. The rest is history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next time you&amp;#39;re in the testing stage of a big idea, keep &lt;a href=&quot;http://quickmvp.com&quot;&gt;QuickMVP&lt;/a&gt; in mind—it&amp;#39;s a bit of a no-brainer. The process isn&amp;#39;t quite free, but anything beats throwing money at an idea that might not be market-ready.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/02/new-in-the-marketplace-quickmvp.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/02/new-in-the-marketplace-quickmvp.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>4 tools for remembering your passwords... a year later</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/assets/images/content/2015-02-11-vault.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Vault&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#39;ve worked hard over the past half-decade making domain registration as easy as possible, but one pain point we often encounter is password memorization. The vast majority of our customers simply don&amp;#39;t need to interact with us very often, and what seems like a strong, easily remembered password could be completely alien when domain renewals come around a year later. But there are solutions for this very problem—all you need is a solid password manager.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#39;s an intro to password managers from &lt;a href=&quot;The%20paranoid%20guide%20to%20digital%20security&quot;&gt;Consumer Reports&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concept is straightforward: You sign up for a service that generates and stores a unique, strong password for each of the websites where you need log-in credentials. You can do that yourself if you have a savant-like memory for numbers, but in all likelihood you don’t. Then, you just need to remember one, excellent password in order to access the service. Yes, you may ask, but what if the password manager gets hacked? Not to worry, says Chris Soghoian. “Password managers encrypt their data, so these services are safe. And, ultimately, in 2015 it’s not a good idea to use the same password for more than one website. That effectively means that you have to outsource the task.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;1Password&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/assets/images/content/2015-02-11-one-password.png&quot; alt=&quot;1Password&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the name suggests, &lt;a href=&quot;https://agilebits.com/onepassword&quot;&gt;1Password&lt;/a&gt; is a tool that acts as a vault for all your passwords, secured by a single password of your creation. Basically, using a browser extension (available for Safari, Firefox, Chrome, and Opera), app, or smartphone app, you can open your vault with your master password and have instant access to all the passwords you&amp;#39;ve created, on any device you happen to be using.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#39;s a little excerpt from an extremely in-depth piece by the Sweet Setup, titled &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thesweetsetup.com/apps/best-password-manager-and-why-you-need-one/&quot;&gt;The best password manager (and why you need one) - 1Password&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, 1Password is the best app for managing your passwords because it does the best job of taking hold of our slippery digital identity, all the myriad digital bits of ourselves we use to prove who we are, and helps ease the friction of our travels through the digital world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#39;s another glowing review from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.macstories.net/reviews/1password-4-for-mac-review/&quot;&gt;MacStories&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every time a new version of 1Password comes out, I feel like repeating myself: if you’re serious about your secure data and web logins, you need 1Password. While it’s a great thing that Apple will be providing native options for increased password security and form-filling with iCloud Keychain, my recommendation still goes to 1Password if you’re looking for a dedicated app with more and better options aimed at managing your passwords, login details, credit card information, software licenses, and more. iCloud Keychain is meant for Safari, whereas 1Password is system-wide, powered by great customizable menus with keyboard shortcuts, and goes beyond web logins to let you encrypt and protect just about anything. I can’t work without 1Password.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;LastPass&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/assets/images/content/2015-02-11-lastpass.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;LastPass&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another good password manager is &lt;a href=&quot;https://lastpass.com&quot;&gt;LastPass&lt;/a&gt;, which works basically the same way 1Password does, but with a few less bells and whistles (although LastPass has been making huge strides), and a cheaper price (there&amp;#39;s a free option!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#39;s a bit from PC Mag&amp;#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pcmag.com/article2/0,2817,2426798,00.asp&quot;&gt;LastPass 3.0 review&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Storing all of your passwords in a single, secure password manager means you can use a different, strong password for every site, without worrying that you&amp;#39;ll forget. It also means that a successful attack on your password stash could give a hacker access to every one of your secure sites. If that thought worries you, the free LastPass 3.0 is just what you need. Your data is stored online in encrypted form that even the company can&amp;#39;t read, and it&amp;#39;s encrypted going to and from your PCs. You can protect your LastPass data with more different kinds of two-factor authentication than any other password manager I&amp;#39;ve encountered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Dashlane&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/assets/images/content/2015-02-11-dashlane.png&quot; alt=&quot;Dashlane&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dashlane.com&quot;&gt;Dashlane&lt;/a&gt; is similar in many ways to the other password managers on the market (if you want details, David Pogue wrote a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2013/06/06/technology/personaltech/too-many-passwords-and-no-way-to-remember-them-until-now.html&quot;&gt;very positive review&lt;/a&gt; in the New York Times, as did &lt;a href=&quot;http://thenextweb.com/apps/2014/12/09/dashlanes-automatic-password-changer-makes-precious-accounts-less-hackable/&quot;&gt;The Next Web&lt;/a&gt; in late 2014), but a new feature dropped in December that makes it extremely enticing. Here&amp;#39;s the description from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theverge.com/2014/12/9/7357251/dashlane-can-now-change-all-your-passwords-with-a-single-click-and&quot;&gt;the Verge&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dashlane, the subscription-based password management service, is introducing a feature today that ought to become standard in every product like it: the ability to change all your passwords with a single click, including accounts with two-factor authentication enabled. The feature will work with about 75 major websites at launch, including Amazon, Apple, Facebook, Google, LinkedIn, PayPal, Pinterest, and Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Password Changer, as the feature is called, is made possible by Dashlane’s acquisition of PassOmatic, a New York startup that developed the core technology. For now, it works on desktop versions of Dashlane for PC and Mac, though the company is working on a mobile version. Dashlane now includes a big green &amp;quot;change all passwords&amp;quot; button; click it, and it will replace your existing passwords with ones that are unique and randomly generated. If you have two-factor authentication enabled, a pop-up will ask you for a code or for the answer to a security question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Safari Passwords&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to avoid the master password thing and just want a simple password storage system, the Safari Password Manager is a pretty nice tool. Basically, when you&amp;#39;re setting up an account online, Safari can auto-generate and save a secure password that will sync via iCloud Keychain for you to use on any device. It&amp;#39;s incredibly easy, but for some, it might be too easy. Here&amp;#39;s a specific pain-point, from the pro-1Password &lt;a href=&quot;http://thesweetsetup.com/apps/best-password-manager-and-why-you-need-one/&quot;&gt;Sweet Setup&lt;/a&gt; article above:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Different people also have different levels of comfort with iCloud Keychain. I, for one, don’t actually love the frictionless experience. I want to be intentional about how I use my passwords and my credit card information, and I like how 1Password makes me conscious of when I’m using those things. I also like how I have more control over access to my information on my devices. I can require a login to 1Password after not using it for even a few minutes. I also like that if my daughter is using my iPad, she can’t easily hop over to Zappos and buy herself a new pair of shoes with my credit card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, practically anything is better than using the same passwords for all your online accounts (or forgetting your clever creations after a week), and without the help of a password manager, that&amp;#39;s almost always what happens. So before you create yet another password you&amp;#39;ll forget, do a little comparison shopping and leave the memorization to the machines. It&amp;#39;ll change your online life forever.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2015 15:34:45 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/02/tools-for-remembering-your-passwords.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/02/tools-for-remembering-your-passwords.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>New in the Marketplace - PodBean, the podcast platform with its own network</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/assets/images/content/2015-02-10-podbean-best-of.png&quot; alt=&quot;Best of&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/services&quot;&gt;App Marketplace&lt;/a&gt; is filled with dozens of great platforms you can add to your domain with just a few clicks (no DNS knowledge required), and in 2015, we’re looking to add a ton more. As we add new platforms to the list, you can get a little taste of what they offer here in the &amp;quot;New in the Marketplace&amp;quot; blog series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the more interesting challenges podcasters face is exposure, and most of the podcast hosting platforms on the market don’t provide much in terms of built-in audiences. &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/services/podcast/podbean&quot;&gt;PodBean&lt;/a&gt; does, and their built-in podcast marketplace has more than 500,000 independent podcasts covering any category you could ever want. And on top of that, PodBean gives you the tools you need to create customizable websites that can instantly ship shows off to all the biggest podcatchers, with options like unlimited bandwidth and storage, a simple platform for creating premium content, and advertising options via third-party networks for additional monetization. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/assets/images/content/2015-02-10-podbean.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;PodBean&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pricing starts at $3/mo, so if you’re looking for a podcast host that does it all, be sure to check out &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.podbean.com&quot;&gt;PodBean&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2015 16:21:18 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/02/new-in-the-marketplace-podbean.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/02/new-in-the-marketplace-podbean.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>The February domain discounts, including .CLUB, .CM, and .IO</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/assets/images/content/2015-02-06-groundhog.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Phil&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s still summer in NZ, but with &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Punxsutawney_Phil&quot;&gt;Punxsutawney Phil&lt;/a&gt; seeing his shadow in on Feb. 2, the US and Canada will have winter chills for at least six more weeks—and chilly bones deserve especially good domain discounts. So this month, .CLUB, one of our most popular new generic top-level domains (gTLDs), is on sale, and we&amp;#39;re hoping to see a bunch of new clubs (Summer.club? Winter.club?) pop up all around the world. And if clubs aren&amp;#39;t your thing, we have 12 other extensions set at great prices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Popular&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/co-colombian-domain-name-registration-for-colombia&quot;&gt;.co&lt;/a&gt; - $15.50 (from $29.90)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/me-montenegrean-domain-name-registration-for-montenegro&quot;&gt;.me&lt;/a&gt; - $19.90 (from $24.90)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-club&quot;&gt;.club&lt;/a&gt; - $15.50 (from $19.90)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/io-domain-name-registration-for-british-indian-ocean-territory&quot;&gt;.io&lt;/a&gt; - $49.00 (from $59.00)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/mobi-domain-name-registration-for-mobile&quot;&gt;.mobi&lt;/a&gt; - $9.90 (from $24.90)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Colors&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-red&quot;&gt;.red&lt;/a&gt; - $15.50 (from $19.90)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-blue&quot;&gt;.blue&lt;/a&gt; - $15.50 (from $19.90)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-pink&quot;&gt;.pink&lt;/a&gt; - $15.50 (from $19.90)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-black&quot;&gt;.black&lt;/a&gt; - $15.50 (from $69.00)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Places&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/cm-cameroonian-domain-name-registration-for-cameroon&quot;&gt;.cm&lt;/a&gt; - $39.00 (from $149.00)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/asia-domain-name-registration-for-asia&quot;&gt;.asia&lt;/a&gt; - $14.90 (from $24.90)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Non-English&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-shiksha&quot;&gt;.shiksha&lt;/a&gt; - $9.90 (from $19.90)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-%E7%A7%BB%E5%8A%A8&quot;&gt;.移动&lt;/a&gt; - $9.90 (from $19.90)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#39;t want to miss a deal? Be sure to check our &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/special-offer&quot;&gt;domain discounts page&lt;/a&gt; at the beginning of each month, or sign up for our new &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/monthly&quot;&gt;monthly newsletter&lt;/a&gt; (our &lt;a href=&quot;http://us1.campaign-archive1.com/?u=54f078a925697a4e5f21c0fbe&amp;amp;id=314e5bfab8&quot;&gt;first edition&lt;/a&gt; will be in inboxes by Monday!). &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2015 14:01:00 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/02/the-february-domain-discounts.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/02/the-february-domain-discounts.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>New in the Marketplace - Bigcommerce, for beautiful online stores</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/assets/images/content/2015-02-05-bigcommerce-main.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bigcommerce&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For many people, e-commerce was the first big draw of the internet. You could go online, pick out things like clothing or electronics, then have the items shipped directly to your house. It was the future. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the first e-commerce sites really weren&amp;#39;t very sophisticated. They were slow, complicated, and pretty walled off from the rest of the internet. Compare that to &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/services/ecommerce-hosting/bigcommerce&quot;&gt;Bigcommerce&lt;/a&gt; and...well, there really isn&amp;#39;t any comparison. With Bigcommerce, you get custom websites, secure carts, digital product catalogs, marketing tools, reporting, mobile-optimized shopping, etc., etc. And their online stores can literally be created by business owners who have no coding or design capabilities whatsoever. It&amp;#39;s truly amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#39;s what the web is saying about Bigcommerce:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.forbes.com/sites/lydiadishman/2014/03/19/why-bigcommerce-says-its-ready-to-take-on-amazon-web-services-to-help-retailers/&quot;&gt;Forbes&lt;/a&gt;: &amp;quot;Stringfellow says that Bigcommerce’s biggest competitive advantage is that it allows any small retailer to scale from its first sale into the millions. “On average a Bigcommerce client generates nearly twice as much revenue as our nearest competitor,” he underscores. Stringfellow also notes that merchants can choose the look and feel of their store via a marketplace of responsive themes. “We are also consistently optimizing the merchant’s store management interface, the website and all client interfaces to ensure we present the most optimal experience.”&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://signalvnoise.com/posts/2727-bootstrapped-profitable-proud-bigcommerce&quot;&gt;Signal v. Noise&lt;/a&gt;: &amp;quot;That desire led to BigCommerce, which is now approaching 10,000 paying customers. According to Harper, the company has grown 480% over the last 4 years and is the fastest growing ecommerce platform in the world. It was ranked the 14th fastest growing software company (#633 overall) on the Inc 5,000 list for 2010 and it now has 50 employees spread between its Sydney, Australia and Austin, Texas offices.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://techcrunch.com/2013/07/25/bigcommerce-raises-40m-from-steve-cases-revolution-growth-to-help-smbs-manage-e-commerce/&quot;&gt;TechCrunch&lt;/a&gt;: &amp;quot;As founders Eddie Machaalani and Mitchell Harper explain, for as little as $25 a month merchants can set up a storefront and make their first sale within 48 hours. As ecommerce continues to grow in an Amazon-dominated world, Bigcommerce wants to be the layer for SMBs to operate a various sales channels. So a merchant could sell on Amazon, and eBay but have Bigcommerce be the platform from which they sell these goods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Bigcommerce is the big equalizer,” Case said of the company. “Now every entrepreneur can have Amazon-like e-commerce capabilities, in hours – not months or years.”&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/kHffh8lvhww&quot; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#39;re serious about creating a world class e-commerce experience, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bigcommerce.com/v18/&quot;&gt;Bigcommerce&lt;/a&gt; is a great place to start. At the time of writing, plans start at $29.95/mo ($26.96/mo if paid annually), and there&amp;#39;s a 15-day free trial to see if the platform is right for you. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2015 12:58:45 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/02/new-in-the-marketplace-bigcommerce.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/02/new-in-the-marketplace-bigcommerce.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>It takes two to make a thing go right - setting up a website with your domain</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually getting your own website with your own domain name online can be a bit like exploring a foreign land. Navigating uncharted territory, trying to decipher unfamiliar language. Creating a web presence is not for the weak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At iwantmyname, we&amp;#39;ve put a lot of work into trying to make that process as painless as possible. And now, with designer &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/01/say-hi-to-the-newest-iwantmynamer-kevin-layshock.html&quot;&gt;Kevin&lt;/a&gt; on board, we&amp;#39;re hoping to make even greater strides in user experience friendliness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing some people still sometimes struggle with, though, is just how to get a website up and running. If only it all happened by magic as soon as your domain was registered!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Understanding web hosting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typically, you can think of the process a bit like setting up a piece of electronics equipment. The cable needs to be plugged into the machine &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; into an electrical outlet. Your domain name needs to be connected to a web platform in our system &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; in the system of your hosting service platform. When setting up your website, you can do these steps in whatever order you choose. I&amp;#39;ll explain in a bit more detail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All websites need a host, somewhere to &amp;quot;live&amp;quot;. Think of your domain name as the address of your house, and the hosting as the actual house the address refers to. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At iwantmyname, we focus on domains and DNS management, so we don&amp;#39;t offer hosting. However, we want it to be as easy as possible for you to set up hosting with whatever provider you choose. That can be done a couple of different ways, depending on your hosting choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Setting up your site with a service platform&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/assets/images/content/2015-02-03-apps.png&quot; alt=&quot;Apps&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can sign up with a service that provides a platform: this includes web hosting &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; the software to create and display your website and its contents. Examples of this include Squarespace, Big Cartel, Zenfolio, or Tumblr. In those cases, you have an account with the service, and set up and make changes to your website in that account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of those platforms make it incredibly easy to set up great-looking sites with little technical know-how. Click on preferred colours, drag and drop how you want things to look, and you&amp;#39;re all set. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you pay just to have an account, sometimes the services are free. Or they can be free for a basic account, and then you pay to scale up the features and flexibility: a &amp;quot;pro&amp;quot; account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of the services in &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/services&quot;&gt;our one-click marketplace&lt;/a&gt; are that kind. They provide the hosting and platform for your blog, portfolio, online store, etc. Clicking that green &lt;strong&gt;Install&lt;/strong&gt; button adds DNS records for your domain in your iwantmyname dashboard. Those DNS records connect your domain name to your account and site with the service platform. That&amp;#39;s half the battle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Verifying your domain name&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some services require you to verify your domain ownership in their system for security purposes. In those cases you&amp;#39;ll likely have to add another DNS record that contains a unique code, which the service checks for. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You get the code from the other service (Squarespace and Google Apps are good examples) and add a CNAME or or TXT record containing the code, then save the new settings. Where we can, we ask you for that code in our one-click setup, and add that extra record for you. The screenshot below shows the one-click setup for Squarespace. (You can see an example of instructions on how to get the verification code &lt;a href=&quot;http://help.squarespace.com/guides/domain-mapping-with-iwantmyname&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/assets/images/content/2015-02-03-squarespace-verification.png&quot; alt=&quot;Squarespace verification&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the settings have some time to propagate around the Internet (a few hours is plenty of time, usually), you can verify ownership in your account with the platform service. Often you can do this by just entering your domain name in your account there and clicking a button. These services generally have excellent documentation to explain where and how to complete that. But if you have questions, &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/support&quot;&gt;we&amp;#39;re happy to help, too&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This verification is often the biggest part of setting up your domain with the other service. When verification isn&amp;#39;t needed, it&amp;#39;s often as simple as logging in to your account on that platform, adding your domain name in your account, and saving the new settings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where possible, when you finish setting up the DNS records you need in our system, we try to send you to the other site to complete the setup there, too. Once setup is done on both ends and the new settings have time to propagate around the Internet — voila! — you have your new website! (If there&amp;#39;s a snag, &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/support&quot;&gt;we&amp;#39;re here to help&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Setting up your site with third-party hosting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Web hosting can also be provided by a third-party hosting service, on which your website&amp;#39;s files reside. Those services generally only provide hosting, and not the software to create your website or email accounts. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/features/domains/web-hosting&quot;&gt;Our recommended hosting partners are Bluehost and Digital Ocean&lt;/a&gt;, which provide only the hosting. Then you can use whatever software and services you like. WordPress is also a popular option, though it provides both the hosting and the software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you use external web hosting, you connect your domain to the hosting account by adding their nameservers in your iwantmyname dashboard. Using external nameservers is kind of like having your mail forwarded after you move. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/assets/images/content/2015-02-03-nameserver-options.png&quot; alt=&quot;Nameservers&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In your iwantmyname account dashboard, on the nameserver update page, there&amp;#39;s a drop-down list of many popular hosting providers. Clicking on the one with which you have an account will automatically fill in their nameservers. Then you just have to save the new settings. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, you can get the nameservers from your hosting company (or set up your own, if you&amp;#39;re techy) and add them. They often look something like this: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ns1.domainhosting.com&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ns2.domainhosting.com&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you use external web hosting, there is one important thing to remember, which is that you then have to set up any DNS records in your web hosting account, &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; in your iwantmyname account. Our DNS management dashboard can only work when our nameservers are in place. If there&amp;#39;s any trouble with the DNS records, we can&amp;#39;t access or see them in your hosting account, so you&amp;#39;d need to ask your hosting provider for help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When setting up your website with a domain name you have registered with us, you will only have to set things up in one of these two ways: either adding DNS records to a service platform, or updating nameservers for an external web hosting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is possible to set up more than one service platform in your iwantmyname account. For example, if you would like to set up a website and email accounts. Or have an online store and a blog. &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/support&quot;&gt;Feel free to get in touch&lt;/a&gt; if you have questions about how to do any of these things.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2015 11:55:04 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/02/setting-up-a-website.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/02/setting-up-a-website.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Meet the domain extensions of February, including .work, .delivery, and .yoga</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/assets/images/content/2015-02-02-business.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;work&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generic top-level domain (gTLD) launches have gotten off to a bit of a slow start in 2015, but the overall stats are looking more impressive by the day. According to &lt;a href=&quot;https://ntldstats.com&quot;&gt;ntldstats.com&lt;/a&gt;, there are now 4,121,213 new gTLDs registered (a nearly 400,000 jump from Jan 1), and &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/new-gtld-domain-extensions&quot;&gt;so many options to choose from&lt;/a&gt;—there&amp;#39;s literally never been a better time than today to get a unique domain with your brand name. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This month, we have eight new domain extensions, including .yoga, .work, and .energy. It&amp;#39;s hard to predict individual TLD popularity because of the abundant options available, but some industry specific options (like .delivery for home delivery startups) have done pretty well in niche markets. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Feb 10&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-casa&quot;&gt;.casa&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-work&quot;&gt;.work&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Feb 11&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-delivery&quot;&gt;.delivery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-energy&quot;&gt;.energy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Feb 17&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-cricket&quot;&gt;.cricket&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-party&quot;&gt;.party&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-yoga&quot;&gt;.yoga&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Feb 24&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-science&quot;&gt;.science&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the full list of the gTLDs coming out (now updated through March 11th), be sure to visit our &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/new-gtld-launch-dates&quot;&gt;launch calendar&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2015 12:45:54 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/02/meet-the-domain-extensions-of-february.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/02/meet-the-domain-extensions-of-february.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>New in the Marketplace - Simplecast, podcast hosting made easy</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/assets/images/content/2015-01-30-simplecast.png&quot; alt=&quot;Simplecast&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Our &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/services&quot;&gt;App Marketplace&lt;/a&gt; is filled with dozens of great platforms you can add to your domain with just a few clicks (no DNS knowledge required), and in 2015, we’re looking to add a ton more. As we add new platforms to the list, you can get a little taste of what they offer here in the &amp;quot;New in the Marketplace&amp;quot; blog series.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ladies and gentleman, podcasts are a thing now, and real people are listening to them. What was once a tiny community of hobbyists and public radio hosts is now an industry with hit shows being covered by national publications. But what makes podcasting magic is that there&amp;#39;s virtually nothing stopping you from starting your own show and building an audience—all you need is a half-decent mic, a quiet room, and some simple editing software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest hangup I&amp;#39;ve seen lately though is hosting. Once you create your show and record some episodes, how do you get them online (and then to podcatchers like iTunes, Stitcher, and Overcast)? Well, if you&amp;#39;re looking for a hassle-free solution, &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/services/podcast/simplecast&quot;&gt;Simplecast&lt;/a&gt; just might be perfect. With Simplecast, you get unlimited storage and a one-step file importer to build clean sites (using templates or your own design), collaboration tools to facilitate your future team (you know, for when you get big), and easy-to-understand metrics for seeing how you&amp;#39;re doing. It&amp;#39;s all pretty painless, giving you all the energy you need to post your show on a consistent schedule. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/assets/images/content/2015-01-30-simplecast-analytics.png&quot; alt=&quot;Analytics&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m not usually one to read too much into &lt;a href=&quot;https://simplecast.fm/about&quot;&gt;About&lt;/a&gt; page copy, but the message of simplicity on the Simplecast site really rings true:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story behind Simplecast is as simple as the platform itself…we needed it. After publishing multiple podcasts, the same issues kept popping up and we kept saying to ourselves that publishing podcasts had to be easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Podcasting is still pretty young as a platform and we hope to keep building a solid product that makes it easier for all of us. We asked ourselves what we would want in a podcasting platform and it was simple: try it out for free, don&amp;#39;t limit bandwidth, manage everything in one place, get only the stats we need, allow multiple podcasts per account, and have a player that is easy to use and distribute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to try it out, &lt;a href=&quot;https://simplecast.fm&quot;&gt;Simplecast&lt;/a&gt; has a 14-day free trial, then is $12/mo (or $120/yr). Now I know there are a few free solutions out there for podcast hosting, but you often get what you pay for. Here&amp;#39;s a tweet I often refer to from Merlin Mann (podcast extraordinaire):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just went to listen to a podcast hosted on Soundcloud and it added an extra-extra preroll ad.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Guys. Hosting&amp;#39;s cheap. Have a little dignity.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Merlin Mann (@hotdogsladies) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hotdogsladies/status/549423128355426304&quot;&gt;December 29, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 14:30:07 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/01/new-in-the-marketplace-simplecast.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/01/new-in-the-marketplace-simplecast.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>New in the Marketplace - Webflow, a drag-and-drop site builder for modern websites</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/assets/images/content/2015-01-29-webflow-moving.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Webflow gif&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Our &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/services&quot;&gt;App Marketplace&lt;/a&gt; is filled with dozens of great platforms you can add to your domain with just a few clicks (no DNS knowledge required), and in 2015, we’re looking to add a ton more. As we add new platforms to the list, you can get a little taste of what they offer here in the &amp;quot;New in the Marketplace&amp;quot; blog series.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems like every website builder has some sort of drag-and-drop feature these days, but the functionality is never quite what you think it will be. There are often limitations, and the dragging and dropping is often limited to template locations and conventional ideas. With &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/services/website-builder/webflow&quot;&gt;Webflow&lt;/a&gt; though, you really can tinker to your heart’s desire—it’s almost like a modern rethinking of Dreamweaver, but fully hosted and not tied to a Creative Cloud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s what others are saying:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://techcrunch.com/2014/03/11/responsive-website-builder-webflow-raises-1-5-million-from-khosla-tim-draper-others/&quot;&gt;TechCrunch&lt;/a&gt;: &amp;quot;Today, Webflow lets designers build responsive websites using a drag-and-drop website builder with an intuitive interface in order to customize their site with common web elements, like sliders, maps, buttons, divs, videos, social widgets, and more. On the backend, Webflow generates W3C-compliant HTML5 and CSS3 code. There aren’t many competitors for a service like this, beyond to some extent, Bootstrap, Foundation or Adobe’s Edge Reflow – but those require more a more advanced skill set to use.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.smashingmagazine.com/2014/08/05/designing-responsive-websites-browser-webflow/&quot;&gt;Smashing Magazine&lt;/a&gt;: &amp;quot;Webflow is a tool targeted at designers who are looking for an alternative to Photoshop and Fireworks for responsive web design. It’s not an all-encompassing solution for creating websites — at least not yet — but by enabling me to focus on layout, interaction and content behavior without having to code, it sped up our team’s design phase immensely.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.forbes.com/sites/alextaub/2014/05/08/webflow-lets-designers-create-websites-without-learning-to-code/&quot;&gt;Forbes&lt;/a&gt;: &amp;quot;Webflow’s vision is to do the same thing for web design as tools like Blogger and WordPress did for personal publishing. Those tools completely took down technical barriers (previously you had to be a master of HTML and FTP to get your thoughts online) and opened up the world of publishing to orders of a magnitude of more people, and in the process transformed the web. Similarly, web design currently requires designers to be masters of HTML, CSS and JavaScript, but the change is inevitable and Webflow plans to lead the charge.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/assets/images/content/2015-01-29-webflow.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Webflow&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a designer who knows what you want, but doesn’t have the time to get your hands too dirty in the dev world, &lt;a href=&quot;https://webflow.com&quot;&gt;Webflow&lt;/a&gt; just might be your next killer tool. Best of all, the platform has a free tier to get started on, and a ton (seriously, a lot) of short &lt;a href=&quot;http://tutorials.webflow.com&quot;&gt;tutorial videos&lt;/a&gt; to help you learn the platform. Give it a go, we think you&amp;#39;ll like it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2015 12:00:27 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/01/new-in-the-marketplace-webflow.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/01/new-in-the-marketplace-webflow.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>New in the Marketplace - Muut, a reimagined forum/commenting platform</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/assets/images/content/2015-01-28-muut-acion.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Muut Action&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Our &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/services&quot;&gt;App Marketplace&lt;/a&gt; is filled with dozens of great platforms you can add to your domain with just a few clicks (no DNS knowledge required), and in 2015, we’re looking to add a ton more. As we add new platforms to the list, you can get a little taste of what they offer here in the New in the Marketplace blog series.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting a blog is quite the endeavor. It’s a commitment to consistent writing, creative thinking, and unending doubt as to whether or not you’re hitting your goals. But one think blog creators often overlook is the means for audiences to have conversations around your work. Too often, the commenting/forum tools used look like they were created in the late 90s, and often function in ways that discourage natural thought processes—and that’s something &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/services/forum-hosting/muut&quot;&gt;Muut&lt;/a&gt; is trying to change. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a bit from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://muut.com/manifesto/&quot;&gt;Muut Manifesto&lt;/a&gt; (I always like a good manifesto):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Muut is a radically different discussion platform that can be embedded on any website. It is unencumbered by the weight of unnecessary features and distractions, and places the conversation back to the forefront.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A clean user interface, persistent content and a deep integration to the site will allow a more natural and meaningful discussion to take place, and enable people to focus on topics they care about. It’s a lightweight, super fast, and responsive platform that places minimal strain on data bandwidth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re on an important mission. A proper forums and commenting system will increase traffic on any given website, and the audience will stay longer. There is no sane reason not to have forums or commenting on a website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/assets/images/content/2015-01-28-forum-placement.png&quot; alt=&quot;muut placement options&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, Muut is a clean, embeddable, customizable (no iframes), crawlable, responsive, realtime, worry-free conversation platform for your site. And best of all, you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://muut.com/pricing/&quot;&gt;try it out&lt;/a&gt; (for an unlimited amount of time, with unlimited bandwidth, users, and data… just a few limited features) for free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Here&amp;#39;s a little something extra if you&amp;#39;re looking to sign up. Use &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.anrdoezrs.net/click-3194335-12097132&quot;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt; and enter promo code MUUT20 by March 1, 2015 to get 20% off.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2015 12:19:52 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/01/new-in-the-marketplace-muut.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/01/new-in-the-marketplace-muut.html</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
