<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>iwantmyname Domain Blog</title>
		<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog</link>
		<atom:link href="https://iwantmyname.com/blog/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>SEO penalties of moving our blog to a subdomain</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me start this article by confessing that we’re not SEO gurus at iwantmyname. Everything we&amp;#39;ve done in the last few years in terms of SEO was done with a basic understanding of the topic and by providing a good product with relevant content and landing pages. This always served us well and we were happy with our rankings overall. With that out of the way, I’d like to tell you about our experience with switching our blog to a subdomain. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the very beginning of July last year, we moved our blog from a subdirectory URL (&lt;code&gt;iwantmyname.com/blog&lt;/code&gt;) to a subdomain (&lt;code&gt;blog.iwantmyname.com&lt;/code&gt;) for better maintainability and performance with GitHub Pages&amp;#39; &lt;abbr title=&quot;content delivery network&quot;&gt;CDN&lt;/abbr&gt; and future-proofing in case we wanted to switch to a different platform down the road. We made this decision after doing lots of research and had long discussions about how it might impact our search engine rankings, but we ultimately agreed to make the change. After all, it was 2014 and Google should be clever enough that it wouldn’t make any difference because they know the blog (subdomain or not) is part of iwantmyname, right? As Matt Cutts said &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_MswMYk05tk&quot;&gt;in one of his webmaster videos&lt;/a&gt; “it’s a question which one is easier for you and whichever one makes you happier I would go and do it that way”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we expected an initial hit after making the subdomain switch and traffic slowly recovering, the turnaround didn’t happen after 6 months, as you can see in the following example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/assets/images/content/2015-01-16-blog-traffic-subdomain-switch.png&quot; alt=&quot;Blog traffic after switch to subdomain&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From what we can tell, we did everything by the books with &lt;code&gt;301&lt;/code&gt; redirects for all URLs - so what happened? Could it have been just coincidence that Google updated their algorithm and we got penalized for some reason?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One signal that Google introduced one month after us making the switch was to give SSL-secured sites a little ranking boost. Since &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/iwantmyname/blog&quot;&gt;our blog is running on GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;, which &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/isaacs/github/issues/156&quot;&gt;doesn’t currently support HTTPS&lt;/a&gt;, could that have prevented the traffic from recovering? Certainly it can’t be that much of a ranking signal—although they mentioned it would increase in importance over time?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So after waiting for six months, we reverted the change and switched our blog back to the previous &lt;code&gt;/blog&lt;/code&gt; subdirectory. It’s still hosted on GitHub Pages and we’re using a simple Nginx proxy to show the content under &lt;code&gt;iwantmyname.com/blog&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;location = /blog {
  # GitHub Pages doesn&amp;#39;t redirect this properly, so we&amp;#39;ll handle it
  return 301 /blog/;
}

# ^~ to allow /blog/ to match before our other regex locations
location ^~ /blog/ {
  proxy_pass https://iwantmyname.github.io;
  proxy_intercept_errors on;
  # serve custom 404 page from our blog repo instead of GitHub Pages&amp;#39; 404
  error_page  404  /blog/404.html;
  # allow GitHub to pass caching headers instead of using our own
  expires off;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An important side effect is that our blog pages are now secured under our primary SSL certificate again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on this experience and the following &lt;a href=&quot;http://moz.com/community/q/moz-s-official-stance-on-subdomain-vs-subfolder-does-it-need-updating#reply_217479&quot;&gt;recommendation from Moz’s Rand Fishkin&lt;/a&gt;, we decided it would be better for our long-term SEO strategy to put our blog back on our primary domain:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would still strongly urge folks to keep all content on a single subdomain. We recently were able to test this using a subdomain on Moz itself (when moving our beginner&amp;#39;s guide to SEO from guides.moz.com to the current URL http://moz.com/beginners-guide-to-seo). The results were astounding - rankings rose dramatically across the board for every keyword we tracked to the pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will certainly keep a close eye on traffic for the next few months and keep you updated. Hope this helps some of you when deciding on the age-old debate of whether you should have your blog on a subdomain or not!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2015 15:53:45 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/01/seo-penalties-of-moving-our-blog-to-a-subdomain.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/01/seo-penalties-of-moving-our-blog-to-a-subdomain.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>New gTLDs and SEO performance</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.circleid.com/posts/20150112_new_gtlds_show_promising_seo_performance/&quot;&gt;From Roland LaPlante - CircleID:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the arrival of hundreds of new generic top-level domains (gTLDs), many marketers are excited that they can now get a web address that best describes their business or brand. For instance, a company in the organic business can now get a web address on .ORGANIC, or a brand that&amp;#39;s all about passion and excitement can now get on .RED, etc. At the same time, many are also asking some important SEO related questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will Google crawl new gTLDs?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will new gTLDs automatically score higher in Google&amp;#39;s search algorithms?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the SEO best practices for migrating a site to a new gTLD?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Should brands REALLY get on new gTLDs and give up the status quo?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#39;s address them one by one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2015 15:32:01 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/01/new-gtlds-and-seo-performance.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/01/new-gtlds-and-seo-performance.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Say hi to the newest iwantmynamer, Kevin Layshock</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;With 2015 now in full swing, we&amp;#39;d like to announce our newest addition—Kevin Layshock. Over the course of the next year (decade(s)?), he&amp;#39;ll be designing his way around the iwantmyname universe, buttoning up the website, redesigning our emails, improving our branding, and generally making everything a bit more friendly and usable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to say hi, you can find him on Twitter &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/couthmonger&quot;&gt;@couthmonger&lt;/a&gt;. Conversation starters include: interesting UI/UX design, contemporary art, beautiful lettering, comic books, podcasts, good movies (only good ones), coffee, and of course, tasty beverages.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2015 13:30:05 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/01/say-hi-to-the-newest-iwantmynamer-kevin-layshock.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/01/say-hi-to-the-newest-iwantmynamer-kevin-layshock.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>How to use a standard Gmail account for free custom domain email</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://simplyian.com/2015/01/07/Hacking-GMail-to-use-custom-domains-for-free/&quot;&gt;From Ian Macalinao:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s pretty much common knowledge that GMail is awesome. It’s fast, connects seamlessly with the rest of your Google services such as Drive, has a cool app called Inbox, and is overall an extremely powerful email service. However, to use it with a custom domain, you need to purchase Google Apps for either $5 or $10/month, which for casual users is a bit unnecessary. On top of that, you don’t even get all of the features a personal account gets, e.g. Inbox.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there’s a free way to use your GMail account with a custom domain: Mailgun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Neat trick for more advanced users to set up custom domain email using a standard Gmail account and &lt;a href=&quot;http://mailgun.com&quot;&gt;Mailgun&lt;/a&gt; (for up to 10,000 emails a month). &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2014/06/yes-you-can-still-get-free-custom-email-addresses.html&quot;&gt;Yes, you can still get free custom domain email addresses&lt;/a&gt; — even in 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2015 18:25:06 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/01/how-to-use-a-standard-gmail-account-for-free-custom-domain-email.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/01/how-to-use-a-standard-gmail-account-for-free-custom-domain-email.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Doing is almost always more important than worrying</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thenameinspector.com/weird-startup-names-of-2014/&quot;&gt;From The Name Inspector:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Name Inspector has been reflecting on last year’s startup names while sipping on what’s left of the apple peel bourbon he made for the holidays. He’s got to say, it seems like some of these companies were named by people who sipped lots of bourbon. Here are some weird names of startups in CrunchBase that were founded in 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember when Nirvana (the band) first started getting played on the radio. Most of my friends were really into the music, but all I could think was “I’m pretty sure I have what it takes to sing incomprehensible lyrics, too! I’m definitely going to be a rock star.” And sure, naming your brand is a whole lot different than singing songs, but the message is similar—extreme talent aside, Nirvana was a success because they actually made music. I wasn’t because I was too worried about everything to ever get on stage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I’m trying to say, and what a lot of the startups mentioned in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thenameinspector.com/weird-startup-names-of-2014/&quot;&gt;the article&lt;/a&gt; prove, is that you shouldn’t let branding uncertainty (or even wackiness) prevent you from doing what you want to do. Sure, maybe you think it’s a mistake to name a brand &lt;em&gt;AssessUp&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;KeeeWeee&lt;/em&gt;, but look at all these brands. They exist...they’re real companies with profiles on CrunchBase! You just never know what might become the next big household brand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In many ways, that same thought process also works for domain extensions. I talk to people all the time who spend a lot of energy worrying about not getting the perfect .com, but the world is changing, and people’s comfort level with “strange” non-.com’s is growing by the day. If what you’re creating is good, people will find you wherever you’re at—.io, .co, your local country code top-level domain (ccTLD), or any of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/new-gtld-domain-extensions&quot;&gt;new domain extensions&lt;/a&gt; on the market. Just go with the domain that fits your brand best—the rest will often work itself out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2015 15:16:06 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/01/doing-is-almost-always-more-important-than-worrying.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/01/doing-is-almost-always-more-important-than-worrying.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>The January domain discounts, including .Vegas and .Asia</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s a new year, so let&amp;#39;s talk a bit about domain discounts. This month, we have a host of sales carrying over from December, plus two location-based TLDs moonlighting as cultural favorites. .Vegas, hailing from the US city of Las Vegas, is synonymous on the web (and elsewhere) with gambling culture, and will likely draw interest with gaming sites and travel microsites. And .Asia, the world&amp;#39;s largest continent, is attempting to bring online nations together for business and trade. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take a look at 2015&amp;#39;s first domain discount list, and start the new year right with a shiny new online space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;New this month&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-asia&quot;&gt;.asia&lt;/a&gt; - $14.90/yr (from $24.90)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-vegas&quot;&gt;.vegas&lt;/a&gt; - $24.90/yr (from $79.00)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Continued from last month&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-black&quot;&gt;.black&lt;/a&gt; - $9.90/yr (from $69.00)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-blue&quot;&gt;.blue&lt;/a&gt; - $9.90/yr (from $19.90)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-co&quot;&gt;.co&lt;/a&gt; - $15.50/yr (from $29.90)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-io&quot;&gt;.io&lt;/a&gt; - $49.00/yr (from $59.00)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-me&quot;&gt;.me&lt;/a&gt; - $19.90/yr (from $24.90)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-mobi&quot;&gt;.mobi&lt;/a&gt; - $9.90/yr (from $24.90)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-ninja&quot;&gt;.ninja&lt;/a&gt; - $15.50/yr (from $24.90)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-pink&quot;&gt;.pink&lt;/a&gt; - $9.90/yr (from $19.90)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-red&quot;&gt;.red&lt;/a&gt; - $9.90/yr (from $19.90)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-reviews&quot;&gt;.reviews&lt;/a&gt; - $19.00/yr (from $29.00)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-rocks&quot;&gt;.rocks&lt;/a&gt; - $15.50/yr (from $19.00)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-shiksha&quot;&gt;.shiksha&lt;/a&gt; - $9.90/yr (from 19.00)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-social&quot;&gt;.social&lt;/a&gt; - $22.50/yr (from $39.00)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-%E7%A7%BB%E5%8A%A8&quot;&gt;移动&lt;/a&gt; - $9.90/yr (from $19.90)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#39;t want to miss a deal? Be sure to check our &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/special-offer&quot;&gt;domain discounts page&lt;/a&gt; at the beginning of each month for the full list of what we have for sale. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 08:21:47 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/01/the-january-domain-discounts.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/01/the-january-domain-discounts.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Meet the domain extensions of January (2015!), including .degree, .space, and .band</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2014 is done, folks. Our new gTLD catalogue is now filled with &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/new-gtld-domain-extensions&quot;&gt;257 new generic top-level domains (gTLDs)&lt;/a&gt;, including the ever-popular &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-club&quot;&gt;.club&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-link&quot;&gt;.link&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-guru&quot;&gt;.guru&lt;/a&gt; (and of course, &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-kiwi&quot;&gt;.kiwi&lt;/a&gt;), and we have a ton more to come in 2015. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the big question...has the new gTLD launch been a success? Well, it depends what your metric is. .Xyz recently hit the 750,000 domains registered mark, making it the most registered new gTLD out there, and as Peter Roesler of Inc. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.inc.com/peter-roesler/will-new-top-level-domains-matter-in-2015.html&quot;&gt;put it&lt;/a&gt;, &amp;quot;If you want to use one of the new TLDs to build a site with an easy-to-remember name, you won&amp;#39;t be disappointed&amp;quot;. Sure, the registration numbers aren&amp;#39;t to the level of .com yet, but I think any gTLD registry owner would tell you it&amp;#39;s a marathon, not a sprint. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2015, I&amp;#39;d expect to see steady gTLD growth as more people become aware of their existence (if the general public knew about the glorious &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-pizza&quot;&gt;.pizza&lt;/a&gt; extension, we&amp;#39;d see an online pizza renaissance for sure). And with another year of new launches, paired with the ever-dwindling supply of good remaining .coms, the growth might be faster than people expect. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prognostication aside, we have a big year of gTLDs ahead of us, and it all begins with the 11 new extensions we&amp;#39;re launching this month. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;January 14&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-degree&quot;&gt;.degree&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-gives&quot;&gt;.gives&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-world&quot;&gt;.world&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;January 20&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-brussels&quot;&gt;.brussels&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-vlaanderen&quot;&gt;.vlaanderen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;January 21&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-forsale&quot;&gt;.forsale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;January 28&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-band&quot;&gt;.band&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-how&quot;&gt;.how&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-rip&quot;&gt;.rip&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-ryukyu&quot;&gt;.ryukyu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-space&quot;&gt;.space&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the full list of the gTLDs coming out (now updated through March 11th), be sure to visit our &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/new-gtld-launch-dates&quot;&gt;launch calendar&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 14:25:30 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/01/meet-the-domain-extensions-of-january.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/01/meet-the-domain-extensions-of-january.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Reply All covers Longform.org’s attempt to buy their corresponding .com</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve never resold or purchased a domain on an aftermarket in my life, but hearing stories about that side of the domain industry is vastly entertaining. There’s intrigue, secret internet dealings, big characters, big egos—it’s all there. And this week, one of my favorite new podcasts, Reply All, covered Longform.org’s attempt to purchase their corresponding .com from Michael Berkens, reseller extraordinaire and founder of The Domains. It’s a good one—give it a listen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Just a heads up...if you’re easily offended, there are a couple curse words in this episode. Nothing big, but they’re there.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/183982208&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=true&amp;amp;show_comments=false&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;visual=true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2015 11:35:28 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/01/reply-all-covers-longform-orgs-attempt-to-buy-their-corresponding-com.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/01/reply-all-covers-longform-orgs-attempt-to-buy-their-corresponding-com.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Last minute Christmas gift idea: register a personal domain for your friends or family</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;We all know the rush for the last few presents a couple of days before Christmas. But why should you go to overcrowded shopping centers when you can shop online? With iWantMyName you don&amp;#39;t even have to be afraid that it&amp;#39;s not delivered on time. It&amp;#39;s the 24th already? No worries, just &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/&quot;&gt;search for a domain name&lt;/a&gt; and you&amp;#39;ll have it within a couple of minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buying a personal domain name for your friends or relatives is the perfect Christmas gift. Here are some ideas to find a good name:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  Get a .COM or .ME with first name (middle name) last name, e.g. &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/search/?domain=SantaNicholasClaus.com&quot;&gt;SantaNicholasClaus.com&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/search/?domain=SantaNClaus.com&quot;&gt;SantaNClaus.com&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/search/?domain=HolySantaClaus.me&quot;&gt;HolySantaClaus.me&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/search/?domain=HolySClaus.me&quot;&gt;HolySClaus.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  Be creative with a &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain_hack&quot;&gt;domain hack&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/search/?domain=NicholasCla.us&quot;&gt;NicholasCla.us&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/search/?domain=SantaLives.in&quot;&gt;SantaLives.in&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  Register the Christmas domain .CX: &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/search/?domain=SantaAndTheReindeer.cx&quot;&gt;SantaAndTheReindeer.cx&lt;/a&gt;
Add one of our &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/features/custom-domain-applications-and-dns&quot;&gt;free features&lt;/a&gt; to it and the presentee can use his name immediately. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The iWantMyName Team wishes Merry Christmas and a happy New Year!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2008 19:43:53 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2008/12/last-minute-christmas-gift-idea-register-a-personal-domain-for-your-friends-or-family.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2008/12/last-minute-christmas-gift-idea-register-a-personal-domain-for-your-friends-or-family.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>The iWantMyName Blog has arrived</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;A few weeks after our launch the iWantMyName Blog has finally arrived.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here we&amp;#39;ll keep you informed about what&amp;#39;s going on at iWantMyName: new features, special offers, tips how to use your domain etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S. Also don&amp;#39;t forget to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.new.facebook.com/pages/iWantMyName-International-domain-name-registration/97823890470&quot;&gt;become a fan on Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/iwmn&quot;&gt;follow @iwmn on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2008 19:52:11 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2008/12/the-iwantmyname-blog-is-here.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2008/12/the-iwantmyname-blog-is-here.html</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
