<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>iwantmyname Domain Blog</title>
		<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog</link>
		<atom:link href="https://iwantmyname.com/blog/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>New in the Marketplace - Muut, a reimagined forum/commenting platform</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/assets/images/content/2015-01-28-muut-acion.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Muut Action&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Our &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/services&quot;&gt;App Marketplace&lt;/a&gt; is filled with dozens of great platforms you can add to your domain with just a few clicks (no DNS knowledge required), and in 2015, we’re looking to add a ton more. As we add new platforms to the list, you can get a little taste of what they offer here in the New in the Marketplace blog series.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting a blog is quite the endeavor. It’s a commitment to consistent writing, creative thinking, and unending doubt as to whether or not you’re hitting your goals. But one think blog creators often overlook is the means for audiences to have conversations around your work. Too often, the commenting/forum tools used look like they were created in the late 90s, and often function in ways that discourage natural thought processes—and that’s something &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/services/forum-hosting/muut&quot;&gt;Muut&lt;/a&gt; is trying to change. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a bit from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://muut.com/manifesto/&quot;&gt;Muut Manifesto&lt;/a&gt; (I always like a good manifesto):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Muut is a radically different discussion platform that can be embedded on any website. It is unencumbered by the weight of unnecessary features and distractions, and places the conversation back to the forefront.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A clean user interface, persistent content and a deep integration to the site will allow a more natural and meaningful discussion to take place, and enable people to focus on topics they care about. It’s a lightweight, super fast, and responsive platform that places minimal strain on data bandwidth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re on an important mission. A proper forums and commenting system will increase traffic on any given website, and the audience will stay longer. There is no sane reason not to have forums or commenting on a website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/assets/images/content/2015-01-28-forum-placement.png&quot; alt=&quot;muut placement options&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, Muut is a clean, embeddable, customizable (no iframes), crawlable, responsive, realtime, worry-free conversation platform for your site. And best of all, you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://muut.com/pricing/&quot;&gt;try it out&lt;/a&gt; (for an unlimited amount of time, with unlimited bandwidth, users, and data… just a few limited features) for free.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2015 12:19:52 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/01/new-in-the-marketplace-muut.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/01/new-in-the-marketplace-muut.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Why does iwantmyname need a monthly newsletter?</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Newsletters and blogs. Every corner of the internet seems to now be filled with newsletters and blogs in an ongoing competition for user attention. It&amp;#39;s easy to take a cynical view and say that it’s all just unnecessary noise, but in a way, we’re all laying the groundwork for the future of how brands can communicate effectively in a marketplace where competition can literally be created overnight in a bedroom. The reality is that brand culture and the way it’s communicated is one of the last differentiating factors a company has (right after user experience and innovation, I’d say), so it’s hugely important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there’s a challenge. Digital startups today are looking to capture global audiences with smaller staffs, more competition, and leaner margins than the analog brands of yore. For example, here at iwantmyname, our current marketing/communications goal is to reach the entirety of the English-speaking world (and beyond) with 11 people and no giant marketing budget speak of. Basically, we&amp;#39;ve almost exclusively leveraged word-of-mouth to reach customers/visitors in 234 countries (Google Analytics even says we got a visit from N. Korea?)...something we&amp;#39;re extremely proud of, but it&amp;#39;s a constant grind to spread our message of simplicity even further—in a sincere way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Sincerity in brand messaging&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe I’m just a naive between-Millennial-and-Gen-Xer (Xennial?), but I often look at advertising as an insincere gesture. When I see display ads, I often think of them as giant billboards trying to subliminally make me like things (I don’t like you, but that cheeseburger looks delicious!). Social marketing is often the same—companies tweet mildly funny tidbits to their followers, hoping for some sort of delightful, friendly response. If their posts were personal notes or direct messages, they’d be charming, but it’s hard to be charmed by a message directed at no one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s just so much noise. 10 tweets a day from each brand, three Facebook posts, display ads, news articles, sponsorships, appearances. As a consumer, I’m not looking for radio silence, I’m just yearning for a way to turn it off most of the week. I like to see innovation and ideas and compatible company cultures, but I don’t have the time or mental capacity to keep up with fifteen brands shouting at me everywhere I go. None of us do. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, as an iwantmyname brand ambassador, I feel like the responsible thing to do is to help create a way to deliver our thoughts and innovations without filling people&amp;#39;s lives with even more noise—to compress all the clutter into one manageable chunk. In 2015, I really think this is the best way to follow brands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Sign up for the monthly newsletter&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most days we (along with so many other brands) publish blog posts, then do some connecting social posts—but it would be crazy to expect anyone to pay attention on a daily basis. If you follow the iwantmyname blog daily, as my mom would say, bless your heart. But let’s be honest…if you’re not a keeping up with the industry on a professional or semi-professional basis, you shouldn’t &lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; to be thinking about domains all the time. We designed iwantmyname to be the simplest domain registrar on the internet because we &lt;em&gt;didn&amp;#39;t&lt;/em&gt; want people to have to regularly think about our end. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We do have some interesting ideas though, and we regularly highlight features and give suggestions that can make lives easier. For example, if you’re looking to host a podcast, we recently added &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/services/podcast/simplecast&quot;&gt;Simplecast&lt;/a&gt; to our available plugins. It’s a really neat platform—something we think you should know about. And we often post about new &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/new-gtld-domain-extensions&quot;&gt;generic top-level domains (gTLDs)&lt;/a&gt; coming out, which could inspire you to start the next great website. We’re also pretty big on startup culture, so we often write about new tools and thought technologies we find interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you want some more of the above, or if you just want to know if our brand aligns with your ideals and priorities, the best/least-intrusive option is to &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/monthly&quot;&gt;sign up for our newsletter&lt;/a&gt;. Sure, it’s yet another thing  to sign up for, but in a way it sets you free. After you sign up, you can be certain we’ll deliver you our latest thoughts in one easily deletable email (seriously, one click and it’s gone), and after that, you can go back to thinking about whatever it is you should be thinking about—like your job, your family, or your hobby du jour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, for more instant coverage, our social platforms (like &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/iwantmyname&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/iwantmyname&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;) work great. Our general social strategy is to only spread thoughts—and very few good thoughts can be condensed to 140 characters—so 1-3 times a day we post links to blogs we’ve written, plus the occasional update, and that’s about it. If you see something you find interesting, click on it, but if you don’t, don&amp;#39;t sweat it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Stats also seem to support a monthly newsletter&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I imagine it’s pretty clear by now that I prefer newsletters as the content driver for most brands, but the stats seem to support that thinking as well. If you’ve been an iwantmyname customer for a while, you’ve probably seen the yearly newsletter we send to remind people of our existence (we send it to every customer). Here are some stats from the end-of-2014 edition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sent to 99,960 mailboxes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;29.2% open rate (vs. the 14.7 industry average, according to MailChimp)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most clicked items were:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the link to subscribe to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/monthly&quot;&gt;new monthly newsletter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/special-offer&quot;&gt;December domain discounts&lt;/a&gt;, which tells me that a lot of the people interested in domain discounts aren’t regularly visiting our blog or site—which is perfectly understandable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/a/ideegeo.com/forms/d/1WzXl1WdMt8eRoH1Kprl5QtRXmX-L4Citp9dYXvzTHUs/viewform&quot;&gt;link to help&lt;/a&gt; with the iwantmyname API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t say for certain that this is common for newsletters, but the analytics for this particular send seems to support the thinking that our customers would like a monthly edition, and that there are certain topics and tidbits people would like delivered to them on a semi-regular basis. That alone is reason enough to publish a monthly edition, so everything extra is gravy, as they say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;TLDR?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Companies need monthly newsletters because people tend to appreciate news and ideas presented in unobtrusive, easily deletable packages. Brands are unique in that they have a ton of combined knowledge to share, but (I’m serious about this) customers shouldn’t have to spend more than 30 minutes a month to keep up with their latest thought technologies. If you want to follow a brand&amp;#39;s blogs and social posts, that’s awesome, but you shouldn’t &lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; to. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if you’d like to hear more from us (unobtrusively), be sure to subscribe to our new monthly newsletter, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/monthly&quot;&gt;iwantmyname:Monthly&lt;/a&gt;. We’ll be sending our first edition later on this week, and we think you’ll really like it (and if you don’t, just unsubscribe…&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xB5ceAruYrI&quot;&gt;hakuna matata&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2015 16:36:20 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/01/why-does-iwantmyname-need-a-monthly-newsletter.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/01/why-does-iwantmyname-need-a-monthly-newsletter.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Startup and tech domain name trends in 2015 and beyond. What’s coming after .IO, .CO, and .ME?</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the early days of the internet, .COM was the top choice for companies and their online presences. Then, in the second half of the 2000s, we saw country code top-level domains (ccTLDs) such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/io-domain-name-registration-for-british-indian-ocean-territory&quot;&gt;.IO&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/me-montenegrean-domain-name-registration-for-montenegro&quot;&gt;.ME&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/co-colombian-domain-name-registration-for-colombia&quot;&gt;.CO&lt;/a&gt; become popular alternatives for tech startups and developers. Now, after the 2014 introduction of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/new-gtld-domain-extensions&quot;&gt;new generic top-level domains (gTLDs)&lt;/a&gt;, we’re looking at yet another shift. So which TLDs will take the reigns in the tech/startup world? Let’s take a look at some of the contenders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For companies, we have:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-software&quot;&gt;.SOFTWARE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-technology&quot;&gt;.TECHNOLOGY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-digital&quot;&gt;.DIGITAL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some good options, but with shorter alternatives (e.g. .TECH and .APP) yet to launch, we’ll have to wait and see how they do in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, developers can choose between:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-codes&quot;&gt;.CODES&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-consulting&quot;&gt;.CONSULTING&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-build&quot;&gt;.BUILD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(On a side note, we were surprised to see .CODES being used for personal sites, i.e. yourname.CODES)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Domain extensions coming soon:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-app&quot;&gt;.APP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-tech&quot;&gt;.TECH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-cloud&quot;&gt;.CLOUD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-data&quot;&gt;.DATA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/dot-systems&quot;&gt;.SYSTEMS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.APP is certainly the 800-pound gorilla here, and we’re expecting it to do really, really well (it’s the TLD with the most pre-orders at iwantmyname).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the TLDs above are technology related (for the article), but if you pull back a bit, there&amp;#39;s a much more important trend at play here—naming diversity. With &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/new-gtld-domain-extensions&quot;&gt;more than 200 new gTLDs already available&lt;/a&gt; and many more to come, why would you restrict yourself by following trendy naming patterns, like what happened in the past with .LY (remember these?), or extensions with inexact meanings like .IO, .CO, and .ME? If you’re starting the next Instagram (which launched using the instagr.AM domain hack), wouldn’t it be better to use instagram.PHOTOS or a more generic instagram.APP, for example?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the reasons the .IO, .ME, and .CO domains initially became popular was that they were empty namespaces with lots of keywords available. However, good names are starting to become rare in these “tech-TLDs”, and that’s exactly why we’re so excited about the new top-level domain alternatives. There are now more naming options than ever, and it will take a while—if ever—until good and affordable names are hard to come by.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So will there be a next .IO, .ME or .CO (which are still great domain extensions by the way)? If anything, we see .APP as the most likely contender, but there&amp;#39;s no set launch date yet. Until then, when choosing a domain, just remember that &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/01/doing-is-almost-always-more-important-than-worrying.html&quot;&gt;doing is almost always more important than worrying&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2015 09:23:51 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/01/io-co-me-domain-alternatives.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/01/io-co-me-domain-alternatives.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Are your messaging apps/tools secure?</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Security is one of those things people tend to shy away from because it&amp;#39;s inconvenient, but keeping things safe is often as easy as using the right service. If you do a lot of online chatting, be sure to check out this secure messaging scorecard from the EFF—it&amp;#39;s an interesting read. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/secure-messaging-scorecard&quot;&gt;From the Electronic Frontier Foundation:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the face of widespread Internet surveillance, we need a secure and practical means of talking to each other from our phones and computers. Many companies offer “secure messaging” products—but are these systems actually secure? We decided to find out, in the first phase of a new EFF Campaign for Secure &amp;amp; Usable Crypto.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This scorecard represents only the first phase of the campaign. In later phases, we are planning to offer closer examinations of the usability and security of the tools that score the highest here. As such, the results in the scorecard below should not be read as endorsements of individual tools or guarantees of their security; they are merely indications that the projects are on the right track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2015 15:00:32 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/01/are-your-messaging-tools-secure.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/01/are-your-messaging-tools-secure.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Start naming your brands and domains like a pro</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Naming and choosing domains often go hand-in-hand, but many don&amp;#39;t take either as seriously as they probably should. To get a glimpse of the professional naming process, take a gander at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2015/01/18/magazine/the-weird-science-of-naming-new-products.html?_r=0&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;The Weird Science of Naming New Products&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt; by Neal Gabler of the New York Times Magazine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea is to do everything — to leave no word unturned. He visits the website onelook.com, which shows how words work with other words, or sketchengine.co.uk, which combs texts and concordances, flags parts of speech and shows how a specific word appears in billions of words of text. He visits rhymezone.com to find all the words that rhyme with a word. That is how he came up with the name for an ideation application for the Palm Pilot — he began with “brain,” looked for rhyming words and concluded with BrainForest. For this project, he thought of words about travel, but also about entertainment, the sense of engagement, connection, energy, even spheres. And he laid them all out on an Excel spreadsheet — 1,200 names in all by the time he had finished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a single project, namers can come up with as many as 6,500 names. Big naming companies will do anywhere from 40 to 50 projects a year, and smaller ones 15 to 20, which adds up to a lot of names. Of course, only one name will be chosen for each project, and that is the only one the client will own. The rest, however, won’t necessarily go to waste. Every naming agency keeps a list of its discards in a computer program. These are then classified by message (at Catchword); by distinctiveness, appeal, memorability and concept (at Interbrand); or by whatever other way the namers might want to retrieve them. Catchword has 650 of these categorized lists. And many of the names will be recycled, which suggests that there is a kind of Platonic ideal of good names, independent of products good or bad — a name so good that it could work, if not on anything, than at least on many things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now clearly many (if not most) people/brands can&amp;#39;t afford the premium costs of naming firms, but we should all strive to dig a bit deeper into our brands and ideals before coming up with names (if you don&amp;#39;t have at least 100 ideas on paper, you&amp;#39;re probably not trying hard enough). Just another something to add to your 2015 resolutions list. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2015 15:58:16 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/01/start-naming-your-brands-and-domains-like-a-pro.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/01/start-naming-your-brands-and-domains-like-a-pro.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Things to know about domains before buying your first domain name</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s never more apparent how puzzling domain names are to people than when I get asked about my job. “A domain registrar? What the heck is that?” I get it all the time, but what surprises me most is that many of these same people already own domains in some form or another—usually brokered through legacy web-design firms charging $20-30/mo for Flash websites with glitzy visitor counters (seriously, if you&amp;#39;re paying $30/mo for a site built a decade ago, you&amp;#39;re getting ripped off).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So my goal of goals is to set them on the right path, usually with an abridged version of this very post—my spiel on domain names, what you’re buying, what the deal is with all the new domain extensions, what email has to do with it all, and a bit about Whois privacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#section-1&quot;&gt;Domain name? Domain registrar?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#section-2&quot;&gt;Domain extensions, or top-level domains (TLDs)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#section-3&quot;&gt;The new gTLDs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#section-4&quot;&gt;What to do with your domain name?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#section-5&quot;&gt;A final word about privacy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#section-6&quot;&gt;And please, don’t be shy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;section-1&quot;&gt;1. Domain name? Domain registrar?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just to get in the right frame of mind, let&amp;#39;s think of the internet at an entirely new planet Earth. Then, think of the domain extensions (like .com, ,net, .edu) as countries, and the individual domain names (like iwantmyname.com or yourname.com) as pieces of property within those countries. Then, as your domain registrar, iwantmyname is like a big real estate agency, able to sell you a piece of property in a ton of countries on the planet. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To recap:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The internet is a huge planet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Domain extensions are countries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Individual domain names are property&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Domain registrars are your real estate agents&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As the writer of this, I’m your content guide to internet real estate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;section-2&quot;&gt;2. Domain extensions, or top-level domains (TLDs)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the beginnings of the public internet, the web was filled with a fairly limited number of domain extensions (also called top-level domains (or TLDs)). In the US, most websites ended in .com, .net, .org, .edu, or .gov, and around the world, many sites adopted their country code top-level domains (or ccTLDs)—like .co.uk in the UK and .co.nz in New Zealand. No matter where you were though, .com was the clear popularity leader, and that popularity advantage still exists today. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But remember, .com is like a country, and like any country, there’s limited desirable space. And limited desirable space always leads to overcrowding. The problem is twofold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With more and more people getting on the internet, we’re starting to run out of short, memorable domain names. And by run out, I mean that by 2014, every two, three, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2013/12/four-letter-coms-are-a-four-letter-wordgone.html&quot;&gt;four letter .com domain had already been registered&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It’s not like all these domains are being used though. Basic rules of supply and demand brought countless opportunistic businessmen who bought up these domains and started selling them on the domain aftermarket for premium prices (some even went in the million-dollar range!).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of people blame these so-called cybersquatters for the lack of good .com names available, but it’s hard to blame them for wanting to be part of the action (do you blame real-estate speculators for the lack of cheap property in your area?). Just remember that this supply/demand issue is based on the fact that the only desirable TLD is .com, which was borderline true in years past. If the amount of good options multiply through...what then?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;section-3&quot;&gt;3. The new gTLDs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll spare you the details and backstory, but in 2014, &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/new-gtld-domain-extensions&quot;&gt;hundreds upon hundreds of new domain extensions&lt;/a&gt; were created (often called the new generic TLDs (gTLDs), or new TLDs (nTLDs)), making that lack of quality domain names a thing of the past. Now, if I want to use my name in a domain, I can get Chris.ninja, Chris.club, Chris.cool, Chris.enterprises, Chris.vodka, etc., etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I hinted at already, the problem we’re running into now isn’t a supply issue, it’s a human nature issue—people are afraid of the unknown. Sticking with the property analogy, if you open a shiny new store in a brand new place, will people find it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all depends on how you’re being discovered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If social media is your biggest traffic driver, your links will work fine no matter what your TLD is. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Depending on who you ask, there might actually be a small search engine optimization (SEO) advantage to using a new gTLD (but maybe none at all). As long as your brand is good and your copy isn’t spammy, your search engine results should be fine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The only potential harm is if people think your domain looks like a scam because of your TLD. There&amp;#39;s a fairly small (in the scheme of things) history of spam websites buying up domain names similar to real brand names on various TLDs, but as long as your brand doesn&amp;#39;t include fake looking strings of numbers, random characters (usually lots of dashes), or fishy misspellings, you should be fine. As more and more big/legitimate websites adopt these new domain extensions, that stigma should go away.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a ton of articles online that have research “proving” either side of the discoverability debate (whether the new gTLDs are good or bad for business), but my stance is that there are too many people with too much money invested into these new gTLDs for them to completely fail. Maybe none of them will reach the popularity of .com, but people’s attitude towards domains that don’t end in .com is definitely starting to shift. My best advice would be to worry about the name of your brand first, then find an applicable TLD to fit it. There are &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/domains/domain-name-registration-list-of-extensions&quot;&gt;hundreds to choose from&lt;/a&gt; now, so there&amp;#39;s no reason to be bound to the crowded land of .com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;section-4&quot;&gt;4. What to do with your domain name&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we’ve established that domain names are property—what kinds of things can you build on it? Let’s run through a couple options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Build a website&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most common thing to do with a domain name is to build a website. And unless you’re deft at writing code (if so, you probably don’t need to be reading this), the best course of action is to use one of the many platforms available to build your site with ease (many have templates or some form of drag-and-drop tools available, making web design easy enough for everyone).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here’s the gist. On one end, you have your domain name, and on the other, you have a website built on a platform like Squarespace. To get your Squarespace site to pair with your domain, you have to add the correct DNS records to your domain name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here at iwantmyname, we make that part easy. Once you buy your domain, you can set it up to work with many of the web’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/services/ecommerce-hosting/&quot;&gt;most popular platforms&lt;/a&gt; with just a few clicks. So instead of worrying about editing DNS records, you can get started with a platform like Squarespace, Shopify, Tumblr, or Ghost in a snap. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seriously... it’s almost automatic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;A quick word about www.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every once in a while we get asked how much it costs to add the www. to a website. It’s totally free—the www. is just a subdomain that isn’t necessary, but still common because people got used to saying it in the 90’s. Our &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/services/email-hosting/&quot;&gt;platform setups&lt;/a&gt; add the www. option automatically, so there’s no need to worry about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Get an email address&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things we get asked most is how to get a custom email address. So first, let’s be clear about how your domain name fits into your email. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you look at an email address, it usually looks something like this—chris@yourname.com. To create this, the owner of yourname.com had to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get the yourname.com domain name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select and sign up for an &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/services/email-hosting/&quot;&gt;email hosting service&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Point the domain name to that email hosting service&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add individual email addresses (like chris@yourname.com) through the email hosting service admin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like anything on the web, there are a lot of different companies out there that do email hosting—Google, Fastmail, Zoho, etc. All of them will be able to get your mail from point A to point B, but they all offer slightly different features at different price points. My suggestion would be to head to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/services/email-hosting/&quot;&gt;email plugin page&lt;/a&gt;, then look at each platform’s website to see which features you’d be happiest with. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Sometimes you just need to wait for inspiration&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some people, getting a domain means there&amp;#39;s an immediate plan. For others, it’s important to wait for inspiration to strike. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This happens to me all the time. I’ll be driving home from lunch, thinking about how to best tell people about my awesome dining experience, then decide to create a restaurant review website. After an hour or so of quick naming exercises, I’ll grab a domain to kickstart the writing process (kind of like buying a guitar to guilt yourself into learning how to play). But sometimes, if I lose interest too fast, I’ll sit on the domain for a month or two while the ideas percolate—once you register a domain, it’s yours for a year, so there’s no big rush. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just remember that if you don’t decide to use the domain, be sure to turn renewals off so you won’t keep paying for it year after year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;section-5&quot;&gt;5. A final word about privacy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Online privacy has been all over the news lately (for good reason), and one of the easier things you can do to hide some of your information is to enable Whois privacy (it’s free) on your domain. &lt;a href=&quot;https://help.iwantmyname.com/customer/portal/articles/184425-do-you-offer-a-whois-privacy-service-&quot;&gt;Here’s a good guide&lt;/a&gt; to how Whois privacy works and how to enable it, but please note that only the domain extensions listed in that article support it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;section-6&quot;&gt;6. And please, don’t be shy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the uninitiated, the internet can be a big, scary place. If you ever run into any issues with your domain, or just can’t figure out how to link it to the platform you want, &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/support&quot;&gt;send us a message&lt;/a&gt; and we’ll be sure to help out. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2015 11:12:32 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/01/things-to-know-about-domains-before-buying-your-first-domain-name.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/01/things-to-know-about-domains-before-buying-your-first-domain-name.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>SEO penalties of moving our blog to a subdomain</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me start this article by confessing that we’re not SEO gurus at iwantmyname. Everything we&amp;#39;ve done in the last few years in terms of SEO was done with a basic understanding of the topic and by providing a good product with relevant content and landing pages. This always served us well and we were happy with our rankings overall. With that out of the way, I’d like to tell you about our experience with switching our blog to a subdomain. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /excerpt --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the very beginning of July last year, we moved our blog from a subdirectory URL (&lt;code&gt;iwantmyname.com/blog&lt;/code&gt;) to a subdomain (&lt;code&gt;blog.iwantmyname.com&lt;/code&gt;) for better maintainability and performance with GitHub Pages&amp;#39; &lt;abbr title=&quot;content delivery network&quot;&gt;CDN&lt;/abbr&gt; and future-proofing in case we wanted to switch to a different platform down the road. We made this decision after doing lots of research and had long discussions about how it might impact our search engine rankings, but we ultimately agreed to make the change. After all, it was 2014 and Google should be clever enough that it wouldn’t make any difference because they know the blog (subdomain or not) is part of iwantmyname, right? As Matt Cutts said &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_MswMYk05tk&quot;&gt;in one of his webmaster videos&lt;/a&gt; “it’s a question which one is easier for you and whichever one makes you happier I would go and do it that way”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we expected an initial hit after making the subdomain switch and traffic slowly recovering, the turnaround didn’t happen after 6 months, as you can see in the following example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/assets/images/content/2015-01-16-blog-traffic-subdomain-switch.png&quot; alt=&quot;Blog traffic after switch to subdomain&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From what we can tell, we did everything by the books with &lt;code&gt;301&lt;/code&gt; redirects for all URLs - so what happened? Could it have been just coincidence that Google updated their algorithm and we got penalized for some reason?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One signal that Google introduced one month after us making the switch was to give SSL-secured sites a little ranking boost. Since &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/iwantmyname/blog&quot;&gt;our blog is running on GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;, which &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/isaacs/github/issues/156&quot;&gt;doesn’t currently support HTTPS&lt;/a&gt;, could that have prevented the traffic from recovering? Certainly it can’t be that much of a ranking signal—although they mentioned it would increase in importance over time?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So after waiting for six months, we reverted the change and switched our blog back to the previous &lt;code&gt;/blog&lt;/code&gt; subdirectory. It’s still hosted on GitHub Pages and we’re using a simple Nginx proxy to show the content under &lt;code&gt;iwantmyname.com/blog&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;location = /blog {
  # GitHub Pages doesn&amp;#39;t redirect this properly, so we&amp;#39;ll handle it
  return 301 /blog/;
}

# ^~ to allow /blog/ to match before our other regex locations
location ^~ /blog/ {
  proxy_pass https://iwantmyname.github.io;
  proxy_intercept_errors on;
  # serve custom 404 page from our blog repo instead of GitHub Pages&amp;#39; 404
  error_page  404  /blog/404.html;
  # allow GitHub to pass caching headers instead of using our own
  expires off;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An important side effect is that our blog pages are now secured under our primary SSL certificate again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on this experience and the following &lt;a href=&quot;http://moz.com/community/q/moz-s-official-stance-on-subdomain-vs-subfolder-does-it-need-updating#reply_217479&quot;&gt;recommendation from Moz’s Rand Fishkin&lt;/a&gt;, we decided it would be better for our long-term SEO strategy to put our blog back on our primary domain:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would still strongly urge folks to keep all content on a single subdomain. We recently were able to test this using a subdomain on Moz itself (when moving our beginner&amp;#39;s guide to SEO from guides.moz.com to the current URL http://moz.com/beginners-guide-to-seo). The results were astounding - rankings rose dramatically across the board for every keyword we tracked to the pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will certainly keep a close eye on traffic for the next few months and keep you updated. Hope this helps some of you when deciding on the age-old debate of whether you should have your blog on a subdomain or not!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2015 15:53:45 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/01/seo-penalties-of-moving-our-blog-to-a-subdomain.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/01/seo-penalties-of-moving-our-blog-to-a-subdomain.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>New gTLDs and SEO performance</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.circleid.com/posts/20150112_new_gtlds_show_promising_seo_performance/&quot;&gt;From Roland LaPlante - CircleID:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the arrival of hundreds of new generic top-level domains (gTLDs), many marketers are excited that they can now get a web address that best describes their business or brand. For instance, a company in the organic business can now get a web address on .ORGANIC, or a brand that&amp;#39;s all about passion and excitement can now get on .RED, etc. At the same time, many are also asking some important SEO related questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will Google crawl new gTLDs?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will new gTLDs automatically score higher in Google&amp;#39;s search algorithms?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the SEO best practices for migrating a site to a new gTLD?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Should brands REALLY get on new gTLDs and give up the status quo?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#39;s address them one by one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2015 15:32:01 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/01/new-gtlds-and-seo-performance.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/01/new-gtlds-and-seo-performance.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Say hi to the newest iwantmynamer, Kevin Layshock</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;With 2015 now in full swing, we&amp;#39;d like to announce our newest addition—Kevin Layshock. Over the course of the next year (decade(s)?), he&amp;#39;ll be designing his way around the iwantmyname universe, buttoning up the website, redesigning our emails, improving our branding, and generally making everything a bit more friendly and usable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to say hi, you can find him on Twitter &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/couthmonger&quot;&gt;@couthmonger&lt;/a&gt;. Conversation starters include: interesting UI/UX design, contemporary art, beautiful lettering, comic books, podcasts, good movies (only good ones), coffee, and of course, tasty beverages.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2015 13:30:05 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/01/say-hi-to-the-newest-iwantmynamer-kevin-layshock.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/01/say-hi-to-the-newest-iwantmynamer-kevin-layshock.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>How to use a standard Gmail account for free custom domain email</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://simplyian.com/2015/01/07/Hacking-GMail-to-use-custom-domains-for-free/&quot;&gt;From Ian Macalinao:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s pretty much common knowledge that GMail is awesome. It’s fast, connects seamlessly with the rest of your Google services such as Drive, has a cool app called Inbox, and is overall an extremely powerful email service. However, to use it with a custom domain, you need to purchase Google Apps for either $5 or $10/month, which for casual users is a bit unnecessary. On top of that, you don’t even get all of the features a personal account gets, e.g. Inbox.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there’s a free way to use your GMail account with a custom domain: Mailgun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Neat trick for more advanced users to set up custom domain email using a standard Gmail account and &lt;a href=&quot;http://mailgun.com&quot;&gt;Mailgun&lt;/a&gt; (for up to 10,000 emails a month). &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2014/06/yes-you-can-still-get-free-custom-email-addresses.html&quot;&gt;Yes, you can still get free custom domain email addresses&lt;/a&gt; — even in 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2015 18:25:06 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://iwantmyname.com/blog/2015/01/how-to-use-a-standard-gmail-account-for-free-custom-domain-email.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/01/how-to-use-a-standard-gmail-account-for-free-custom-domain-email.html</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
